<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iphone on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/iphone/</link><description>Recent content in iphone on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 15:43:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/iphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#TheCabin Mobile for iPhone</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/09/#thecabin-mobile-for-iphone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 15:43:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/09/#thecabin-mobile-for-iphone/</guid><description>I've always said if I took all the time and effort I spent into side projects and spent them on something else I'd have a lot of cool other things. But I've spent some nights and weekends working on this new little app, my first submission to the iTunes App Store. (Approved in 8 days, FYI) As some of you may know, for the past 15 years I've been helping manage an internet relay chat (IRC) channel I started called #TheCabin.</description></item><item><title>My thoughts on the Mophie Juicepack</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/10/my-thoughts-on-the-mophie-juicepack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 09:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/10/my-thoughts-on-the-mophie-juicepack/</guid><description>{.alignright width=&amp;quot;245&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;quot;245&amp;rdquo;}A few weeks ago I purchased the Mophie Juicepack Air in preperation for my trip to Chicago for my class reunion. When I announced on Twitter I was picking one up I had a few requests for my thoughts on it after some use. Admittedly, the new iPhone 3GS has substantially better battery live than the 3G. Very noticeable. However, there are times and situations where that's still not good enough.</description></item><item><title>#TheCabin for iOS</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/project/thecabin-for-ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/thecabin-for-ios/</guid><description>#TheCabin for iOS is a native iPhone and iPad application for accessing #TheCabin, an Internet Relay Chat channel.
There used to be chat rooms where you can meet new friends and be a part of a community with people from all over the world, and one such place still exists.
#TheCabin started in 1995 and has had the opportunity to have people from all over the world become friends through it.</description></item></channel></rss>