<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>San Francisco on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/san-francisco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in San Francisco on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/san-francisco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Another adventure begins.  Goodbye Omaha.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2012-01-29-2012-01-goodbye-omaha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2012-01-29-2012-01-goodbye-omaha/</guid>
      <description>My time in Omaha is coming to an end. On Friday, February 3rd I&#39;ll have relocated to San Francisco.When looking back at the past three years it&#39;s hard to decide what to put in this rather long retrospective post. But I&#39;ll use it as my last opportunity to highlight, clarify, give thanks, and try to explain why I&#39;m taking on this new adventure.
I moved to Omaha thinking I&#39;d have to dodge cows on the way to the office every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gabe&#39;s 2012 Year in Review</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2012-12-28-2012-12-2012-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2012-12-28-2012-12-2012-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s time for my mostly-annual &#34;stuff and things&#34; post. I&#39;ve missed some years, but I think I have more new stuff this time around. I&#39;ll try and detail all of the software, hardware and services that I&#39;ve used this year to make my personal and professional life better or more interesting.
Software
 Desktop (OS X)   Xcode.
Love it or hate it, I live in it. Actually, I don&#39;t know if I love it or hate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye, Rdio</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2015-11-17-goodbye-rdio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2015-11-17-goodbye-rdio/</guid>
      <description>Like everybody else, I felt like I had heard every song on Pandora by the time I discovered Rdio. I was user number 4075, a paid unlimited user, signing up on June 6, 2010. I was really happy to hear anything I wanted. I used the Rdio Desktop client to create a collection on the service with my local iTunes Library. I listened to it a lot.
Like many others, I moved to Spotify once it finally came to the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve lived in San Francisco for a while</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2012-07-22-2012-07-ive-lived-in-san-francisco-for-a-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2012-07-22-2012-07-ive-lived-in-san-francisco-for-a-while/</guid>
      <description>I was asked a few weeks back why I haven&#39;t written a post on my blog since I&#39;ve been to San Francisco. I mean, there must be a lot of stuff to talk about, right? It&#39;s a pretty significant move and maybe the world wants to hear me blab about it. But I think in general I have been blabbing about it, but in more specific channels. But that&#39;s not to say I shouldn&#39;t have a larger periodic update.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>