<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcamp 2010: The Musical</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2010-11-17-2010-11-barcamp-2010-the-musical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2010-11-17-2010-11-barcamp-2010-the-musical/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been thinking about what I wanted to do for Barcamp this year. I was chatting over lunch today with this week&#39;s Coworking Wednesday participants about how I wished there was something different I could do. Something collaborative and break the mold of what an unconference session should be. I mentioned music stuff and @whatevermatt mentioned a drum circle.I thought about that a while (at least 2 to 3 minutes) later that day (today) and thought I&#39;d see if I could pull something off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Days Off</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2006-12-20-2006-12-happy-days-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2006-12-20-2006-12-happy-days-off/</guid>
      <description>Well, they&#39;re days off for me, anyway.I&#39;ve been off so far this week, and this is my last day off. Wanted to blow some vacation days before I lose them. Wish I could carry some over, but I can&#39;t. Oh well.
Been spending most of the time on music. Most of it really sucks, so I find myself wanting to spend more and more time making it not suck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ice, Ice, Baby.  Too cold.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2009-08-02-2009-08-ice-ice-baby-too-cold/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2009-08-02-2009-08-ice-ice-baby-too-cold/</guid>
      <description> Word to your mother.Gabe performing Ice Ice Baby in Bellevue from Gabe Kangas on Vimeo.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost and Found: A video experiment started in 2006</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2010-10-14-2010-10-3685/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2010-10-14-2010-10-3685/</guid>
      <description>In 2006 I was diligently working on my (still unreleased) new album &#34;The Longest Post&#34;. With that I decided to create a couple music videos both as an experiment on if I could make something fun, and to have a visual way to distribute some songs.A couple apartment moves later and the hard drives with the music videos were lost.
Until now. In October, 2010 I found the hard drives while cleaning out my music studio and decided it was time to show them to the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man, it&#39;s SXSW time already?  How time flies.  I&#39;ll sure not be busy.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2007-03-09-2007-03-man-its-sxsw-time-already-how-time-flies-ill-sure-be-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2007-03-09-2007-03-man-its-sxsw-time-already-how-time-flies-ill-sure-be-busy/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been a whole year already since I hadn&#39;t gone to SXSW 2006 and it&#39;s time again for me to not go to SXSW 2007. I don&#39;t have my hotel all booked and my flights are not ready to go. I won&#39;t be arriving in Austin tonight.
I&#39;m really pumped about the panels that are scheduled, I can&#39;t wait to not see them.
Did you see the lineups of the bands?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeing my first Drum Corps show in 10 years</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2014-06-23-2014-6-seeing-my-first-drum-corps-show-in-10-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2014-06-23-2014-6-seeing-my-first-drum-corps-show-in-10-years/</guid>
      <description>I haven&#39;t seen a drum corps live since I was in The Racine Kilties in 2004. I don&#39;t know if it was me doing the Chinese New Year parade with The Renegades this year, or if enough time has passed where I was ready to see a show again, but I did. DCI West at Stanford took place this weekend and I thought I&#39;d chronicle a few thoughts I have about the activity (as ruled by DCI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So i&#39;m working on music</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2007-01-20-2007-01-so-im-working-on-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2007-01-20-2007-01-so-im-working-on-music/</guid>
      <description>I think I have about 15 songs now in various stages of completion. There&#39;s probably only two or so that are &#34;done&#34;, another two or so that are barely started, and the rest all in between.I&#39;m going through the phase now where I ignore all the original songs that I spent a lot of time on. During the holidays I didn&#39;t have much time to spend on music, so it was a good cleansing period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status on my album, or whatever</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2007-06-09-2007-06-status-on-my-album-or-whatever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2007-06-09-2007-06-status-on-my-album-or-whatever/</guid>
      <description>So i&#39;ve pretty much had the freedom now for over a month to work on my music whenever I want to. There&#39;s a problem though, an a rather large one. I don&#39;t want to. There&#39;s just too much going on, and i&#39;m unable to focus on a large project like that at the present time. It&#39;s really bothering me.I mean, there&#39;s no timeline, so there&#39;s really no problem. It&#39;s my own thing, and there&#39;s nobody chomping at the bit to listen to this stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I&#39;d like to do in 2013</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2013-01-01-2012-12-stuff-id-like-to-do-in-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2013-01-01-2012-12-stuff-id-like-to-do-in-2013/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m not a fan of New Years resolutions, but there are some things I&#39;d like to do in this next year. All very doable things, but if you think that in any way you&#39;d be able to help with any of them I&#39;d certainly be up for pointers!
 Contribute to an open source project that focuses on a) mobile and b) something I care about. (Note: I checked out the Colloquy source last night and started looking at their bug list to see if I could help with anything).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Song Recommendation: Mark Mallman - Mother Made Me Do It</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2010-10-11-2010-10-weekly-song-recommendation-mark-mallman-mother-made-me-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2010-10-11-2010-10-weekly-song-recommendation-mark-mallman-mother-made-me-do-it/</guid>
      <description>I haven&#39;t done a music recommendation post in a while. It&#39;s certainly not weekly, but I&#39;m not changing the naming. I don&#39;t know, stopped feeling inspired, I guess.Well fuck if I don&#39;t feel inspired now.
I&#39;ve always been a fan of Mark Mallman&#39;s. It started, like many of artists I enjoy do, seeing a show of theirs without knowing who they were beforehand. This is a prime example of the Gabe Kangas music/movie introduction theory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>