<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Omaha on Gabe Kangas</title>
    <link>https://gabekangas.com/categories/omaha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Omaha on Gabe Kangas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en_US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 04:20:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/categories/omaha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gabe&#39;s 2012 Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/12/gabes-2012-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 04:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/12/gabes-2012-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s time for my mostly-annual &#34;stuff and things&#34; post. I&#39;ve missed some years, but I think I have more new stuff this time around. I&#39;ll try and detail all of the software, hardware and services that I&#39;ve used this year to make my personal and professional life better or more interesting.
Software
 Desktop (OS X)   Xcode.
Love it or hate it, I live in it. Actually, I don&#39;t know if I love it or hate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another adventure begins.  Goodbye Omaha.</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/01/another-adventure-begins.-goodbye-omaha./</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 10:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/01/another-adventure-begins.-goodbye-omaha./</guid>
      <description>My time in Omaha is coming to an end. On Friday, February 3rd I&#39;ll have relocated to San Francisco. When looking back at the past three years it&#39;s hard to decide what to put in this rather long retrospective post. But I&#39;ll use it as my last opportunity to highlight, clarify, give thanks, and try to explain why I&#39;m taking on this new adventure.
I moved to Omaha thinking I&#39;d have to dodge cows on the way to the office every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcamp Omaha 2010 was rad (and the jam was fun)</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/11/barcamp-omaha-2010-was-rad-and-the-jam-was-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 16:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/11/barcamp-omaha-2010-was-rad-and-the-jam-was-fun/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the organization team of Barcamp2010 here in Omaha it was another great event. Learned some stuff and had some fun. Also thanks to everyone to indulged me in my attempt for a lunchtime jam session. I can&#39;t honestly say it was the most musical thing ever performed, but we all had fun anyway :) Thanks to everyone who took part! It was nice to mix things up a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcamp 2010: The Musical</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/11/barcamp-2010-the-musical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 19:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/11/barcamp-2010-the-musical/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been thinking about what I wanted to do for Barcamp this year. I was chatting over lunch today with this week&#39;s Coworking Wednesday participants about how I wished there was something different I could do. Something collaborative and break the mold of what an unconference session should be. I mentioned music stuff and @whatevermatt mentioned a drum circle. I thought about that a while (at least 2 to 3 minutes) later that day (today) and thought I&#39;d see if I could pull something off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choices, decisions and fear: Part 2.</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/choices-decisions-and-fear-part-2./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/choices-decisions-and-fear-part-2./</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m a fan of transparency. I like to know what people are up to, and I think there are people that like to know what I&#39;m up to as well. This includes the background and emotions behind major life decisions. So here&#39;s my story. If you&#39;re reading this you already know it&#39;s been a rough couple months as far as my career path goes. I knew I needed to move elsewhere, but I didn&#39;t know in what capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gabe Kangas Association for Awesome is proud to sponsor Omaha Bar Camp 2009</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/gabe-kangas-association-for-awesome-is-proud-to-sponsor-omaha-bar-camp-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 00:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/gabe-kangas-association-for-awesome-is-proud-to-sponsor-omaha-bar-camp-2009/</guid>
      <description>The Gabe Kangas Association for Awesome (GKAFA) is proud to announce they will be sponsoring this year&#39;s Omaha Bar Camp.
As you may know The Gabe Kangas Association for Awesome is the branch of Gabe Kangas who&#39;s goal is to spread awesome both in local and remote markets. When the opportunity arose to take part this year team awesome jumped at the opportunity.
GKAFA has a long history of spreading awesome via sponsorships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The social experiment: #1 Peter Cales</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/the-social-experiment-#1-peter-cales/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 09:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/the-social-experiment-#1-peter-cales/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been laughed at. My sanity has been questioned. I&#39;ve even been told that the idea was all just a part of Skynet&#39;s plan for world domination. But I can now proudly say that &#34;the experiment&#34; (or The Creepy Twitter Experiment) can be executed successfully without death or even serious injury. As a refresher: I wrote a script to pick a person completely randomly from people I follow on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new social experiment</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/a-new-social-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 11:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/a-new-social-experiment/</guid>
      <description>If you remember back I recently had #TweetDinner. Where people a web site decided who my &#34;closest friends&#34; were all got together for dinner and hung out. It was a good time, I consider it a success. It doesn&#39;t hurt that they were cool people. So I think it&#39;s time for a new social experiment.
Currently I follow 340 people on Twitter. Some of them are automated entertainment sources, many of them are out of the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closest friends of Gabe #tweetdinner</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/06/closest-friends-of-gabe-#tweetdinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 22:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/06/closest-friends-of-gabe-#tweetdinner/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m certainly on a kick lately of wanting to take part in some social experimentation. So when this idea came to mind, I couldn&#39;t pass it up. The other day I jumped on a new Tweeter stats type thing. There&#39;s hundreds of them. This one is twitteranalyzer.com. After it analyzed my online social circle it determined who my &#34;closest friends&#34; were. Although all awesome people, they&#39;re not the people I&#39;ve spent the most time with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My BIG post on BIGOmaha</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/my-big-post-on-bigomaha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2009 16:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/my-big-post-on-bigomaha/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m not going to talk about what Big Omaha was, or was not in the &#34;Big Omaha brought the counties best and brightest creative blah blah blah&#34; type thing. I&#39;m not going to write much about what the speakers had to say. I&#39;m going to tell my tale of the first ever Big Omaha conference and the parts that mattered to me. This will probably be long and spread with random photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking news: Big Omaha proves how awesome Gabe is</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/breaking-news-big-omaha-proves-how-awesome-gabe-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/breaking-news-big-omaha-proves-how-awesome-gabe-is/</guid>
      <description>Big Omaha is a success. No doubt. The friendships that were built, the inspiration that filled multiple venues. It&#39;s a story that will be retold many times for the next year. But the real story took place online yesterday, when it was discussed how really awesome I am. Names hidden to protect the innocent.
[17:56] &amp;lt;OldFriend1&amp;gt; NewFriend from omaha? [17:56] &amp;lt;NewFriend&amp;gt; yep [17:57] &amp;lt;NewFriend&amp;gt; we met at the Big Omaha thing [17:57] &amp;lt;OldFriend2&amp;gt; ohhh [17:57] &amp;lt;OldFriend2&amp;gt; what did you think of gabe?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six months of being an Omahan ( #bigomaha )</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/six-months-of-being-an-omahan-#bigomaha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 15:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/six-months-of-being-an-omahan-#bigomaha/</guid>
      <description>So this week marks six months of living in Omaha. I can&#39;t help but look back to a simple blog post I made on August 1st, 2008. I wrote &#34;Do I want to move to Omaha? Not really.&#34; Now flash forward to May 2009 where my journey in Omaha has so little to do with the reason I came here in the first place.
It&#39;s mostly about the people for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick catch-up post</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/a-quick-catch-up-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 10:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/a-quick-catch-up-post/</guid>
      <description>I opened my blog editor here with an idea of what to post. Then I got side tracked, and I no longer remember what it was I planned on talking about. So instead this is just going to be a catch-up post. Sorry about that. I bought a new camera the other day. With BIGOmaha coming up I needed a way to document the event, so off to Nebraska Furniture Mart I went.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be at Big Omaha May 7th and 8th.  Seriously.</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/be-at-big-omaha-may-7th-and-8th.-seriously./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 10:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/be-at-big-omaha-may-7th-and-8th.-seriously./</guid>
      <description>Big Omaha is coming up. It&#39;s really your last chance right now to get tickets.
I&#39;d really love to try and convince you to go, but at this point, if this is your kind of thing... you&#39;re already not willing to miss it. However, if you&#39;re out of town, out of state... whatever, this is a GREAT chance to visit the amazing city of Omaha. Seriously. Get a ticket, and get your ass here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alright, I&#39;ll blog.  Leave me alone about it.</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/03/alright-ill-blog.-leave-me-alone-about-it./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 18:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/03/alright-ill-blog.-leave-me-alone-about-it./</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s a really exciting time right now. It&#39;s South by Southwest conference/festival time! And you know as well as I do what that means! Nothing.
I get really bitter this time every year. All the professional &#34;consultants&#34;, &#34;media experts&#34;, and &#34;freelancers&#34; all converge in Texas to talk about awesome things. While us lame kids with corporate jobs sit in our cubes and listen to them talk about how much fun they&#39;re having.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irregardless, it&#39;s time to cowboy up</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/irregardless-its-time-to-cowboy-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 14:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/irregardless-its-time-to-cowboy-up/</guid>
      <description>So I haven&#39;t blogged anything about my job since I&#39;ve moved to Omaha I don&#39;t think. Well, here&#39;s my first.Met our new &#34;uber manager&#34; today, or the manager of my manager. Let me put it simply, i&#39;m scared shitless. I can&#39;t think of someone I can relate to any less.
For hobbies, it&#39;s Huskers football. He also likes to fish and cook game. He said the word &#34;irregardless&#34; and told us to &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I should update more often.  Here&#39;s one.</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-should-update-more-often.-heres-one./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 15:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-should-update-more-often.-heres-one./</guid>
      <description>Hello, friends.
No huge updates going on. I&#39;ve been trying to get everything in order here, to the best of my ability. Unpacking boxes, putting things places. Got my surround sound kicking in my livingroom with my AppleTV attached. Have my two wireless networks running (802.11g and 802.11n as to not to share frequencies), and little by little going through clothes that are in boxes and putting them away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omaha meetup.com email I just got</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/omaha-meetup.com-email-i-just-got/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 00:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/omaha-meetup.com-email-i-just-got/</guid>
      <description>Slightly humorous highlights:
Ron Paul?
Huckabee for president 2008 meetup still active?
Church in the home.
The Newest Omaha Meetup Groups:
The Fremont D&amp;amp;D and Board Games Meetup Group
Play Group for Happy Crafters
Church in the Home
The Fremont Friends Meetup Group
What&#39;s Cooking Lincoln!
Omaha LGBT parents group
  This Week&#39;s Meetups
  Sunday, November 9, 2008
   1:00 PM
 Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons: D&amp;amp;D Game</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I like Omaha</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-like-omaha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 20:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-like-omaha/</guid>
      <description>I just ventured to downtown Omaha. It&#39;s the area I haven&#39;t been to yet. I went off the beaten path and found the area I heard so much about called &#34;Old Market&#34;. For a few blocks here, I don&#39;t feel like i&#39;m in Omaha anymore.
I found a coffee shop with wifi here, and that&#39;s where i&#39;m blogging from. Before this I went to a couple record stores. RECORD stores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I live in Omaha</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-live-in-omaha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 01:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-live-in-omaha/</guid>
      <description> Well, I&#39;m here. There&#39;s a lot to blog about, really. But it&#39;s midnight, and I don&#39;t think i&#39;d be able to do everything justice at this point. So at this point let me just offer up a couple videos I made. More to come!
Videos:
Gabe drives to Omaha
Gabe tours his apartment
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last day at the Chicago office</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/my-last-day-at-the-chicago-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 14:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/my-last-day-at-the-chicago-office/</guid>
      <description>So today i&#39;m saying my goodbye&#39;s at the Chicago office. There&#39;s a get together after work today at a local pub and it seems like a decent amount of people are going to be showing up. Just got back a few ago from my last ROM coffee run. My secret crush, Lilly, wasn&#39;t there, though.
My desk is clean, things are packed up for me to bring home... another chapter closed in the big book of relocation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 days to go/Photo montage</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/7-days-to-go/photo-montage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 16:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/7-days-to-go/photo-montage/</guid>
      <description>Seven days from today I&#39;ll be on my way to Omaha. A moving company is coming first thing Saturday morning to put everything on a truck and off I go. Sounds so simple.
In honor of me leaving, I put together a quick collection of some photos of random times/events/entertaining things that took place here. I have another week to make some more great memories, but here&#39;s a little selection so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good morning, Omaha</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/good-morning-omaha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 09:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/good-morning-omaha/</guid>
      <description>Was an exciting weekend to say the least. Friday night I went out with Jess, who&#39;s introducing me to some great people. Saturday and Sunday I met up with Jillian who&#39;s looking for apartments and is kind enough to let me tag along. And Saturday night I went to a coworker&#39;s party that followed the Alcohol + Fire = Burning Things rule. Here&#39;s the video!I have an application for one apartment, but that&#39;s it so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apartment hunting == not fun</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/apartment-hunting-not-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 17:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/apartment-hunting-not-fun/</guid>
      <description>Went out with Jillian today to look at apartments. She was really helpful. She&#39;s looking in the Dundee area just like I am. I&#39;m not sure how i&#39;d get anything done around here without all the helpful people i&#39;m meeting! The last lady I talked to sounded about 10 years past death. She sounded like she didn&#39;t believe what company I worked for because she&#39;s lived here all her life, and she&#39;s never heard of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello from Omaha!</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/hello-from-omaha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 22:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/hello-from-omaha/</guid>
      <description> Should I be blurring out the company name or something? I never know how to deal with that. Whatever. For all you know I work across the street at the Holiday Inn and I thought this logo was funny looking.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m in Omaha</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/im-in-omaha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 15:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/im-in-omaha/</guid>
      <description>Quick post. But i&#39;m here, alive, and working. How about that.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anyone shop online for clothes?  Aparently it&#39;s more difficult than I thought.</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/anyone-shop-online-for-clothes-aparently-its-more-difficult-than-i-thought./</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 14:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/anyone-shop-online-for-clothes-aparently-its-more-difficult-than-i-thought./</guid>
      <description>Seems like right now is the first time in a while i&#39;ve just been sitting around relaxing. Threw some laundry in, picked up a little. Probably get back to packing this weekend at some point.
A week from right now I&#39;ll already be in Omaha. Slightly surreal.
I&#39;m trying to go through online and bookmark new clothes, since I&#39;m having to go through an overhaul of my wardrobe. I can no longer wear concert tshirts and cartoon characters to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Omaha part 2</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/hello-omaha-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2008 11:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/hello-omaha-part-2/</guid>
      <description>So it&#39;s official. October will be the last month I live in the fine state of Illinois. Who would have ever thought, right? But yesterday I accepted the position in Omaha, NE with West.
My first day in my new role will be October 6th, so I gave West Notifications my 2 weeks yesterday. After that they&#39;re going to fly me out a couple times so I can find somewhere to live, meet my team, and get my move situated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>