<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>review on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/review/</link><description>Recent content in review on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 04:20:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gabe's 2012 Year in Review</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/12/gabes-2012-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 04:20:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/12/gabes-2012-year-in-review/</guid><description>It's time for my mostly-annual &amp;quot;stuff and things&amp;quot; post. I've missed some years, but I think I have more new stuff this time around. I'll try and detail all of the software, hardware and services that I've used this year to make my personal and professional life better or more interesting.\
Software ========
Desktop (OS X) Xcode.
Love it or hate it, I live in it. Actually, I don't know if I love it or hate it.</description></item><item><title>2010 Year in Review</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/2010-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 18:59:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/2010-year-in-review/</guid><description>I was planning on doing the @lasertron Radvent project more than I did, but after the first few I wasn't able to resonate with it anymore. They involved things that didn't make sense to me. Either making things, or interacting with people. Christmas parties, neighbors, etc. I didn't have any of these and I felt pretty lame. So instead I figured i'd write this blog post about 2010. I wish I could say I have a lot of detailed things to talk about that happened in the past year, but I really don't.</description></item><item><title>My thoughts on the Mophie Juicepack</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/10/my-thoughts-on-the-mophie-juicepack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 09:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/10/my-thoughts-on-the-mophie-juicepack/</guid><description>{.alignright width=&amp;quot;245&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;quot;245&amp;rdquo;}A few weeks ago I purchased the Mophie Juicepack Air in preperation for my trip to Chicago for my class reunion. When I announced on Twitter I was picking one up I had a few requests for my thoughts on it after some use. Admittedly, the new iPhone 3GS has substantially better battery live than the 3G. Very noticeable. However, there are times and situations where that's still not good enough.</description></item></channel></rss>