<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>project on Gabe Kangas</title>
    <link>https://gabekangas.com/categories/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in project on Gabe Kangas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en_US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:21:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/categories/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bat Player for AppleTV</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/project/thebatplayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/thebatplayer/</guid>
      <description>Listen to your favorite internet radio stations and discover new music, all through your Apple TV.
It’s a big screen experience, utilizing the space to present a beautiful interface focusing on details about each song and artist while entertaining visualizations bounce along to the music.
The Bat Player comes with a mix of curated stations and a directory that you can browse right out of the box, but any internet radio station can be added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bat Station</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/project/the-bat-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/the-bat-station/</guid>
      <description>The Bat Station is an internet radio station that categorizes itself as &amp;ldquo;Gothy and dancy, with a 90s twist&amp;rdquo;.
Gabe runs this station to not only share the music he loves with people, but also to generally increase the amount of internet radio stations that are available.
Audio Stream link for you to put in your player of choice.
Audio Stream link for you to put in your player of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longtail Music</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/project/longtail-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/longtail-music/</guid>
      <description>Longtail Music is a loosely connected network of independent internet radio stations where each station is independently run and managed, allowing for a wide variety of content and style.
In a world of algorithmically generated on-demand streaming products, sponsored playlists and an overabundance of Top 40 music videos flooding the social networks it&amp;rsquo;s time to find another approach to finding unique music that you&amp;rsquo;ll love.
There is an entire community of live stations, each with their own deep knowledge of a specific slice of music who are sharing their music tastes, recommendations and content 24/7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TheCabin for Android</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/project/thecabin-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/thecabin-for-android/</guid>
      <description>#TheCabin for Android is a native Android application for accessing #TheCabin, an Internet Relay Chat channel.
There used to be chat rooms where you can meet new friends and be a part of a community with people from all over the world, and one such place still exists.
#TheCabin started in 1995 and has had the opportunity to have people from all over the world become friends through it. And while #TheCabin isn’t a dating site, multiple marriages have even taken place after people met there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TheCabin for iOS</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/project/thecabin-for-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/thecabin-for-ios/</guid>
      <description>#TheCabin for iOS is a native iPhone and iPad application for accessing #TheCabin, an Internet Relay Chat channel.
There used to be chat rooms where you can meet new friends and be a part of a community with people from all over the world, and one such place still exists.
#TheCabin started in 1995 and has had the opportunity to have people from all over the world become friends through it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TheCabin Web Chat</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/project/thecabin-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/thecabin-web/</guid>
      <description>#TheCabin for the web is a React web app that allows users to chat on Internet Relay Chat from a browser.
There used to be chat rooms where you can meet new friends and be a part of a community with people from all over the world, and one such place still exists.
#TheCabin started in 1995 and has had the opportunity to have people from all over the world become friends through it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>node-internet-radio</title>
      <link>https://gabekangas.com/project/node-internet-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/node-internet-radio/</guid>
      <description>Node.js module to get Now Playing information from an internet radio stream in the form of the following object:
{ listeners: &#39;89&#39;, bitrate: &#39;128&#39;, title: &#39;Die Antwoord - I Fink U Freaky&#39;, fetchsource: &#39;SHOUTCAST_V1&#39; } The syntax is simple:
getStationInfo(url, callback, [method]); Install npm install node-internet-radio This Node.js module supports three different methods to fetch the station details of an internet radio stream. All but fetching details from the raw audio stream give you the currently playing track, bitrate, and listener count.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>