<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>audio on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/audio/</link><description>Recent content in audio on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/audio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Owncast Livestream Dec 3, 2020</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/dec-3-2020/dec-3-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/dec-3-2020/dec-3-2020/</guid><description>Download here.
Another fun Owncast test stream! I went a bit more trancey this time and I thought it was a good mix of tunes.
On the downside, however, there was some troubleshooting required during the set, so there was some excessive looping required to buy myself some time. Oh well, that&amp;rsquo;s live streaming for you!
Tracklist 00:00:00 Alexander Metzger - Police Radio Intro (Time Bandits Mix) 00:00:00 Moby - Too Much Change (KAS:ST Remix) 00:04:20 Space 92 - Run (Original Mix) 00:11:00 The Second Wave - Fallen Star (Original Mix) 00:14:57 i_o - Castles In The Sky (Extended Mix) 00:22:24 STUDIO-X vs.</description></item><item><title>Gabe @ Owncast Stream Sept 17, 2020</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/gabe-owncast-stream-sept-17-2020/gabe-owncast-stream-sept-17-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/gabe-owncast-stream-sept-17-2020/gabe-owncast-stream-sept-17-2020/</guid><description>Download audio here.
We all got together to listen to some music and hang out while testing the next release of Owncast last night.
I had a blast, and it seems like everyone else did too. This continuted tradition of getting together to hang out on a live stream to beta test is really pretty great. Everyone enjoys themselves, we get feedback about Owncast, and it exercises the work that&amp;rsquo;s been done on the software.</description></item><item><title>Owncast Stream July 28, 2020</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/owncast-stream-july-28-2020/owncast-stream-july-28-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/owncast-stream-july-28-2020/owncast-stream-july-28-2020/</guid><description>Download here.
More Owncast testing! Had a fantastic time streaming some tunes for friends. Everyone seemed to enjoy themselves, and I got some good testing in from everyone visiting the Owncast server. Win, win!
Here’s an audio recording of the evening.
Tracklist 00:00:00 Daft Punk - Technologic (Deborah De Luca Edit) 00:01:16 Nine Inch Nails - Closer To God 00:06:38 AESTHETISCHE - Cold Bliss MMXX 00:11:04 artillery nightspace - renouncing the agent 00:14:05 Faderhead - I Did Not Know (feat.</description></item><item><title>Owncast Test Stream</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/owncast-test-stream-2020-07-07/owncast-test-stream-2020-07-07/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/owncast-test-stream-2020-07-07/owncast-test-stream-2020-07-07/</guid><description>On July 7th, 2020 I did a live video stream to test Owncast. This is the audio recording from that video. It was cool to have people drop by, listen to some music, and help test out the server. I really appreciate the time anybody spends to help me test things, since when it comes to things like Owncast it needs to be used to be tested. And people need to tune in for me to get any useful data out of it.</description></item><item><title>Shelter in Place at The Bat Station #2</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-2-may-13-2020/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-2-may-13-2020/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-2/</guid><description>May 13, 2020. Another live stream mix on The Bat Station! This was my first time doing a mix using Rekordbox, so I’m a little rusty with it. I tried to be a little more creative in chopping things up in real-time that caters to my inner musician tendencies. It’s cool to treat DJ hardware as an instrument. I had fun, and I hope you enjoy the music I picked out.</description></item><item><title>Shelter in Place at The Bat Station Mix</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-mix-apri-24-2020/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-mix-apri-24-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-mix-apri-24-2020/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-mix-apri-24-2020/</guid><description>This is the first time I did a public live stream on The Bat Station. A handful of people tuned in and it was pretty cool. I figured if it all fell apart I could just not share the recording, but it turned out ok.
I&amp;rsquo;m still not great a this whole mixing thing, but I&amp;rsquo;m getting better, and it&amp;rsquo;s fun to share this new hobby and show you all my progress!</description></item><item><title>Gabe's 90s Dance Mix</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/gabe-s-90s-dance-mix/gabe-s-90s-dance-mix/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/gabe-s-90s-dance-mix/gabe-s-90s-dance-mix/</guid><description> For fun I wanted to do a little mix with some 90s dance tracks. I unapologetically love that stuff. I still don’t know how to DJ or mix tracks properly, but I’m enjoying myself.</description></item></channel></rss>