<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Work on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/work/</link><description>Recent content in Work on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A personal update about career and the future</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2021/04/a-personal-update-about-career-and-the-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2021/04/a-personal-update-about-career-and-the-future/</guid><description>Before COVID hit I was about three years into working at a pretty cool company as an iOS engineer. I joined the company before the product launched and had a great time. But like things do, sometimes you grow apart when the company gets bigger and priorities change. So at the point everyone started working from home full time it became increasingly more difficult and I decided to leave the company.</description></item><item><title>When work becomes life: A Pandemic story</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/03/when-work-becomes-life-a-pandemic-story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/03/when-work-becomes-life-a-pandemic-story/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s no lack of thinkpieces around the lockdowns and global work from home changes taking place. But I wanted to discuss a different angle that people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be discussing, at least publicly.
Right now the internet is flooded with screenshots of Zoom video conferences, everyone smiling, talking about their cute background images and how comfortable it is to be home. They&amp;rsquo;re talking about how they&amp;rsquo;re working more efficient than ever, how they can just roll out of bed and immediately start working.</description></item><item><title>Embarrassment is embarrassing.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/10/embarrassment-is-embarrassing./</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/10/embarrassment-is-embarrassing./</guid><description>I haven't updated many people on what i've been up to lately. And there's a simple reason for that: embarrassment. It's not fun to talk about being a failure. Part of me didn't want to be dramatic in telling a story and having people read into things, but I'll try to be a little more transparent and see where that gets me. Maybe the last thing you knew was that Hollrback launched, I was traveling around talking to amazing people about it, and getting awesome feedback.</description></item><item><title>I've been quiet! I've been busy!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/01/ive-been-quiet-ive-been-busy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/01/ive-been-quiet-ive-been-busy/</guid><description>I haven't blogged for quite a while. And that's not a bad thing. It's been a couple months now since I left my position at West, and I haven't said a word about it since then. There's no real reason why except I've been super busy. Busy with a handful of really awesome things.
I've had the chance to work on some really neat projects lately, and I'm really looking forward to continuing it.</description></item><item><title>Choices, decisions and fear: Part 2.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/choices-decisions-and-fear-part-2./</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:22:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/choices-decisions-and-fear-part-2./</guid><description>I'm a fan of transparency. I like to know what people are up to, and I think there are people that like to know what I'm up to as well. This includes the background and emotions behind major life decisions. So here's my story. If you're reading this you already know it's been a rough couple months as far as my career path goes. I knew I needed to move elsewhere, but I didn't know in what capacity.</description></item><item><title>The freedom of choice. The fear of making the wrong ones.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/the-freedom-of-choice.-the-fear-of-making-the-wrong-ones./</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 17:10:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/the-freedom-of-choice.-the-fear-of-making-the-wrong-ones./</guid><description>To anyone from work who may come upon this post: hi.
If you would have asked me what I wanted to do for a living even just a few years ago I would have described the job I have now. Heck, even as a kid I envisioned (after wanting to be an astronaut) sitting in a big building somewhere with lots of people in front of a computer cranking out tasks.</description></item><item><title>Mourning the loss of an office</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/mourning-the-loss-of-an-office/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/mourning-the-loss-of-an-office/</guid><description>Yesterday it was announced that the office I used to work at in Chicago, and who many still work at will be closing at the end of October. I understand that business is business, but these are my friends. Friends that believed my company when they acquired it a couple years ago and said &amp;quot;this office and everyone in it is going nowhere. We value the employees here and we're keeping this Chicago office.</description></item><item><title>A quick catch-up post</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/a-quick-catch-up-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 10:21:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/a-quick-catch-up-post/</guid><description>I opened my blog editor here with an idea of what to post. Then I got side tracked, and I no longer remember what it was I planned on talking about. So instead this is just going to be a catch-up post. Sorry about that. I bought a new camera the other day. With BIGOmaha coming up I needed a way to document the event, so off to Nebraska Furniture Mart I went.</description></item><item><title>Next step... there is no next step. Yet.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/next-step...-there-is-no-next-step.-yet./</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 15:10:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/next-step...-there-is-no-next-step.-yet./</guid><description>I love hearing people's plans for the future. If they're graduating from college, or just have their first real job and have big plans... hearing that stuff is cool. Having vision and goals are what keep people alive. You need to be driven to continue to do something. A stagnant life isn't really life at all. I've been thinking about that a lot lately. What is my next step? And I don't mean personally, or professionally.</description></item><item><title>Irregardless, it's time to cowboy up</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/irregardless-its-time-to-cowboy-up/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 14:44:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/irregardless-its-time-to-cowboy-up/</guid><description>So I haven't blogged anything about my job since I've moved to Omaha I don't think. Well, here's my first.Met our new &amp;quot;uber manager&amp;quot; today, or the manager of my manager. Let me put it simply, i'm scared shitless. I can't think of someone I can relate to any less.
For hobbies, it's Huskers football. He also likes to fish and cook game. He said the word &amp;quot;irregardless&amp;quot; and told us to &amp;quot;cowboy up&amp;quot;.</description></item></channel></rss>