<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hollrback on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/hollrback/</link><description>Recent content in hollrback on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 10:05:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/hollrback/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Another adventure begins. Goodbye Omaha.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/01/another-adventure-begins.-goodbye-omaha./</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 10:05:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/01/another-adventure-begins.-goodbye-omaha./</guid><description>My time in Omaha is coming to an end. On Friday, February 3rd I'll have relocated to San Francisco. When looking back at the past three years it's hard to decide what to put in this rather long retrospective post. But I'll use it as my last opportunity to highlight, clarify, give thanks, and try to explain why I'm taking on this new adventure.
I moved to Omaha thinking I'd have to dodge cows on the way to the office every day.</description></item><item><title>Embarrassment is embarrassing.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/10/embarrassment-is-embarrassing./</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/10/embarrassment-is-embarrassing./</guid><description>I haven't updated many people on what i've been up to lately. And there's a simple reason for that: embarrassment. It's not fun to talk about being a failure. Part of me didn't want to be dramatic in telling a story and having people read into things, but I'll try to be a little more transparent and see where that gets me. Maybe the last thing you knew was that Hollrback launched, I was traveling around talking to amazing people about it, and getting awesome feedback.</description></item><item><title>Boulder Startup Week 2011</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/05/boulder-startup-week-2011/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/05/boulder-startup-week-2011/</guid><description>So on the recommendation of my friend @sethhwilson in the hour before the deadline I half-assed an email to @ryanwanger of Boulder Startup Week for their "We'll fly you to Boulder free" offer. They were going to hand pick a handful of people and bring them in for the event. I honestly kind of forgot about it, and I really only did it as one of those "take advantage of opportunity because you never know"</description></item></channel></rss>