<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Bat Player for AppleTV</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/project/thebatplayer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/thebatplayer/</guid><description>Listen to your favorite internet radio stations and discover new music, all through your Apple TV.
It’s a big screen experience, utilizing the space to present a beautiful interface focusing on details about each song and artist while entertaining visualizations bounce along to the music.
The Bat Player comes with a mix of curated stations and a directory that you can browse right out of the box, but any internet radio station can be added.</description></item><item><title>The Bat Station</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/project/the-bat-station/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/the-bat-station/</guid><description>The Bat Station is an internet radio station that categorizes itself as &amp;ldquo;Gothy and dancy, with a 90s twist&amp;rdquo;.
Gabe runs this station to not only share the music he loves with people, but also to generally increase the amount of internet radio stations that are available.
Audio Stream link for you to put in your player of choice.
Audio Stream link for you to put in your player of choice.</description></item><item><title>Longtail Music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/project/longtail-music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/longtail-music/</guid><description>Longtail Music was a loosely connected network of independent internet radio stations where each station is independently run and managed, allowing for a wide variety of content and style.
In a world of algorithmically generated on-demand streaming products, sponsored playlists and an overabundance of Top 40 music videos flooding the social networks it&amp;rsquo;s time to find another approach to finding unique music that you&amp;rsquo;ll love.
There is an entire community of live stations, each with their own deep knowledge of a specific slice of music who are sharing their music tastes, recommendations and content 24/7.</description></item><item><title>Owncast Livestream Dec 3, 2020</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/dec-3-2020/dec-3-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/dec-3-2020/dec-3-2020/</guid><description>Download here.
Another fun Owncast test stream! I went a bit more trancey this time and I thought it was a good mix of tunes.
On the downside, however, there was some troubleshooting required during the set, so there was some excessive looping required to buy myself some time. Oh well, that&amp;rsquo;s live streaming for you!
Tracklist 00:00:00 Alexander Metzger - Police Radio Intro (Time Bandits Mix) 00:00:00 Moby - Too Much Change (KAS:ST Remix) 00:04:20 Space 92 - Run (Original Mix) 00:11:00 The Second Wave - Fallen Star (Original Mix) 00:14:57 i_o - Castles In The Sky (Extended Mix) 00:22:24 STUDIO-X vs.</description></item><item><title>Gabe @ Owncast Stream Sept 17, 2020</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/gabe-owncast-stream-sept-17-2020/gabe-owncast-stream-sept-17-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/gabe-owncast-stream-sept-17-2020/gabe-owncast-stream-sept-17-2020/</guid><description>Download audio here.
We all got together to listen to some music and hang out while testing the next release of Owncast last night.
I had a blast, and it seems like everyone else did too. This continuted tradition of getting together to hang out on a live stream to beta test is really pretty great. Everyone enjoys themselves, we get feedback about Owncast, and it exercises the work that&amp;rsquo;s been done on the software.</description></item><item><title>Owncast Stream July 28, 2020</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/owncast-stream-july-28-2020/owncast-stream-july-28-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/owncast-stream-july-28-2020/owncast-stream-july-28-2020/</guid><description>Download here.
More Owncast testing! Had a fantastic time streaming some tunes for friends. Everyone seemed to enjoy themselves, and I got some good testing in from everyone visiting the Owncast server. Win, win!
Here’s an audio recording of the evening.
Tracklist 00:00:00 Daft Punk - Technologic (Deborah De Luca Edit) 00:01:16 Nine Inch Nails - Closer To God 00:06:38 AESTHETISCHE - Cold Bliss MMXX 00:11:04 artillery nightspace - renouncing the agent 00:14:05 Faderhead - I Did Not Know (feat.</description></item><item><title>Owncast Test Stream</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/owncast-test-stream-2020-07-07/owncast-test-stream-2020-07-07/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/owncast-test-stream-2020-07-07/owncast-test-stream-2020-07-07/</guid><description>On July 7th, 2020 I did a live video stream to test Owncast. This is the audio recording from that video. It was cool to have people drop by, listen to some music, and help test out the server. I really appreciate the time anybody spends to help me test things, since when it comes to things like Owncast it needs to be used to be tested. And people need to tune in for me to get any useful data out of it.</description></item><item><title>Shelter in Place at The Bat Station #2</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-2-may-13-2020/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-2-may-13-2020/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-2/</guid><description>May 13, 2020. Another live stream mix on The Bat Station! This was my first time doing a mix using Rekordbox, so I’m a little rusty with it. I tried to be a little more creative in chopping things up in real-time that caters to my inner musician tendencies. It’s cool to treat DJ hardware as an instrument. I had fun, and I hope you enjoy the music I picked out.</description></item><item><title>Shelter in Place at The Bat Station Mix</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-mix-apri-24-2020/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-mix-apri-24-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-mix-apri-24-2020/shelter-in-place-at-the-bat-station-mix-apri-24-2020/</guid><description>This is the first time I did a public live stream on The Bat Station. A handful of people tuned in and it was pretty cool. I figured if it all fell apart I could just not share the recording, but it turned out ok.
I&amp;rsquo;m still not great a this whole mixing thing, but I&amp;rsquo;m getting better, and it&amp;rsquo;s fun to share this new hobby and show you all my progress!</description></item><item><title>Gabe's 90s Dance Mix</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/gabe-s-90s-dance-mix/gabe-s-90s-dance-mix/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/mixes/gabe-s-90s-dance-mix/gabe-s-90s-dance-mix/</guid><description> For fun I wanted to do a little mix with some 90s dance tracks. I unapologetically love that stuff. I still don’t know how to DJ or mix tracks properly, but I’m enjoying myself.</description></item><item><title>A journey through my music tastes</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/03/a-journey-through-my-music-tastes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/03/a-journey-through-my-music-tastes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this blog post as a draft for a couple months now. And who knows how long it would have stayed as a draft, but Keith Flint of The Prodigy died this week, and given how much I owe to The Prodigy being one of my earliest electronic loves, I felt I should actually publish it.
My music taste and the different artists that I've listened to throughout my life is a big part of my identity.</description></item><item><title>Obsessed with the new Blaqk Audio single</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/junk/2019-01-16-obsessed_with_the_new_blaqk_audio_single/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/junk/2019-01-16-obsessed_with_the_new_blaqk_audio_single/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m completely hooked on this new Blaqk Audio single. The new album isn&amp;rsquo;t out until March, but I&amp;rsquo;m very much looking forward to it if it&amp;rsquo;s as good as this song is. Plus they&amp;rsquo;re touring, so that&amp;rsquo;s super exciting.</description></item><item><title>I will never understand people who do not enjoy psytrance</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/junk/2019-01-13-i_will_never_understand_people_who_do_not_enjoy_psytrance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/junk/2019-01-13-i_will_never_understand_people_who_do_not_enjoy_psytrance/</guid><description>So many people think of psytrance as some lesser genre. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why. How can you not love this?</description></item><item><title>Introducing Longtail Music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2017/04/introducing-longtail-music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2017/04/introducing-longtail-music/</guid><description>It's no secret I've been frustrated with music discovery for a while. Ever since Rdio shut down I've listened to less music on mainstream services. While I do have a Spotify account, I tend to only use it to listen to old playlists and comfort music. Where music discovery has been successful for me, however, is with internet radio. Having a person with deep knowledge within a certain style hand-picking tracks for me every day has proven time and time again that it's a system that works.</description></item><item><title>Radvent Dec 5 - #Radvent tunage</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-5-#radvent-tunage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 20:06:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-5-#radvent-tunage/</guid><description>Create the soundtrack of your year.
Now THIS is more like it! Though to be honest I feel like I talk about music to people so often I don't know what to put here that's worth reading.
It's actually pretty easy for me to find what I've been listening to this past year because of Last.FM. In fact here is my 12 month chart in detail. However, this year I haven't really been "</description></item><item><title>Lost and Found: A video experiment started in 2006</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/lost-and-found-a-video-experiment-started-in-2006/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 13:57:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/lost-and-found-a-video-experiment-started-in-2006/</guid><description>In 2006 I was diligently working on my (still unreleased) new album "The Longest Post". With that I decided to create a couple music videos both as an experiment on if I could make something fun, and to have a visual way to distribute some songs. A couple apartment moves later and the hard drives with the music videos were lost.
Until now. In October, 2010 I found the hard drives while cleaning out my music studio and decided it was time to show them to the world.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Song Recommendation: Mark Mallman - Mother Made Me Do It</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/weekly-song-recommendation-mark-mallman-mother-made-me-do-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/weekly-song-recommendation-mark-mallman-mother-made-me-do-it/</guid><description>I haven't done a music recommendation post in a while. It's certainly not weekly, but I'm not changing the naming. I don't know, stopped feeling inspired, I guess. Well fuck if I don't feel inspired now.
I've always been a fan of Mark Mallman's. It started, like many of artists I enjoy do, seeing a show of theirs without knowing who they were beforehand. This is a prime example of the Gabe Kangas music/movie introduction theory.</description></item></channel></rss>