<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>big omaha on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/big-omaha/</link><description>Recent content in big omaha on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 18:54:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/big-omaha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to communicate, by Gary Vaynerchuk</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/how-to-communicate-by-gary-vaynerchuk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 18:54:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/how-to-communicate-by-gary-vaynerchuk/</guid><description>What great conversation between Gary Vaynerchuk, the internet and I today. There's something invigorating about a really constructive conversation where you come out of it feeling better about the topic than when you went in. While it's a great business and brand technique, the world would in general be a much better place if it happened more often. Gary reached out to me after reading my blog post that I had Alex (@alexpgates) check out, and wanted to clear up any miscommunication with me, and everyone else on how he's seen or interpreted.</description></item><item><title>My BIG post on BIGOmaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/my-big-post-on-bigomaha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2009 16:26:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/my-big-post-on-bigomaha/</guid><description>I'm not going to talk about what Big Omaha was, or was not in the "Big Omaha brought the counties best and brightest creative blah blah blah" type thing. I'm not going to write much about what the speakers had to say. I'm going to tell my tale of the first ever Big Omaha conference and the parts that mattered to me. This will probably be long and spread with random photos.</description></item><item><title>Breaking news: Big Omaha proves how awesome Gabe is</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/breaking-news-big-omaha-proves-how-awesome-gabe-is/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/breaking-news-big-omaha-proves-how-awesome-gabe-is/</guid><description>Big Omaha is a success. No doubt. The friendships that were built, the inspiration that filled multiple venues. It's a story that will be retold many times for the next year. But the real story took place online yesterday, when it was discussed how really awesome I am. Names hidden to protect the innocent.
[17:56] &amp;lt;OldFriend1&amp;gt; NewFriend from omaha? [17:56] &amp;lt;NewFriend&amp;gt; yep [17:57] &amp;lt;NewFriend&amp;gt; we met at the Big Omaha thing [17:57] &amp;lt;OldFriend2&amp;gt; ohhh [17:57] &amp;lt;OldFriend2&amp;gt; what did you think of gabe?</description></item><item><title>Quick Big Omaha video</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/quick-big-omaha-video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 13:42:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/quick-big-omaha-video/</guid><description> In time I'll absolutely make a post about BigOmaha. How can I not? But until then, check out this compilation (that's pretty speaker specific, but whatever) of photos that is visually entertaining, but not at all showing the energy of the event.
Big Omaha from Mike Malone on Vimeo.</description></item></channel></rss>