<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>the bat player on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/the-bat-player/</link><description>Recent content in the bat player on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 09:41:48 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/the-bat-player/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apple Has Shut Down The Bat Player</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/08/apple-has-shut-down-the-bat-player/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 09:41:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/08/apple-has-shut-down-the-bat-player/</guid><description>Today The Bat Player on AppleTV was shut down. I wanted to document a bit about the history of the application, and why it&amp;rsquo;s being rejected from the Apple AppStore.
I started The Bat Player in 2014. I wanted a better Internet Radio experience on the TV. I dreamt of artist info, album details and photos. At the time most Internet Radio apps just showed text of the currently playing track and I wanted more.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye Longtail Music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/12/goodbye-longtail-music/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:21:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/12/goodbye-longtail-music/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I shut down Longtail Music, my internet radio discovery platform. I wanted to give a bit of a postmortem to talk about what I sent out to do, what it did, and why I think things never worked out.
I originally built Longtail Music as a spinoff from my time with The Bat Player, an internet radio client for the TV. I thought if The Bat Player was a client for people who already love internet radio and know what they want to listen to, then I want to build something on the web for people to discover internet radio for the first time and discover a station they would love.</description></item><item><title>Why I love developing for the Apple TV</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2016/07/why-i-love-developing-for-the-apple-tv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 15:37:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2016/07/why-i-love-developing-for-the-apple-tv/</guid><description>tvOS isn’t getting the credit it deserves. I've found Apple TV the platform that I’ve had the most fun developing for in a long time.
The television is the physically largest canvas currently available. What has been a central point of the living room has historically been the most difficult thing to break into. The number of people willing to build awkwardly horrible “Samsung apps”, for example, are very few.</description></item></channel></rss>