<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>owncast on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/owncast/</link><description>Recent content in owncast on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/owncast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Owncast v0.1.0 Retrospective - Redesign</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2023/02/owncast-v0.1.0-retrospective-redesign/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2023/02/owncast-v0.1.0-retrospective-redesign/</guid><description>With Owncast v0.1.0 in a bug fixing and early testing phase now, I thought I’d write some blog posts about what it’s been like to work on the project. A lot of projects don’t go into depth about how the sausage is made, but I still think people are interested in what’s going on even though they don&amp;rsquo;t go out of their way to ask.</description></item><item><title>Decentralized discovery</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/08/decentralized-discovery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/08/decentralized-discovery/</guid><description>Often the first thing brought up when discussing decentralized content is the difficulty of discovery. Big Tech has all these data points combining the content on their platform with all the consumers so they can make educated guesses to route people to content that benefit the platform, data brokers, advertisers, governments, and lastly somewhere down the line the consumers. How can those who want to opt out of those networks compete in this game?</description></item><item><title>Being a part of a team</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/05/being-a-part-of-a-team/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/05/being-a-part-of-a-team/</guid><description>Growing up I was never a sports person, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend a lot of time on what you&amp;rsquo;d call &amp;ldquo;typical&amp;rdquo; teams. But I was heavily into the performing arts all throughout my youth. This included different organized groups such as choirs, theater performances, and both competitive and non-competitive bands of all kinds, including the stereotypical high school garage band. This continued on even after high school, where I took part in a couple competitive Drum &amp;amp; Bugle corps.</description></item><item><title>A brief update on Owncast</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/12/a-brief-update-on-owncast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/12/a-brief-update-on-owncast/</guid><description>I made a post when I pushed up my initial idea of Owncast to GitHub, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted any status updates to my own website since then. There&amp;rsquo;s been some significant traction lately, so I wanted to take a moment to write an update.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been making steady progress under the radar with a fantastic group of people who have discovered the project. We knew that once we completed our Owncast web admin feature that we&amp;rsquo;d let a few more people know about the status of things, since it&amp;rsquo;s an added level of polish and ease of use that might appeal to people.</description></item></channel></rss>