<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A personal update about career and the future</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2021/04/a-personal-update-about-career-and-the-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2021/04/a-personal-update-about-career-and-the-future/</guid><description>Before COVID hit I was about three years into working at a pretty cool company as an iOS engineer. I joined the company before the product launched and had a great time. But like things do, sometimes you grow apart when the company gets bigger and priorities change. So at the point everyone started working from home full time it became increasingly more difficult and I decided to leave the company.</description></item><item><title>A brief update on Owncast</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/12/a-brief-update-on-owncast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/12/a-brief-update-on-owncast/</guid><description>I made a post when I pushed up my initial idea of Owncast to GitHub, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted any status updates to my own website since then. There&amp;rsquo;s been some significant traction lately, so I wanted to take a moment to write an update.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been making steady progress under the radar with a fantastic group of people who have discovered the project. We knew that once we completed our Owncast web admin feature that we&amp;rsquo;d let a few more people know about the status of things, since it&amp;rsquo;s an added level of polish and ease of use that might appeal to people.</description></item><item><title>Apple Has Shut Down The Bat Player</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/08/apple-has-shut-down-the-bat-player/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 09:41:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/08/apple-has-shut-down-the-bat-player/</guid><description>Today The Bat Player on AppleTV was shut down. I wanted to document a bit about the history of the application, and why it&amp;rsquo;s being rejected from the Apple AppStore.
I started The Bat Player in 2014. I wanted a better Internet Radio experience on the TV. I dreamt of artist info, album details and photos. At the time most Internet Radio apps just showed text of the currently playing track and I wanted more.</description></item><item><title>Owncast: A project to take control over your own live streaming</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/06/owncast-a-project-to-take-control-over-your-own-live-streaming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/06/owncast-a-project-to-take-control-over-your-own-live-streaming/</guid><description>Backstory. In 2020 the world changed when everyone become stuck in their homes, looking for creative outlets to share their art, skills and themselves from inside their bedroom.
This created an explosion of live streaming on Facebook Live, YouTube, Instagram, and Twitch. These services provided everything they needed, an easy way to live stream to the world, and a chat for users to be a part of their community.</description></item><item><title>Some recent projects for my DJ mix hobby</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/05/some-recent-projects-for-my-dj-mix-hobby/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/05/some-recent-projects-for-my-dj-mix-hobby/</guid><description>While the lockdowns have been going on, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t been working (I&amp;rsquo;ll probably blog about that soon), I&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping busy with other projects.
I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up a new hobby of doing some DJ mixes, streaming them on internet radio, and recording them for sharing with friends. This has led me to building some tooling around all of this stuff that I think, for a small population, might find useful.</description></item><item><title>When work becomes life: A Pandemic story</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/03/when-work-becomes-life-a-pandemic-story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/03/when-work-becomes-life-a-pandemic-story/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s no lack of thinkpieces around the lockdowns and global work from home changes taking place. But I wanted to discuss a different angle that people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be discussing, at least publicly.
Right now the internet is flooded with screenshots of Zoom video conferences, everyone smiling, talking about their cute background images and how comfortable it is to be home. They&amp;rsquo;re talking about how they&amp;rsquo;re working more efficient than ever, how they can just roll out of bed and immediately start working.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye Longtail Music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/12/goodbye-longtail-music/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:21:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/12/goodbye-longtail-music/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I shut down Longtail Music, my internet radio discovery platform. I wanted to give a bit of a postmortem to talk about what I sent out to do, what it did, and why I think things never worked out.
I originally built Longtail Music as a spinoff from my time with The Bat Player, an internet radio client for the TV. I thought if The Bat Player was a client for people who already love internet radio and know what they want to listen to, then I want to build something on the web for people to discover internet radio for the first time and discover a station they would love.</description></item><item><title>It's time a for change: I'm trying Linux on the desktop</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/05/its-time-a-for-change-im-trying-linux-on-the-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/05/its-time-a-for-change-im-trying-linux-on-the-desktop/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve felt lousy about the internet, software, computers and technology lately. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve abandoned a project of mine and that made me feel pretty bad. It made me think about my relationship with my personal computer and the things I use it for. I realized once I removed macOS and iOS software development from things I use my computer for I&amp;rsquo;m not really tied to a Mac. And though I love macOS, Macintosh computers, and the entire Apple ecosystem, I just needed to look at something else for a while and rekindle that passion I have for my computer.</description></item><item><title>I'm discontinuing work on Mastochist for Mastodon</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/04/im-discontinuing-work-on-mastochist-for-mastodon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/04/im-discontinuing-work-on-mastochist-for-mastodon/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m no longer going to continue work on my Mastodon client, Mastochist. And even though it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really impact anybody but myself, I felt I owed people a detailed explanation and apology since people have heard me talk about the work I&amp;rsquo;ve put in it for quite a while.
Mostly I owe an apology to Cara who I hired to design the look of the app, and she became my sounding board as I built out features.</description></item><item><title>A journey through my music tastes</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/03/a-journey-through-my-music-tastes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/03/a-journey-through-my-music-tastes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this blog post as a draft for a couple months now. And who knows how long it would have stayed as a draft, but Keith Flint of The Prodigy died this week, and given how much I owe to The Prodigy being one of my earliest electronic loves, I felt I should actually publish it.
My music taste and the different artists that I've listened to throughout my life is a big part of my identity.</description></item><item><title>Working with others on personal projects</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/working-with-others-on-personal-projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/working-with-others-on-personal-projects/</guid><description>I like working with other people. I like having people to throw ideas off of, and having sanity checks for approaches I&amp;rsquo;m taking with things. I like the additional creativity that happens when you have another voice in the conversation and I like learning from people who know more about a topic than I do.
This is generally pretty difficult with personal projects. And for whatever reason many of my projects start with me using a technology I&amp;rsquo;ve never used before.</description></item><item><title>Can we encourage Facebook employees to go elsewhere?</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/can-we-encourage-facebook-employees-to-go-elsewhere/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/can-we-encourage-facebook-employees-to-go-elsewhere/</guid><description>I was walking to work this morning past a group of Facebook employees waiting for their bus. I wanted to say something to them. While I didn&amp;rsquo;t, it got me thinking, what if?
What if I actually stopped to say something? Would it turn confrontational? Would they ignore me? What if I had an encouraging, positive, standardized statement that said &amp;ldquo;Hey, you&amp;rsquo;re really fucking good at your job. You have options.</description></item><item><title>New web site for 2019</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/01/new-web-site-for-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/01/new-web-site-for-2019/</guid><description>If you look back at my recent 2018 Year in Review you know I was toying with the idea of updating my web site to use a static site generator. As you can see, I went through with it. Let me explain a bit of the process, and my rationalization behind it all.
I last did a major refresh of my web site about 6 years ago where I went from self-hosting a Wordpress blog to moving everything over to Squarespace.</description></item><item><title>My 2018 in review</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2018/12/my-2018-in-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 20:53:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2018/12/my-2018-in-review/</guid><description>I figured enough has taken place this year, enough changes have taken place, and I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on enough projects that a post recapping things might be worthwhile.
To start, here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist of my favorite songs of the year that you can listen to while reading this post.
{=html} &amp;lt;iframe class=&amp;quot;embedly-embed&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;//cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fopen.spotify.com%2Fembed%2Fuser%2Fgabek%2Fplaylist%2F19O9V2b18geBYuRWo17fqb&amp;amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fopen.spotify.com%2Fuser%2Fgabek%2Fplaylist%2F19O9V2b18geBYuRWo17fqb&amp;amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fmosaic.scdn.co%2F640%2F7f289e90ddb7bb04b51abcb0a0c8abc9e073d089997f86b60c8f790386efa16144af5e3ccc7c523be28ee5d01614983310f16f1f3746586affdf2f57ff72bd8dc442fbeeb681d09e36c4598982c578b8&amp;amp;amp;key=61d05c9d54e8455ea7a9677c366be814&amp;amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;amp;schema=spotify&amp;amp;amp;wmode=opaque&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;380&amp;quot; scrolling=&amp;quot;no&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; allow=&amp;quot;autoplay; fullscreen&amp;quot; allowfullscreen=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; So what did I do with this year?</description></item><item><title>Your internet sucks.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2018/07/your-internet-sucks./</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 15:53:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2018/07/your-internet-sucks./</guid><description>I've been very disheartened with the internet recently. Between Twitter's Nazis and Facebook's data collection, ad policies and democracy manipulation, I've begun to feel like the internet that I loved was gone. And as more people almost exclusively spend time using services that are run by corporate entities, these services are systematically killing off third party access to their content in order to lock you into an experience that they control.</description></item><item><title>Why your tech stack matters (It's not why you think)</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2018/02/why-your-tech-stack-matters-its-not-why-you-think/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 17:32:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2018/02/why-your-tech-stack-matters-its-not-why-you-think/</guid><description>Recently I've received a lot of messages from recruiters looking for an iOS developer to build with React Native. And while I generally don't care what technologies people are selecting to build their products, I find this to be a subject that I think warrants a deeper dive. But a disclaimer up front: I have a bias, and I only speak for me, not for any team I'm currently or have been a part of.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Longtail Music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2017/04/introducing-longtail-music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2017/04/introducing-longtail-music/</guid><description>{=html} &amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/214576527?wmode=opaque&amp;amp;amp;api=1&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;640&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;360&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Longtail Music Promo&amp;quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; It's no secret I've been frustrated with music discovery for a while. Ever since Rdio shut down I've listened to less music on mainstream services. While I do have a Spotify account, I tend to only use it to listen to old playlists and comfort music.
Where music discovery has been successful for me, however, is with internet radio.</description></item><item><title>Why I love developing for the Apple TV</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2016/07/why-i-love-developing-for-the-apple-tv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 15:37:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2016/07/why-i-love-developing-for-the-apple-tv/</guid><description>&amp;lt;!--?xml version=&amp;quot;1.0&amp;quot; encoding=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; standalone=&amp;quot;no&amp;quot;?--&amp;gt;{=html}
tvOS isn&amp;rsquo;t getting the credit it deserves. I've found Apple TV the platform that I&amp;rsquo;ve had the most fun developing for in a long time.
The television is the physically largest canvas currently available. What has been a central point of the living room has historically been the most difficult thing to break into. The number of people willing to build awkwardly horrible &amp;ldquo;Samsung apps&amp;rdquo;, for example, are very few.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye, Rdio</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/11/goodbye-rdio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 17:41:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/11/goodbye-rdio/</guid><description>Like everybody else, I felt like I had heard every song on Pandora by the time I discovered Rdio. I was user number 4075, a paid unlimited user, signing up on June 6, 2010. I was really happy to hear anything I wanted. I used the Rdio Desktop client to create a collection on the service with my local iTunes Library. I listened to it a lot.
Like many others, I moved to Spotify once it finally came to the US.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye, Rdio</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/11/goodbye-rdio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 17:41:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/11/goodbye-rdio/</guid><description>Like everybody else, I felt like I had heard every song on Pandora by the time I discovered Rdio. I was user number 4075, a paid unlimited user, signing up on June 6, 2010. I was really happy to hear anything I wanted. I used the Rdio Desktop client to create a collection on the service with my local iTunes Library. I listened to it a lot.
Like many others, I moved to Spotify once it finally came to the US.</description></item><item><title>Launching The Bat Player on the Roku Store and its aftermath</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/07/launching-the-bat-player-on-the-roku-store-and-its-aftermath/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 16:39:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/07/launching-the-bat-player-on-the-roku-store-and-its-aftermath/</guid><description>After a year of development The Bat Player went live on Roku's Channel Store.
The Bat Player first went public in September of last year. This means if you knew the right Roku Channel Code you could install it on your device. I put up a web site to make this easier, and shared it with a couple specific communities like the Roku forums and Reddit's Roku subreddit.
My goal all along was to get it available in their mainstream directory.</description></item><item><title>Developing for Roku</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2014/12/developing-for-roku/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2014/12/developing-for-roku/</guid><description>{=html} &amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/112659447?wmode=opaque&amp;amp;amp;api=1&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1280&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;720&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;The Bat Player&amp;quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; Ask yourself, &amp;quot;Do I know anybody who's developed anything for the Roku Media Player?&amp;quot; More than likely the answer is no. If you ask others you might get get some response, but more than likely nobody you know has done it either.
And that's why I wanted to throw up a little piece about building for the Roku.</description></item><item><title>Seeing my first Drum Corps show in 10 years</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2014/06/seeing-my-first-drum-corps-show-in-10-years/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 21:54:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2014/06/seeing-my-first-drum-corps-show-in-10-years/</guid><description>I haven't seen a drum corps live since I was in The Racine Kilties in 2004. I don't know if it was me doing the Chinese New Year parade with The Renegades this year, or if enough time has passed where I was ready to see a show again, but I did. DCI West at Stanford took place this weekend and I thought I'd chronicle a few thoughts I have about the activity (as ruled by DCI).</description></item><item><title>Building TastemakerX for iOS</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/12/building-tastemakerx-for-ios/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 19:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/12/building-tastemakerx-for-ios/</guid><description>It's still in beta, and I'm still happily iterating over all of the features of the application, but I wanted to share the tools I used, the services I take advantage of, and overall tidbits that might be useful to fellow developers about how I've been building TastemakerX. Maybe you can in turn share some things with me.
Tools that made my life easier. &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-
Spark Inspector
Spark Inspector Both it and Reveal popped up around the same time, but since then I've been using Spark Inspector as a tool to debug view-related things.</description></item><item><title>My thoughts and experiences on the Pebble Smart Watch</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/02/my-thoughts-and-experiences-on-the-pebble-smart-watch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:54:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/02/my-thoughts-and-experiences-on-the-pebble-smart-watch/</guid><description>LIke with a lot of things in life I told myself I didn't want one. And then when it came down to it I realized I was lying to myself and I actually did.
This was the story behind the Pebble Smart Watch. Once people started getting them delivered, and I read this review I knew I must have it. Luckily Criagslist exists and people were selling theirs. Watch acquired.</description></item><item><title>Stuff I'd like to do in 2013</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/01/stuff-id-like-to-do-in-2013/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 18:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/01/stuff-id-like-to-do-in-2013/</guid><description>I'm not a fan of New Years resolutions, but there are some things I'd like to do in this next year. All very doable things, but if you think that in any way you'd be able to help with any of them I'd certainly be up for pointers!
Contribute to an open source project that focuses on a) mobile and b) something I care about. (Note: I checked out the Colloquy source last night and started looking at their bug list to see if I could help with anything).</description></item><item><title>Gabe's 2012 Year in Review</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/12/gabes-2012-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 04:20:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/12/gabes-2012-year-in-review/</guid><description>It's time for my mostly-annual &amp;quot;stuff and things&amp;quot; post. I've missed some years, but I think I have more new stuff this time around. I'll try and detail all of the software, hardware and services that I've used this year to make my personal and professional life better or more interesting.\
Software ========
Desktop (OS X) Xcode.
Love it or hate it, I live in it. Actually, I don't know if I love it or hate it.</description></item><item><title>Respect for gender goes both ways. A rant from a modern male.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/09/respect-for-gender-goes-both-ways.-a-rant-from-a-modern-male./</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 00:36:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/09/respect-for-gender-goes-both-ways.-a-rant-from-a-modern-male./</guid><description>I'll probably upset a lot of people because this is something that people just don't talk about, and would be seen as weak if said out loud. But here it is: I'm sick of the male stereotype.
You know how &amp;quot;woman, get in the kitchen!&amp;quot; is a totally not ok thing to say? For so many reasons, not just because it's demeaning, and it attempts to put someone in their place, but also as a person.</description></item><item><title>I've lived in San Francisco for a while</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/07/ive-lived-in-san-francisco-for-a-while/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 10:23:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/07/ive-lived-in-san-francisco-for-a-while/</guid><description>I was asked a few weeks back why I haven't written a post on my blog since I've been to San Francisco. I mean, there must be a lot of stuff to talk about, right? It's a pretty significant move and maybe the world wants to hear me blab about it. But I think in general I have been blabbing about it, but in more specific channels. But that's not to say I shouldn't have a larger periodic update.</description></item><item><title>Another adventure begins. Goodbye Omaha.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/01/another-adventure-begins.-goodbye-omaha./</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 10:05:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2012/01/another-adventure-begins.-goodbye-omaha./</guid><description>My time in Omaha is coming to an end. On Friday, February 3rd I'll have relocated to San Francisco. When looking back at the past three years it's hard to decide what to put in this rather long retrospective post. But I'll use it as my last opportunity to highlight, clarify, give thanks, and try to explain why I'm taking on this new adventure.
I moved to Omaha thinking I'd have to dodge cows on the way to the office every day.</description></item><item><title>Embarrassment is embarrassing.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/10/embarrassment-is-embarrassing./</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/10/embarrassment-is-embarrassing./</guid><description>I haven't updated many people on what i've been up to lately. And there's a simple reason for that: embarrassment. It's not fun to talk about being a failure. Part of me didn't want to be dramatic in telling a story and having people read into things, but I'll try to be a little more transparent and see where that gets me. Maybe the last thing you knew was that Hollrback launched, I was traveling around talking to amazing people about it, and getting awesome feedback.</description></item><item><title>Boulder Startup Week 2011</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/05/boulder-startup-week-2011/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/05/boulder-startup-week-2011/</guid><description>So on the recommendation of my friend @sethhwilson in the hour before the deadline I half-assed an email to @ryanwanger of Boulder Startup Week for their &amp;quot;We'll fly you to Boulder free&amp;quot; offer. They were going to hand pick a handful of people and bring them in for the event. I honestly kind of forgot about it, and I really only did it as one of those &amp;quot;take advantage of opportunity because you never know&amp;quot; kind of things that I'm trying to be proactive about.</description></item><item><title>2010 Year in Review</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/2010-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 18:59:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/2010-year-in-review/</guid><description>I was planning on doing the @lasertron Radvent project more than I did, but after the first few I wasn't able to resonate with it anymore. They involved things that didn't make sense to me. Either making things, or interacting with people. Christmas parties, neighbors, etc. I didn't have any of these and I felt pretty lame. So instead I figured i'd write this blog post about 2010. I wish I could say I have a lot of detailed things to talk about that happened in the past year, but I really don't.</description></item><item><title>Radvent Dec 5 - #Radvent tunage</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-5-#radvent-tunage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 20:06:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-5-#radvent-tunage/</guid><description>{.aligncenter .size-medium .wp-image-14617 width=&amp;ldquo;232&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;}
Create the soundtrack of your year.
Now THIS is more like it! Though to be honest I feel like I talk about music to people so often I don't know what to put here that's worth reading.
It's actually pretty easy for me to find what I've been listening to this past year because of Last.FM. In fact here is my 12 month chart in detail.</description></item><item><title>Radvent Dec 3 - Sexy notes to yourself</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-3-sexy-notes-to-yourself/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 14:46:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-3-sexy-notes-to-yourself/</guid><description>{.size-medium .wp-image-14032 .aligncenter width=&amp;ldquo;232&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;}
Write a letter of love to yourself to read again in one year. And then some stuff that has to do with getting away from the computer.
If you haven't noticed, I'm going to ignore the parts of this project that deals with getting away from the computer and doing things. That's not really my jam. Journal, stamps, special pens, beautiful paper, stickers, glue, etc... not things I own.</description></item><item><title>Radvent Dec 2 - Organize</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-2-organize/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 10:04:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-2-organize/</guid><description>{.aligncenter .size-medium .wp-image-13905 width=&amp;ldquo;231&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;}
Spend 15minutes on a drawer, table or surface &amp;amp; make it pretty.
I don't do pretty. See you tomorrow.</description></item><item><title>Radvent Dec 1</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 11:36:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-1/</guid><description>So @lasertron is doing a thing, beginning with her blog over at PrincessLasertron.com, where she's issuing a blog topic every day throughout the month of December. She asked some others if they'd be willing to join her, and here I am. I'm not so bold to think I'll actually blog every day this month, but I'll try.
Enough of that, here's #1. @lasertron writes:
{.aligncenter .size-medium .wp-image-13648 width=&amp;ldquo;231&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;}
What were you doing five years ago today?</description></item><item><title>Barcamp Omaha 2010 was rad (and the jam was fun)</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/11/barcamp-omaha-2010-was-rad-and-the-jam-was-fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 16:41:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/11/barcamp-omaha-2010-was-rad-and-the-jam-was-fun/</guid><description>{.aligncenter width=&amp;ldquo;640&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;360&amp;rdquo;}Thanks to the organization team of Barcamp2010 here in Omaha it was another great event. Learned some stuff and had some fun. Also thanks to everyone to indulged me in my attempt for a lunchtime jam session. I can't honestly say it was the most musical thing ever performed, but we all had fun anyway :) Thanks to everyone who took part! It was nice to mix things up a bit.</description></item><item><title>Barcamp 2010: The Musical</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/11/barcamp-2010-the-musical/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 19:04:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/11/barcamp-2010-the-musical/</guid><description>I've been thinking about what I wanted to do for Barcamp this year. I was chatting over lunch today with this week's Coworking Wednesday participants about how I wished there was something different I could do. Something collaborative and break the mold of what an unconference session should be. I mentioned music stuff and @whatevermatt mentioned a drum circle. I thought about that a while (at least 2 to 3 minutes) later that day (today) and thought I'd see if I could pull something off.</description></item><item><title>Lost and Found: A video experiment started in 2006</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/lost-and-found-a-video-experiment-started-in-2006/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 13:57:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/lost-and-found-a-video-experiment-started-in-2006/</guid><description>In 2006 I was diligently working on my (still unreleased) new album &amp;quot;The Longest Post&amp;quot;. With that I decided to create a couple music videos both as an experiment on if I could make something fun, and to have a visual way to distribute some songs. A couple apartment moves later and the hard drives with the music videos were lost.
Until now. In October, 2010 I found the hard drives while cleaning out my music studio and decided it was time to show them to the world.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Song Recommendation: Mark Mallman - Mother Made Me Do It</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/weekly-song-recommendation-mark-mallman-mother-made-me-do-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/weekly-song-recommendation-mark-mallman-mother-made-me-do-it/</guid><description>I haven't done a music recommendation post in a while. It's certainly not weekly, but I'm not changing the naming. I don't know, stopped feeling inspired, I guess. Well fuck if I don't feel inspired now.
I've always been a fan of Mark Mallman's. It started, like many of artists I enjoy do, seeing a show of theirs without knowing who they were beforehand. This is a prime example of the Gabe Kangas music/movie introduction theory.</description></item><item><title>#TheCabin Mobile for iPhone</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/09/#thecabin-mobile-for-iphone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 15:43:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/09/#thecabin-mobile-for-iphone/</guid><description>I've always said if I took all the time and effort I spent into side projects and spent them on something else I'd have a lot of cool other things. But I've spent some nights and weekends working on this new little app, my first submission to the iTunes App Store. (Approved in 8 days, FYI) As some of you may know, for the past 15 years I've been helping manage an internet relay chat (IRC) channel I started called #TheCabin.</description></item><item><title>Equilibrium had it right</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/07/equilibrium-had-it-right/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 18:49:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/07/equilibrium-had-it-right/</guid><description>I'm a person of logic. Things that I don't see I don't believe. Things that don't make sense I don't assume to be true. Faith isn't really a thing I take part in, and I do things when I see a reason to. I let logic determine my decisions in life, but unfortunately there's circumstance where not only do I let that slide, but it goes completely in the other direction.</description></item><item><title>TechStars for a Day, startup culture, and my comparisons to Omaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/05/techstars-for-a-day-startup-culture-and-my-comparisons-to-omaha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 13:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/05/techstars-for-a-day-startup-culture-and-my-comparisons-to-omaha/</guid><description>Alright, stay with me. I promise you'll get something at the end. I don't promise you'll like it, though. I attended TechStars for a Day in Seattle. If you want to know what this rockin' organization does check it out. But in short, they are a business accelerator. Get your company off the ground in the most awesome way possible.
It seemed like a classic case of serendipity. I was behind the controls at Big Omaha helping the speakers tell their inspiring stories when an email invite came in from TechStars to join them in Seattle to hear more about the program and to give them an opportunity to meet me.</description></item><item><title>I was asked what I've been doing. So here you go!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/04/i-was-asked-what-ive-been-doing.-so-here-you-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2010 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/04/i-was-asked-what-ive-been-doing.-so-here-you-go/</guid><description>I struggled on what should be included in this post. A part of me thinks having a veil over personal feelings about things that I'm doing are a good thing. But that's the opposite of transparency, and I do want to take as many people on the wild ride with me as possible. A while back my buddy Frank said my next blog post should be about what I'm doing. It wasn't until then that I realized from the outside (especially outside of Omaha), what I do, what my goals are, and my what daily routine is may seem a little odd, if not completely invisible.</description></item><item><title>I survived South by Southwest Interactive 2010</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/03/i-survived-south-by-southwest-interactive-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 00:36:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/03/i-survived-south-by-southwest-interactive-2010/</guid><description>Writing a wrap-up post about South by Southwest I would imagine is similar to writing about being teleported to another universe for a short time. A universe where there are no words that a human can make to explain the things they saw. So in that vein let me tell you that it was so.&amp;hellip; yeah. Thanks everyone, have a great weekend.
Alright, I'll give this a shot. It was everything I thought it could be, and more.</description></item><item><title>Gabe takes on South by Southwest Interactive 2010</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/03/gabe-takes-on-south-by-southwest-interactive-2010/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 19:26:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/03/gabe-takes-on-south-by-southwest-interactive-2010/</guid><description>One of the things I've convinced myself of in this past year is that if there's something I want to do, then I should do it.{.alignleft .size-medium .wp-image-1523 width=&amp;ldquo;218&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;240&amp;rdquo;} Sounds simple right? But not so much. In this particular example, South by Southwest, it's something I've wanted to attend for years. But instead of just deciding I was going to go I wallowed in my cube and read/watched what was going on in the week long center of the world.</description></item><item><title>I've been quiet! I've been busy!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/01/ive-been-quiet-ive-been-busy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/01/ive-been-quiet-ive-been-busy/</guid><description>I haven't blogged for quite a while. And that's not a bad thing. It's been a couple months now since I left my position at West, and I haven't said a word about it since then. There's no real reason why except I've been super busy. Busy with a handful of really awesome things.
I've had the chance to work on some really neat projects lately, and I'm really looking forward to continuing it.</description></item><item><title>The Windows 7 Launch Party</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/the-windows-7-launch-party/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 20:19:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/the-windows-7-launch-party/</guid><description>I meant to put this together weeks ago, but I guess things got in the way. But Windows 7 is released only once in a lifetime, so I couldn't just forget about it. Earlier this month @shinyhat threw a Microsoft sanctioned Windows 7 launch party and he invited me along for the ride. It had all of the stuff that Microsoft sent him. Posters, streamers, playing cards, poker chips, a puzzle, and even a Microsoft trivia game.</description></item><item><title>Gabe's tools of the trade</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/gabes-tools-of-the-trade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 14:45:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/gabes-tools-of-the-trade/</guid><description>This isn't the first time I've made a post like this. In fact I used to make a yearly recap of all the tools, software, hardware, etc that made me productive that year. For whatever reason I didn't this past year. Not sure why. Guess I was busy hanging out with you or something. Inspired by Andy Peter's Barcamp Omaha talk I thought I'd share some non-obvious things I use to do things on a daily basis.</description></item><item><title>Choices, decisions and fear: Part 2.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/choices-decisions-and-fear-part-2./</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:22:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/choices-decisions-and-fear-part-2./</guid><description>I'm a fan of transparency. I like to know what people are up to, and I think there are people that like to know what I'm up to as well. This includes the background and emotions behind major life decisions. So here's my story. If you're reading this you already know it's been a rough couple months as far as my career path goes. I knew I needed to move elsewhere, but I didn't know in what capacity.</description></item><item><title>My thoughts on the Mophie Juicepack</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/10/my-thoughts-on-the-mophie-juicepack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 09:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/10/my-thoughts-on-the-mophie-juicepack/</guid><description>{.alignright width=&amp;ldquo;245&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;245&amp;rdquo;}A few weeks ago I purchased the Mophie Juicepack Air in preperation for my trip to Chicago for my class reunion. When I announced on Twitter I was picking one up I had a few requests for my thoughts on it after some use. Admittedly, the new iPhone 3GS has substantially better battery live than the 3G. Very noticeable. However, there are times and situations where that's still not good enough.</description></item><item><title>Reflecting on my ten year High School reunion</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/10/reflecting-on-my-ten-year-high-school-reunion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:55:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/10/reflecting-on-my-ten-year-high-school-reunion/</guid><description>I didn't originally want to go. But to everyone who told me I should: Thank you. Everyone knows I didn't know what to expect. But now that the Grant Community High School class of 1999 reunion is over I can't help but look at those four years far different than I did before. I'll be honest and tell you that I really did discount that time. It wasn't awful, but I was glad it was behind me.</description></item><item><title>Ten year class reunion</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/ten-year-class-reunion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 07:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/ten-year-class-reunion/</guid><description>Wow, ten years since I graduated high school. Many probably will say &amp;quot;it seems like only yesterday&amp;quot; but to me it seems much, much longer. In fact, to be honest, I hardly remember those four years at all. Sure some special moments stand out that included performances or things with friends, but on the whole... really, nothing. I wasn't planning on going to the reunion. It wasn't until my friend Becky from high school asked me to go did I cave and signed up and booked a flight.</description></item><item><title>Gabe Kangas Association for Awesome is proud to sponsor Omaha Bar Camp 2009</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/gabe-kangas-association-for-awesome-is-proud-to-sponsor-omaha-bar-camp-2009/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 00:53:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/gabe-kangas-association-for-awesome-is-proud-to-sponsor-omaha-bar-camp-2009/</guid><description>{width=&amp;ldquo;170&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;170&amp;rdquo;} The Gabe Kangas Association for Awesome (GKAFA) is proud to announce they will be sponsoring this year's Omaha Bar Camp.
As you may know The Gabe Kangas Association for Awesome is the branch of Gabe Kangas who's goal is to spread awesome both in local and remote markets. When the opportunity arose to take part this year team awesome jumped at the opportunity.
GKAFA has a long history of spreading awesome via sponsorships.</description></item><item><title>The freedom of choice. The fear of making the wrong ones.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/the-freedom-of-choice.-the-fear-of-making-the-wrong-ones./</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 17:10:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/the-freedom-of-choice.-the-fear-of-making-the-wrong-ones./</guid><description>To anyone from work who may come upon this post: hi.
If you would have asked me what I wanted to do for a living even just a few years ago I would have described the job I have now. Heck, even as a kid I envisioned (after wanting to be an astronaut) sitting in a big building somewhere with lots of people in front of a computer cranking out tasks.</description></item><item><title>Happy Labor Day!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/happy-labor-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 00:18:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/happy-labor-day/</guid><description>Hope you all have a great one. I'm on call starting 5pm today! You're supposed to watch this every Labor Day.</description></item><item><title>NIN for the last time. For real this time. Chicago.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/nin-for-the-last-time.-for-real-this-time.-chicago./</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 10:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/nin-for-the-last-time.-for-real-this-time.-chicago./</guid><description>{.size-thumbnail .wp-image-1241 width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;} Friday morning started like any other Friday morning. By Friday afternoon I found out that Andy Peters and I were headed to Chicago that night to see one of the last performances of our favorite band, Nine Inch Nails.
A while back Skid Vis surprised Andy and I by telling us he hooked us up with tickets to the completely sold out Nine Inch Nails show in Chicago.</description></item><item><title>The social experiment: #1 Peter Cales</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/the-social-experiment-#1-peter-cales/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 09:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/the-social-experiment-#1-peter-cales/</guid><description>I've been laughed at. My sanity has been questioned. I've even been told that the idea was all just a part of Skynet's plan for world domination. But I can now proudly say that &amp;quot;the experiment&amp;quot; (or The Creepy Twitter Experiment) can be executed successfully without death or even serious injury. As a refresher: I wrote a script to pick a person completely randomly from people I follow on Twitter. I wanted to meet those who we mutually follow, but never met.</description></item><item><title>Admiral Ackbar joins Twitter</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/admiral-ackbar-joins-twitter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 15:39:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/admiral-ackbar-joins-twitter/</guid><description>Per recommendation of @EternalCow I built a bot that puts a much needed appearance of Admiral Ackbar (@AdmiralAckbar_) on Twitter. He's warning (as he should be) to all who will listen that &amp;quot;It's a trap!&amp;quot; This is funny, but the most entertaining part is the fact that people are replying back.
See below for a real time update of responses to &amp;quot;It's a trap!&amp;quot;
I'll soon have itsatrap.org up :P</description></item><item><title>A new social experiment</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/a-new-social-experiment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 11:18:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/a-new-social-experiment/</guid><description>If you remember back I recently had #TweetDinner. Where people a web site decided who my &amp;quot;closest friends&amp;quot; were all got together for dinner and hung out. It was a good time, I consider it a success. It doesn't hurt that they were cool people. So I think it's time for a new social experiment.
Currently I follow 340 people on Twitter. Some of them are automated entertainment sources, many of them are out of the area.</description></item><item><title>Interactions with people and communities, while not having an important common bond.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/interactions-with-people-and-communities-while-not-having-an-important-common-bond./</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 13:22:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/interactions-with-people-and-communities-while-not-having-an-important-common-bond./</guid><description>It's no secret how much I respect my all of my peers in Omaha. Some of the most talented, most creative, friendliest, amazing people ever. But as I learn more about organizations and people here I do see a thread that is often a strong bond between many of them. And that is the Christian belief community here.
There are some really great organizations, from Core Community to inCommon. Smart people in like minded organizations who in a very modern and effective way get together as groups to learn and assist others.</description></item><item><title>Ice, Ice, Baby. Too cold.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/ice-ice-baby.-too-cold./</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2009 22:25:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/ice-ice-baby.-too-cold./</guid><description>Word to your mother.&amp;lt;object width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;allowfullscreen&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html} &amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;allowscriptaccess&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;always&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html} &amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;movie&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=5900578&amp;amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;amp;fullscreen=1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html} &amp;lt;embed src=&amp;quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=5900578&amp;amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;amp;fullscreen=1&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&amp;quot; allowfullscreen=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; allowscriptaccess=&amp;quot;always&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/embed&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/object&amp;gt;{=html}
Gabe performing Ice Ice Baby in Bellevue from Gabe Kangas on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Seattle trip recap</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/seattle-trip-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 11:12:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/seattle-trip-recap/</guid><description>I had a nice trip to Seattle last week. It was really for work purposes, they were sending me to F5 LTM training, but I knew I'd be able to make it into a fun vacation as well. I had no plans when going there, but that rarely stops me from having a good time. {.alignleft width=&amp;ldquo;206&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;155&amp;rdquo;}Thanks to Twitter, and my blog, you're able to see a step by step recap of my whole trip by accessing my Twitter archive page for the week.</description></item><item><title>My interview about Retweet Thursday</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/my-interview-about-retweet-thursday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 11:29:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/my-interview-about-retweet-thursday/</guid><description>Well who would have thought? The fine people over at Silicon Prairie News were interested in talking to me about the weirdest meme to ever hit Twitter (aside from #MufasaMonday I suppose), #retweet_thursday. They told me they weren't sure who was behind it at first, but figured out it was out of Omaha somewhere, so they pinpointed it to me. I never really made it public that the bot was run by me, but I wasn't really hiding the fact either :)</description></item><item><title>Making a leap</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/making-a-leap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 10:20:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/making-a-leap/</guid><description>I'm going to be a real ass-hat with this post, and I apologize. I'm not going to tell any details, but instead I'm just going to type and you can be annoyed afterwards. I've been working on a project. And at first I thought it was going to go one direction, but then I decided to take it a different direction in my execution of it.
Previous projects I've worked on usually have a life cycle that includes me wanting to build something, I work a lot in all of my spare time on it, putting out a version, and then being drained from my &amp;quot;day job&amp;quot; and unable to continue to work on it anymore.</description></item><item><title>Mourning the loss of an office</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/mourning-the-loss-of-an-office/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/mourning-the-loss-of-an-office/</guid><description>Yesterday it was announced that the office I used to work at in Chicago, and who many still work at will be closing at the end of October. I understand that business is business, but these are my friends. Friends that believed my company when they acquired it a couple years ago and said &amp;quot;this office and everyone in it is going nowhere. We value the employees here and we're keeping this Chicago office.</description></item><item><title>The military creeps me out</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/the-military-creeps-me-out/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 11:10:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/the-military-creeps-me-out/</guid><description>So being this is my blog, and I'm really bad at hiding things, once in a while I'll probably write about something pretty unpopular. This will be one of those posts. I'm taking the opportunity this day of independence to write about our military. Now if you're one of those &amp;quot;rah-rah&amp;quot; folks who reply with things like &amp;quot;you should be thanking them for fighting for you&amp;quot; then please do us both a favor and stop reading right now.</description></item><item><title>Closest friends of Gabe #tweetdinner</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/06/closest-friends-of-gabe-#tweetdinner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 22:01:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/06/closest-friends-of-gabe-#tweetdinner/</guid><description>I'm certainly on a kick lately of wanting to take part in some social experimentation. So when this idea came to mind, I couldn't pass it up. The other day I jumped on a new Tweeter stats type thing. There's hundreds of them. This one is twitteranalyzer.com. After it analyzed my online social circle it determined who my &amp;quot;closest friends&amp;quot; were. Although all awesome people, they're not the people I've spent the most time with.</description></item><item><title>A goodbye to an old friend</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/a-goodbye-to-an-old-friend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 10:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/a-goodbye-to-an-old-friend/</guid><description>This post was originally published at ChannelOmaha.com where Gabe is a guest blogger.
I can&amp;rsquo;t think of a more inappropriate first blog to ChanelOmaha.com than a story about how I traveled to Kansas City. But that&amp;rsquo;s just how this is going to be.
On Wednesday night I traveled to Kansas City to say goodbye to an old friend.
I arrived, got comfortable, and heard him tell the same stories he&amp;rsquo;s told so many times before.</description></item><item><title>Where friendship and responsibility collides in a community</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/where-friendship-and-responsibility-collides-in-a-community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 14:57:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/where-friendship-and-responsibility-collides-in-a-community/</guid><description>In the years I've had this blog I've rearely talked about the nitty-gritty of running an IRC channel. In theory, there's not much to it. But in reality, it's a community of people, many who have been there for many, many years. This is where a large group of my friends are. All types of people from all over the world.
But lately the topic of respect and seniority has been brought up more and more often.</description></item><item><title>How to communicate, by Gary Vaynerchuk</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/how-to-communicate-by-gary-vaynerchuk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 18:54:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/how-to-communicate-by-gary-vaynerchuk/</guid><description>What great conversation between Gary Vaynerchuk, the internet and I today. There's something invigorating about a really constructive conversation where you come out of it feeling better about the topic than when you went in. While it's a great business and brand technique, the world would in general be a much better place if it happened more often. Gary reached out to me after reading my blog post that I had Alex (@alexpgates) check out, and wanted to clear up any miscommunication with me, and everyone else on how he's seen or interpreted.</description></item><item><title>My BIG post on BIGOmaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/my-big-post-on-bigomaha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2009 16:26:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/my-big-post-on-bigomaha/</guid><description>I'm not going to talk about what Big Omaha was, or was not in the &amp;quot;Big Omaha brought the counties best and brightest creative blah blah blah&amp;quot; type thing. I'm not going to write much about what the speakers had to say. I'm going to tell my tale of the first ever Big Omaha conference and the parts that mattered to me. This will probably be long and spread with random photos.</description></item><item><title>Breaking news: Big Omaha proves how awesome Gabe is</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/breaking-news-big-omaha-proves-how-awesome-gabe-is/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/breaking-news-big-omaha-proves-how-awesome-gabe-is/</guid><description>Big Omaha is a success. No doubt. The friendships that were built, the inspiration that filled multiple venues. It's a story that will be retold many times for the next year. But the real story took place online yesterday, when it was discussed how really awesome I am. Names hidden to protect the innocent.
[17:56] &amp;lt;OldFriend1&amp;gt; NewFriend from omaha? [17:56] &amp;lt;NewFriend&amp;gt; yep [17:57] &amp;lt;NewFriend&amp;gt; we met at the Big Omaha thing [17:57] &amp;lt;OldFriend2&amp;gt; ohhh [17:57] &amp;lt;OldFriend2&amp;gt; what did you think of gabe?</description></item><item><title>Quick Big Omaha video</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/quick-big-omaha-video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 13:42:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/quick-big-omaha-video/</guid><description>In time I'll absolutely make a post about BigOmaha. How can I not? But until then, check out this compilation (that's pretty speaker specific, but whatever) of photos that is visually entertaining, but not at all showing the energy of the event. &amp;lt;object width=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; data=&amp;quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=4581735&amp;amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;amp;fullscreen=1&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;allowfullscreen&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html} &amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;allowscriptaccess&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;always&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html} &amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;src&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=4581735&amp;amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;amp;fullscreen=1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/object&amp;gt;{=html}
Big Omaha from Mike Malone on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Six months of being an Omahan ( #bigomaha )</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/six-months-of-being-an-omahan-#bigomaha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 15:48:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/six-months-of-being-an-omahan-#bigomaha/</guid><description>So this week marks six months of living in Omaha. I can't help but look back to a simple blog post I made on August 1st, 2008. I wrote &amp;quot;Do I want to move to Omaha? Not really.&amp;quot; Now flash forward to May 2009 where my journey in Omaha has so little to do with the reason I came here in the first place.
It's mostly about the people for me.</description></item><item><title>Search engine queries are funny</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/search-engine-queries-are-funny/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 21:31:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/search-engine-queries-are-funny/</guid><description>{=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; ity com &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}22&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html} 36% gabe kangas &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}5 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}8% december &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}3 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}5% pandora fm &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}3 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}5% drumline grant high school &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}2 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}3% {=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; ugliest desktop&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}2 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}3% real-ity com &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}2 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}3% #heart_tuesday &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% desperate housewives images of gabes house &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% {=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; gabek &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% ity download &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% arcade cabin com &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% annotify &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% tweply &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% {=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; shake like me streaming &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% music &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% ity &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% albums &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% incognito1027 &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% {=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; kazuho okui married &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% october &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% gabe long 2009 &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% gabekangas &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% {=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; kutcher / king / diddydumdum on cnn &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% download crack addict 4 (2005) &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% caprica boobs &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% {=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; gabekangas com &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% pandorafm &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;count_result&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}1 &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}2% {=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>A quick catch-up post</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/a-quick-catch-up-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 10:21:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/05/a-quick-catch-up-post/</guid><description>I opened my blog editor here with an idea of what to post. Then I got side tracked, and I no longer remember what it was I planned on talking about. So instead this is just going to be a catch-up post. Sorry about that. I bought a new camera the other day. With BIGOmaha coming up I needed a way to document the event, so off to Nebraska Furniture Mart I went.</description></item><item><title>Be at Big Omaha May 7th and 8th. Seriously.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/be-at-big-omaha-may-7th-and-8th.-seriously./</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 10:39:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/be-at-big-omaha-may-7th-and-8th.-seriously./</guid><description>{.alignnone .size-full .wp-image-846 width=&amp;ldquo;254&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;188&amp;rdquo;} Big Omaha is coming up. It's really your last chance right now to get tickets.
I'd really love to try and convince you to go, but at this point, if this is your kind of thing... you're already not willing to miss it. However, if you're out of town, out of state... whatever, this is a GREAT chance to visit the amazing city of Omaha. Seriously.</description></item><item><title>Next step... there is no next step. Yet.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/next-step...-there-is-no-next-step.-yet./</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 15:10:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/next-step...-there-is-no-next-step.-yet./</guid><description>I love hearing people's plans for the future. If they're graduating from college, or just have their first real job and have big plans... hearing that stuff is cool. Having vision and goals are what keep people alive. You need to be driven to continue to do something. A stagnant life isn't really life at all. I've been thinking about that a lot lately. What is my next step? And I don't mean personally, or professionally.</description></item><item><title>Tweetup #4</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/tweetup-#4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2009 09:29:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/tweetup-#4/</guid><description>Omaha Tweetup #4 is over. All together, not bad. But certainly the curve his heading downward in the &amp;quot;coolness&amp;quot; chart. It seems as it gets more successful, in better venues, the less charm the event has.
The first tweetup had about 40 people there. It's the first time I met a lot of great people. Not only people I'd start following on Twitter for the first time, but people that are now friends of mine.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the new face of Gabe</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/welcome-to-the-new-face-of-gabe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 01:27:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/welcome-to-the-new-face-of-gabe/</guid><description>Real-ity.com has a long standing history. One that I don't take lightly. &amp;quot;Gabe's Digital Life v3.1337&amp;quot; at real-ity.com was born five or so years ago. Before that it was another, much more simple blog. And before that, collections of links. This dating all the way back to 1997. As my friend BobbyT once said, &amp;quot;I was blogging since it was just called updating a web site.&amp;quot;
But with the culture of the internet as it is, I felt the need to change with it.</description></item><item><title>Congratulations Erin!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/congratulations-erin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 01:36:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/04/congratulations-erin/</guid><description>Just wanted to say congratulations to Miss Erin Standley! She just won the Cut &amp;amp; Paste Chicago design competition! Now she's off to New York in June to compete again. She's quite the badass. Way to kick ass, Erin!</description></item><item><title>Happy Friday, everyone</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/03/happy-friday-everyone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 08:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/03/happy-friday-everyone/</guid><description>In celebration of it being Friday, I'm posting a song for everyone to listen to. What song is more appropriate on a Friday during lent than Rasptutina's &amp;quot;Rats&amp;quot;? Enjoy. Have a good weekend. http://dropbox.real-ity.com/tunes/02 - Rasputina - Rats.mp3</description></item><item><title>Tweply and SMS</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/03/tweply-and-sms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 11:43:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/03/tweply-and-sms/</guid><description>Happy post Saint Patrick's day. So maybe I was optimistic (or pessimistic, depending on how you see it) about Tweply and SMS functionality. Like other projects I've thrown together I felt a need that I couldn't find elsewhere, and then offered it to others. Except this time it's costing me more than I expected with people signing up for it.
I love that people find it useful, but unfortunately I'm paying much more than I expected.</description></item><item><title>Alright, I'll blog. Leave me alone about it.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/03/alright-ill-blog.-leave-me-alone-about-it./</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 18:37:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/03/alright-ill-blog.-leave-me-alone-about-it./</guid><description>It's a really exciting time right now. It's South by Southwest conference/festival time! And you know as well as I do what that means! Nothing.
I get really bitter this time every year. All the professional &amp;quot;consultants&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;media experts&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;freelancers&amp;quot; all converge in Texas to talk about awesome things. While us lame kids with corporate jobs sit in our cubes and listen to them talk about how much fun they're having.</description></item><item><title>iPhone Apps</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/iphone-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 21:14:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/iphone-apps/</guid><description>Just as a quick information dump, with regards to real apps (not jailbreak utils for the console) here's what I have on my iPhone so far:
Utilities:
* SBSettings\ * Winterboard\ * Backgrounder\ * IntelliScreen\ * Supreme Settings
Apps:
* Facebook\ * MySpace\ * Last.FM\ * Pandora\ * Twitterific\ * Tweety\ * NetNewsWire\ * Colloquy\ * Yelp\ * Urban Spoon\ * Wiki Mobile\ * Shazam\ * MCleaner\ * Simplify Media\ * Evernote\ * Cydia</description></item><item><title>And now I own an iPhone</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/and-now-i-own-an-iphone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 10:13:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/and-now-i-own-an-iphone/</guid><description>As an avid mac enthusiast you probably just assume I've had an iPhone since the first version of the device was launched. You'd be wrong.
I've been using a Treo650 on Sprint for many years. Before that, the Treo600. Before that a Treo 300. When I started using a QWERTY phone T9 wasn't even invented yet.
My Treos over the years have been nothing less than a faithful companion. PalmOS has let me select from a wealth of applications, both free and paid, that help me do anything I needed.</description></item><item><title>February updates</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/february-updates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 11:14:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/february-updates/</guid><description>+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+ | count(DISTINCT username) | +&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+ +&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+ 1 row in set (0.09 sec)
I had to to go back to my SMS aggrigator service today and purchase more SMS outbound credits since the 400 I originally purchased were all used up. But that means it's being used, but that also means it's not exactly financially supportible by myself. I'll worry about that later like any good service. I might just use Twitter direct messages instead of SMS.</description></item><item><title>Tweply - since nobody talked me out of it</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/tweply-since-nobody-talked-me-out-of-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/tweply-since-nobody-talked-me-out-of-it/</guid><description>I was hoping someone would talk me out of another stupid idea. Damn you all. So this is what you get. An alpha thingy of Tweply. http://www.real-ity.com/tweply/
No promises how well it'll work, but it should work ok. It looks ugly. Well.. actually it looks more like nothing. That's how my design skills are. Couple header tags, a center, some text and not close out the body.
Again, you have to give out your twitter password to use it.</description></item><item><title>I'm going to make a thing for twitter</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/im-going-to-make-a-thing-for-twitter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 00:33:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/im-going-to-make-a-thing-for-twitter/</guid><description>Anyone who knows me knows I'm addicted to Twitter. I won't go into details of my love affair with the beautiful beast, but let's just say it's a pretty integrated part of my lifestyle work flow. However, there's things I wish it did that it doesn't do. It's not very flexible.
For example, you can send tweets from people you follow to your phone via SMS, and that's a great feature.</description></item><item><title>Irregardless, it's time to cowboy up</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/irregardless-its-time-to-cowboy-up/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 14:44:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/irregardless-its-time-to-cowboy-up/</guid><description>So I haven't blogged anything about my job since I've moved to Omaha I don't think. Well, here's my first.Met our new &amp;quot;uber manager&amp;quot; today, or the manager of my manager. Let me put it simply, i'm scared shitless. I can't think of someone I can relate to any less.
For hobbies, it's Huskers football. He also likes to fish and cook game. He said the word &amp;quot;irregardless&amp;quot; and told us to &amp;quot;cowboy up&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>25 things about me</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/25-things-about-me/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 10:53:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/25-things-about-me/</guid><description>This note-writing meme has been going full force on Facebook lately. I thought I'd cave and do it. Since I did, I'll put it here as well.
Rules:\ Once you've been tagged, you are supposed to write a note with 25 random things, facts, habits, or goals about you. At the end, choose 25 people to be tagged. You have to tag the person who tagged you. If I tagged you, it's because I want to know more about you.</description></item><item><title>Hello from Chicago</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/hello-from-chicago/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 16:32:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/hello-from-chicago/</guid><description>I dragged Cassie (well actually she drove most of the way) to Chicago this week. Been here since Tuesday night, and it's really nice to see the city again.
It is a little eye opening though. Living here for so long, then going elsewhere, and then coming back.
All the odd looks and questions when I say I really do like Omaha, and i'm not just saying that to back myself up in the move.</description></item><item><title>Happy 2009 everyone</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/happy-2009-everyone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 11:53:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/happy-2009-everyone/</guid><description>So it was brought to my attention by one of my tweeple friends that I haven't blogged, specifically about the &amp;quot;no meat experiment&amp;quot; recently. Since before Christmas. So here it is! Christmas was not fun. And from now on i'm not going to celebrate it anymore. Using vacation time to spend forced time with people i'm just not compatible with is just stupid to continue. Guilt is not a &amp;quot;holiday spirit&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>Followup on ingestion tactics</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/12/followup-on-ingestion-tactics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 09:48:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/12/followup-on-ingestion-tactics/</guid><description>Today is Thursday. The 4th full day without any meat. I'm sure it's by far the longest stretch of doing so in my whole life. *maybe* i've gone a whole day without eating meat once.. maybe. But four days is nothing. But I felt it was worth updating anyway.
The first couple days I didn't think anything of it. Just started eating different foods. Yesterday, day three, it hit me. I wanted meat.</description></item><item><title>Pickles</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/12/pickles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 13:57:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/12/pickles/</guid><description>As of last night, around 5pm I've cut out meat from my diet. I've been planning this since around last night at 4:59pm or so. It all started yesterday morning when Cassie and I were out to breakfast. She convinced me to try a piece of egg, a food item I haven't had for about 15 years. It's a slight phobia of cracking open the unfertilized birthplace of an animal. I'm well aware egg is in pretty much everything, and that doesn't bother me.</description></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/12/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 13:35:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/12/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>I should update more often. Here's one.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-should-update-more-often.-heres-one./</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 15:01:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-should-update-more-often.-heres-one./</guid><description>Hello, friends.
No huge updates going on. I've been trying to get everything in order here, to the best of my ability. Unpacking boxes, putting things places. Got my surround sound kicking in my livingroom with my AppleTV attached. Have my two wireless networks running (802.11g and 802.11n as to not to share frequencies), and little by little going through clothes that are in boxes and putting them away.
I was wondering why it is I had so much clothes still packed away.</description></item><item><title>Omaha meetup.com email I just got</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/omaha-meetup.com-email-i-just-got/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 00:52:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/omaha-meetup.com-email-i-just-got/</guid><description>Slightly humorous highlights:\ Ron Paul?\ Huckabee for president 2008 meetup still active?\ Church in the home.
{=html} &amp;lt;div style=&amp;quot;padding-top: 10px; padding-right: 0px; padding-bottom: 10px; padding-left: 0px;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;color: #212324; font-family: Verdana; font-size: 12px;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}The Newest Omaha Meetup Groups:&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}
{=html} &amp;lt;div style=&amp;quot;padding-top: 0px; padding-right: 0px; padding-bottom: 0px; padding-left: 10px;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;color: #212324; font-family: Verdana; font-size: 12px;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}The Fremont D&amp;amp;D and Board Games Meetup Group&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}
&amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;color: #212324; font-family: Verdana; font-size: 12px;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}Play Group for Happy Crafters&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}</description></item><item><title>I like Omaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-like-omaha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 20:49:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-like-omaha/</guid><description>I just ventured to downtown Omaha. It's the area I haven't been to yet. I went off the beaten path and found the area I heard so much about called &amp;quot;Old Market&amp;quot;. For a few blocks here, I don't feel like i'm in Omaha anymore.
I found a coffee shop with wifi here, and that's where i'm blogging from. Before this I went to a couple record stores. RECORD stores. With posters, and old vinyl, and all the kind of niche stuff you'd only see in chicago small independent shops.</description></item><item><title>I live in Omaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-live-in-omaha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 01:02:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/11/i-live-in-omaha/</guid><description>Well, I'm here. There's a lot to blog about, really. But it's midnight, and I don't think i'd be able to do everything justice at this point. So at this point let me just offer up a couple videos I made. More to come!
Videos:\ Gabe drives to Omaha\ Gabe tours his apartment</description></item><item><title>My last day at the Chicago office</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/my-last-day-at-the-chicago-office/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 14:46:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/my-last-day-at-the-chicago-office/</guid><description>So today i'm saying my goodbye's at the Chicago office. There's a get together after work today at a local pub and it seems like a decent amount of people are going to be showing up. Just got back a few ago from my last ROM coffee run. My secret crush, Lilly, wasn't there, though.
My desk is clean, things are packed up for me to bring home... another chapter closed in the big book of relocation.</description></item><item><title>7 days to go/Photo montage</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/7-days-to-go/photo-montage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 16:48:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/7-days-to-go/photo-montage/</guid><description>Seven days from today I'll be on my way to Omaha. A moving company is coming first thing Saturday morning to put everything on a truck and off I go. Sounds so simple.
In honor of me leaving, I put together a quick collection of some photos of random times/events/entertaining things that took place here. I have another week to make some more great memories, but here's a little selection so far.</description></item><item><title>Chronicling my time in Chicago #3</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/chronicling-my-time-in-chicago-#3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:27:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/chronicling-my-time-in-chicago-#3/</guid><description>So I've been back now since Tuesday night. I can say it's slightly odd being back. I had a nice going away lunch with my old team Wednesday, and went out last night after work with some of the Chicago people for dinner and drinks.
I'm seeing more and more people moving on with their lives without me in it. Makes sense, and completely expected, but often hard to watch. People I would be spending more time with and be close to, but given the limited time it's easier just to let things move on by.</description></item><item><title>Good morning, Omaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/good-morning-omaha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 09:14:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/good-morning-omaha/</guid><description>Was an exciting weekend to say the least. Friday night I went out with Jess, who's introducing me to some great people. Saturday and Sunday I met up with Jillian who's looking for apartments and is kind enough to let me tag along. And Saturday night I went to a coworker's party that followed the Alcohol + Fire = Burning Things rule. Here's the video!I have an application for one apartment, but that's it so far.</description></item><item><title>Quick Cal</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/quick-cal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 11:32:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/quick-cal/</guid><description>A plug for my Buddy Jim's OS X widget, QuickCal. Lets you use plain english to add entries to iCal. I admittedly miss the cheesy purple UI that was in old versions, but what can you do?
Go download it. http://smellypuppy.com/wp/?p=41
{width=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;162&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Apartment hunting == not fun</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/apartment-hunting-not-fun/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 17:03:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/apartment-hunting-not-fun/</guid><description>Went out with Jillian today to look at apartments. She was really helpful. She's looking in the Dundee area just like I am. I'm not sure how i'd get anything done around here without all the helpful people i'm meeting! The last lady I talked to sounded about 10 years past death. She sounded like she didn't believe what company I worked for because she's lived here all her life, and she's never heard of it.</description></item><item><title>Hello from Omaha!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/hello-from-omaha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 22:57:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/hello-from-omaha/</guid><description>Should I be blurring out the company name or something? I never know how to deal with that. Whatever. For all you know I work across the street at the Holiday Inn and I thought this logo was funny looking.
{width=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;360&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>I'm in Omaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/im-in-omaha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 15:34:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/im-in-omaha/</guid><description>Quick post. But i'm here, alive, and working. How about that.</description></item><item><title>Anyone shop online for clothes? Aparently it's more difficult than I thought.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/anyone-shop-online-for-clothes-aparently-its-more-difficult-than-i-thought./</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 14:39:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/anyone-shop-online-for-clothes-aparently-its-more-difficult-than-i-thought./</guid><description>Seems like right now is the first time in a while i've just been sitting around relaxing. Threw some laundry in, picked up a little. Probably get back to packing this weekend at some point.
A week from right now I'll already be in Omaha. Slightly surreal.
I'm trying to go through online and bookmark new clothes, since I'm having to go through an overhaul of my wardrobe. I can no longer wear concert tshirts and cartoon characters to work.</description></item><item><title>Chronicling my time in Chicago #2</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/chronicling-my-time-in-chicago-#2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 10:05:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/chronicling-my-time-in-chicago-#2/</guid><description>So last weekend when I last blogged I met up with Katie, Tracy, Michelle and Frank. We had a blast! This Friday night we hope to go out and be all stupid again. In fact, a friend of Frank's (ex-girlfriend's sister actually) is from Omaha, and is in town. So she's going to go out with us. I have so many awesome resources for this move, I can't complain one bit.</description></item><item><title>I'm moving to Jesusland :(</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/im-moving-to-jesusland/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 14:52:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/im-moving-to-jesusland/</guid><description>{width=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo;}
Thanks to psi for the image.</description></item><item><title>Chronicling my time in Chicagoland #1</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/chronicling-my-time-in-chicagoland-#1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 20:43:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/chronicling-my-time-in-chicagoland-#1/</guid><description>Tonight I called my buddy Sean at Old Town Tatu to schedule my Illinois state tattoo. Tuesday night at 8pm. Not sure where it's going yet, or in what style... but he's an awesome artist, and i'll work with him on it. I just want to take Illinois with me when I go. I sent out a blast email (and myspace post) today to everyone letting them know of my time table.</description></item><item><title>Hello Omaha part 2</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/hello-omaha-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2008 11:01:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/hello-omaha-part-2/</guid><description>So it's official. October will be the last month I live in the fine state of Illinois. Who would have ever thought, right? But yesterday I accepted the position in Omaha, NE with West.
My first day in my new role will be October 6th, so I gave West Notifications my 2 weeks yesterday. After that they're going to fly me out a couple times so I can find somewhere to live, meet my team, and get my move situated.</description></item><item><title>Just a little frustrated</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/just-a-little-frustrated/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 10:07:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/just-a-little-frustrated/</guid><description>Just in the past two days two people announced they are leaving the company. Why does that bother me? Because I'm not one of them.
I'm just so frustrated. I try so hard here. I really do. I'm good at what I do and I think i'm seen as an important asset. But management is just turning this place into a fucking zoo.
I never told you about the SOCOM initiative.</description></item><item><title>Music recommendations</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/music-recommendations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 13:30:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/music-recommendations/</guid><description>I was putting a list of artists together for someone who wanted some music recommendations from me. I figured i'd throw it up here as well.
I'd guess most people I know already are aware or are fans of this stuff already, but maybe not.
* The Postal Service: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hMOkfI7wCrI
*!!!: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iYXvSUei4Ow
* Black Moth Super Rainbow: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iYXvSUei4Ow
* Walter Meego: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U0guf7O4mKQ
* Ghostland Observatory: http://www.last.fm/music/Ghostland+Observatory/+videos/+1-wzE1sSVSY_8
* The New Pornographers: http://www.</description></item><item><title>Gabe's Gym Story</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/gabes-gym-story/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 10:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/gabes-gym-story/</guid><description>So I took my gym going to another level.
I haven't been going often... at all. So I figured I needed help if I were to expedite the degutting process. So last week I signed up for a personal trainer at the local Bally's.
I got Jen, a cute, short, bubbly girl. Oh yeah. She's also the manager and just finished her first Iron Man Triathlon this past weekend.
She kicked my ass last night.</description></item><item><title>You are being judged</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/08/you-are-being-judged/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 10:28:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/08/you-are-being-judged/</guid><description>Does anyone else get these things from Facebook &amp;quot;Compare People&amp;quot;? It's always interesting how you're ranked compared to others. Here's my current standings:
#1 craziest (gained 1 place)\ #2 person with the best taste in music (gained 1 place)\ #3 nicest (gained 1 place)\ #5 best room-mate (gained 1 place)\ #6 most entertaining (gained 1 place)
Best room-mate? Really? I'd be the worst. I've only lived with one person before, and it ended awful.</description></item><item><title>I owe you all an update</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/08/i-owe-you-all-an-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 13:38:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/08/i-owe-you-all-an-update/</guid><description>Hello, Internet. I have a few topics to discuss, in no particular order. Ginny and I broke up. I'm taking it pretty hard.
We were only together for comparitively a short time, but honestly it was an amazing time. She took me by the hand and walked me through so many new things. It went from me not understanding how someone could be a part of someone's life if they were married to integrating seamlessly into not just the life of one person, but the family of two.</description></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/08/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 09:26:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/08/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/08/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 21:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/08/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hellooooo Omaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/08/hellooooo-omaha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 14:29:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/08/hellooooo-omaha/</guid><description>So like I said in a previous post, the time to complain about my job and the direction of my role is over. it's time to start doing something to better my situation.
So that time started last night when I applied for an open position in the Load balancer/unix scripting/sendmail/qmail team in Omaha, NE. Unix! I miss you!
Does it sound like a great match to what I'm good at?</description></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 02:10:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 18:48:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hello Inkernet</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/hello-inkernet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:54:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/hello-inkernet/</guid><description>Been a while since I posted anything, so I thought I'd say hi. Couple weeks ago I had my week off of work, and it was great. I don't think I've ever had a week off like that before, and I really think it's something that needs to happen every year.
This year my focus was to work on my music. Sometimes with everything you have to do in life you never get time to do the things you want to do.</description></item><item><title>Cute@Facebook</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/cutefacebook/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 20:34:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/cutefacebook/</guid><description>:)
{width=&amp;ldquo;391&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;60&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 03:22:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 03:20:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/07/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Happy Friday, Internet!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/happy-friday-internet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 09:21:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/happy-friday-internet/</guid><description>Hello everyone. Happy Friday, hope your week wasn't too awful.
I need to start making more new posts on my blog. Sometimes it's the only way people know what's going on, but I'm generally pretty bad at filtering out what's important and interesting and relaying that on to people. In my mind it's all boring and nobody cares but myself. But ever notice that's generally true? When someone asks &amp;quot;how was your day?</description></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2008 17:27:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Place sharp tube. Insert through flesh.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/place-sharp-tube.-insert-through-flesh./</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 00:52:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/place-sharp-tube.-insert-through-flesh./</guid><description>Went and got my right ear &amp;quot;fixed&amp;quot; yesterday. I let it heal since the 2g hole through my lobe never was doing well. So i let it heal completely over a couple months, and yesterday my buddy Johnny over at Native Rituals said I'm good to have a go at it again.
I snapped a picture of the 4g needle. Calling it a needle, though, is really incorrect. It's a large tube with a sharp edge.</description></item><item><title>Let's have a talk. Have a seat.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/lets-have-a-talk.-have-a-seat./</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 20:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/lets-have-a-talk.-have-a-seat./</guid><description>Have a seat. We're going to have a little talk. I often don't talk about my personal life when it comes to other people. Once in a while i'll put a blurb about work, or myself, but generally it's about broad topics that I hope are interesting to read. But I think this topic needs a little explanation.
I'll start with the simple stuff. Good news, I met a girl! Her name is Ginny.</description></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 17:25:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>We may be extraterrestrials after all</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/we-may-be-extraterrestrials-after-all/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:21:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/we-may-be-extraterrestrials-after-all/</guid><description>Told you so.
News of the day. You are an alien.\ &amp;gt; [From &amp;lt;cite&amp;gt;{=html}We may be extraterrestrials after &amp;gt; all&amp;lt;/cite&amp;gt;{=html}]</description></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 14:08:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/06/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 23:56:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>I'm not doing well</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/im-not-doing-well/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 09:47:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/im-not-doing-well/</guid><description>As some of you probably know, I'm a complete nutcase. Not in the &amp;quot;oh look at me, I'm so different and cute.&amp;quot; No, in the way that I'm seriously fucked in the head and there's a possibility I may hurt you, hurt someone you know, or hurt myself on any given day.
Luckily nobody has been injured thus far, but a few broken items in my apartment were harmed in the past week or so.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye BME</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/goodbye-bme/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 07:46:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/goodbye-bme/</guid><description>I'm sad to say that things have changed with one of my favorite, and most inspirational blogs. The sole guy who has run Modblog (and all other associated BME properties) has had to transfer his ownership to someone else and leave the place.
BME, the de-facto location online for all things body modification related is a pretty important place for a lot of people. It's really the most educational blog that I read in the sense of people in the real world doing real things, and how it comes out.</description></item><item><title>I'm someone's bitch</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/im-someones-bitch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 07:35:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/im-someones-bitch/</guid><description>So I went to lunch with an ex-coworker and current coworker Friday. It was an eye opening experience. To make it short, they made me realize all of the actual responsibilities that used any type of knowledge I have are being taken from me one day at a time. Instead being replaced by fucking bullshit monkey tasks.
The last thing I want to feel like when I wake up every morning is that I'm someone's bitch, doing things I don't believe in, and have no say in.</description></item><item><title>Hello this is Gabe blogging...</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/hello-this-is-gabe-blogging.../</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2008 19:58:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/hello-this-is-gabe-blogging.../</guid><description>Hello this is Gabe blogging from the car using jott.com. I am just speaking into my phone and hopefully jott is transcribing what I am saying properly. I just ____ to send a twitter a few minutes ago ____ somebody's name which makes me look really stupid, that's okay, so yeah I am going to meet this person that jott does know the name of ____ my guess is that probably do something after that because the night is young and it is a Friday night.</description></item><item><title>Testing sending to my...</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/testing-sending-to-my.../</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2008 00:57:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/05/testing-sending-to-my.../</guid><description>Testing sending to my blog with jott.com. listen Powered by Jott</description></item><item><title>The amount of time i've listened to music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/the-amount-of-time-ive-listened-to-music/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 10:52:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/the-amount-of-time-ive-listened-to-music/</guid><description>The top 15 artists by amount of time i've listened to their music. Crazy stuff.
{width=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;346&amp;rdquo;}
That's 55 hours of Nine Inch Nails.
This is gathered by using the Last.FM API through http://www.associativetrails.com/stuff/normalisefm/index.cfm.</description></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2008 15:37:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>New Nine Inch Nails Track (with words)</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/new-nine-inch-nails-track-with-words/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 05:33:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/new-nine-inch-nails-track-with-words/</guid><description>New single called Discipline is released. Take a look at the id3 info of the song...
{width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;375&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Saturday Night @ Mannequin Nightclub</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/saturday-night-mannequin-nightclub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 10:54:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/saturday-night-mannequin-nightclub/</guid><description>When you look back at something and realize you're lucky to be alive or not in jail, I suppose it's a worthy story to share.
{=html} &amp;lt;div style=&amp;quot;word-wrap: break-word; -webkit-nbsp-mode: space; -webkit-line-break: after-white-space;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; So Ron and I made plans to hit up Mannequin Nightclub (mentioned as &amp;quot;the hottest new club in Chicago&amp;quot; by some dude there). We reserved a table for VIP bottle service.\ We got to the club around 11:00pm and were really having a good time.</description></item><item><title>Odd IRC dream</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/odd-irc-dream/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2008 03:28:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/odd-irc-dream/</guid><description>So I had a dream last night I was on CabinDuDe, the bot of #thecabin's party line. And then people I've been working with from Omaha at work also joined. We were using it for a chat for work. And then madcow joined and started listening in. It was a pretty crazy dream. I generally don't remember my dreams, but for some reason the past couple nights I have. Odd.</description></item><item><title>My life in Tweets</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/my-life-in-tweets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 08:19:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/my-life-in-tweets/</guid><description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is so depressing. My life consists of work, sleep, lunch, and transit. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.tweetclouds.com/user_pages/gabek.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Got it from Tweetclouds.com.&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;http://www.real-ity.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/200804071318.jpg&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;727&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;505&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;200804071318.jpg&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Gabe's Smart Shuffle. One playlist to rule them all.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/gabes-smart-shuffle.-one-playlist-to-rule-them-all./</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 05:38:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/gabes-smart-shuffle.-one-playlist-to-rule-them-all./</guid><description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The discussion of smart playlists in iTunes came up in #TheCabin today. And I thought I'd post up the details of how my iPod lifeline, &amp;quot;Smart Shuffle&amp;quot; works. I call the playlist that because it's a true shuffle, but within the world I want to give it.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;So here we go.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;To begin with, this is really just for your iPod, not for your full library on your computer. So let's pretend you have a completely empty iPod.</description></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 11:13:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/04/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Today's links</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/03/todays-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 16:31:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/03/todays-links/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Damnit. I'm one of *them*</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/03/damnit.-im-one-of-them/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 17:53:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/03/damnit.-im-one-of-them/</guid><description>I joined a gym today. Damnit. Now i'm one of those assholes. I told myself I wouldn't do that. Be throwing &amp;quot;Yeah, I totally have to go and work out tonight&amp;quot; into conversations to make yourself feel like... something. I don't know. But it's lame. And I don't want to be one of them. But I wanted to do it for myself, so I am. So I put $150 on a 2yr membership with Bally's Fitness because it's the closest to my apartment, and maybe i'll go often enough to make it worthwhile.</description></item><item><title>I got new glasses</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/03/i-got-new-glasses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 07:25:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/03/i-got-new-glasses/</guid><description>{width=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;360&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Help me pick out new prescription glasses</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/help-me-pick-out-new-prescription-glasses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 08:30:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/help-me-pick-out-new-prescription-glasses/</guid><description>Go Here!!!
&amp;lt;iframe frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;100%&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://www.micropoll.com/akira/MicroPoll?id=73162&amp;amp;amp;mode=html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;{=html}
{=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; View Poll |View Results
{=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; Web Poll PoweredBy MicroPoll
{=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; {width=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo;}
&amp;lt;iframe frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;100%&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://www.micropoll.com/akira/MicroPoll?id=73158&amp;amp;amp;mode=html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;{=html}
{=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; View Poll |View Results
{=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; Web Poll PoweredBy MicroPoll
{=html} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; {width=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Test blog post</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/test-blog-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 13:32:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/test-blog-post/</guid><description>Just a test blog post to see if RSS parsing in #TheCabin is working.</description></item><item><title>Bad music (video)</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/bad-music-video/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2008 03:04:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/bad-music-video/</guid><description>Seriously. Do people really listen to music like this? This is awful. What does &amp;quot;Talking out of the side of your neck&amp;quot; even mean?
Plus they use a really bad stereotype of marching band members dancing and spinning and using a mace. I hate that crap.
&amp;lt;embed src=&amp;quot;http://lads.myspace.com/videos/vplayer.swf&amp;quot; flashvars=&amp;quot;m=26378601&amp;amp;amp;v=2&amp;amp;amp;type=video&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;480&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;386&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/embed&amp;gt;{=html}</description></item><item><title>Odd</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/odd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 13:07:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/odd/</guid><description>{#l_782d055cf09b7dfc2dbe01579967c998.gif width=&amp;ldquo;200&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;}
&amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;color: #919191; font-family: &amp;amp;#39;Lucida Grande&amp;amp;#39;;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;nicksandstuff&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;color: #97908D !important; font-weight: bold;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;grneyes&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html} thats slightly scary..and nauseating&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}</description></item><item><title>My new tattoo</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/my-new-tattoo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2008 04:35:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/my-new-tattoo/</guid><description>I hadn't posted this yet, but it's my new tattoo. Done by Matt at Insight Studios in Chicago.
{width=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;188&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>PandoraFM defaced yesterday</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/pandorafm-defaced-yesterday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 04:37:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/pandorafm-defaced-yesterday/</guid><description>Yesterday morning PandoraFM was defaced.
A hacker, not unknown to me from the past, put up some pretty graphic text on the front page of PandoraFM about me. Things i'd never say were posted up, along with mention of contacting &amp;quot;my girlfriend&amp;quot; and family as well. Except I don't have a girlfriend. And the photo he had up was extremely old, certainly not one i'd ever use.
I got ahold of the guy on IRC and talked to him for a bit.</description></item><item><title>The New Pornographers - Bleeding Heart Show</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/the-new-pornographers-bleeding-heart-show/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:19:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/the-new-pornographers-bleeding-heart-show/</guid><description>I'm in the audience somewhere. From the Pitchfork festival this past summer.
&amp;lt;object width=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;325&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;movie&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;http://media.imeem.com/v/_whIurEM7d/aus=false/pv=2&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html} &amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;allowFullScreen&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html} &amp;lt;embed src=&amp;quot;http://media.imeem.com/v/_whIurEM7d/aus=false/pv=2&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;325&amp;quot; allowfullscreen=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/embed&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/object&amp;gt;{=html}</description></item><item><title>I threw up at Cloverfield</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/01/i-threw-up-at-cloverfield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 02:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/01/i-threw-up-at-cloverfield/</guid><description>Just a quick update to tell everyone that I threw up at Cloverfield last night.
It was the second time of me seeing it. I had a full meal (with desert) at Steak and Shake just moments before going to the theater. I hadn't felt all that great all day, a little dizzy and such.
I figure about 40min into the movie and it was time to go. Threw up in a garbage can right in the hallway.</description></item><item><title>What I don't want in a girl</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/01/what-i-dont-want-in-a-girl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 18:45:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/01/what-i-dont-want-in-a-girl/</guid><description>So my buddy Joe at work sent me a link to The Lincoln Park Chad Society web page today. This is the best thing ever. Now no longer do I have to try and explain to people what I would like to see in a girl that i'd want to date. Instead, I can just show them this... what I don't want to have in a girl!
Amanda is a 25 year-old marketing manager for a major firm in downtown Chicago.</description></item><item><title>Gabe's 2007 Review of Stuff</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/12/gabes-2007-review-of-stuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 00:35:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/12/gabes-2007-review-of-stuff/</guid><description>I do this every year. This one is a bit smaller than previous ones, and I try not to duplicate too much from things I've already talked about. Regardless, here is my review of things and stuff involved with me in 2007. I'd love to go through and hyperlink all these things for you, but it's really a lot of work, and I'm lazy. So if you're at all interested, and you probably aren't, just go ahead and google it.</description></item><item><title>Worst. Holiday. Season. Ever.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/12/worst.-holiday.-season.-ever./</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2007 19:49:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/12/worst.-holiday.-season.-ever./</guid><description>This is the first holiday season I've ever spent completely alone.
I'm not a big fan of Christmas time to begin with. I hate shopping. I hate trying to figure out what people want. I'm bad it, and I buy people complete crap. At least with Dragon Woman she'd help me shop for people, and people would end getting stuff they actually liked. I'd be forced to have even a little bit of holiday spirit, but this year I don't have any of that.</description></item><item><title>Hello weekend</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/12/hello-weekend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2007 13:09:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/12/hello-weekend/</guid><description>Hello bloggy blog. I haven't really had a lot of time to post an update lately. But I always say that, and so do most people with blogs.
This is the first weekend in a while where i'm at home. I've been spending a lot of time off doing stuff. Last weekend, believe it or not, I was in Racine for the Kilties banquet. Dawn invited me to go with her, and I used the opportunity to donate my uniform back to the corps.</description></item><item><title>I love OS X 10.5 Leopard</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/11/i-love-os-x-10.5-leopard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2007 10:56:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/11/i-love-os-x-10.5-leopard/</guid><description>I love OS X. Made this little demo of how you can manage and navigate windows in 10.5 Leopard.&amp;lt;embed src=&amp;quot;http://www.metacafe.com/fplayer/947209/navigation.swf&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;345&amp;quot; wmode=&amp;quot;transparent&amp;quot; pluginspage=&amp;quot;http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/embed&amp;gt;{=html}</description></item><item><title>Who I should vote for</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/11/who-i-should-vote-for/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 13:42:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/11/who-i-should-vote-for/</guid><description>So I listened to Net@Nite the other day and heard about a new site called Connect2Elect. It allows you to rate what is important to you as far as views, and it'll rank what candidates match you. You put all your views, in order of importance, and this is what I ended up with.
{=html} &amp;lt;center&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;/center&amp;gt; Now it may be a bit misleading, as some of the things I ranked as #1 in importance aren't &amp;quot;core issues&amp;quot; of the election.</description></item><item><title>From me. To you. My blog.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/11/from-me.-to-you.-my-blog./</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2007 14:41:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/11/from-me.-to-you.-my-blog./</guid><description>Hello friends.
I've been quiet lately. And for that, I apologize. Not a ton has been going on, but enough.
Work has been really busy lately. I've become what people like to call &amp;quot;important&amp;quot; due to all the projects going on, and my knowledge on the subjects required. Lots and lots of meetings. More than I'd like. I have more work on my plate than I can sometimes handle, but i'm totally cranking through things.</description></item><item><title>Wild dream last night</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/11/wild-dream-last-night/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 11:35:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/11/wild-dream-last-night/</guid><description>So I had a dream last night. Really odd one.
I dreamt that I had some control over a robot. Like a big, crazy, Voltronesque robot. But nobody knew about it, even though it was huge. And I controlled it via a unix shell.
There was someone, and i'm not sure who.. or why, but I wanted them dead. And I found out they were flying on a plane. So I told my robot to grab the plane (with it's hands.</description></item><item><title>Hello from Marquette, Michigan</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/hello-from-marquette-michigan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2007 11:28:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/hello-from-marquette-michigan/</guid><description>I made it up to the UP in one piece. My car didn't disappear or anything. I have about 30min or so until I have to be at my aunt's for my grandparent's 60th anniversary party. But I decided to drive around and see if I could find somewhere with wifi.
I found a Starbucks and knew that would be a good start.
I walk in, &amp;quot;Excuse me, do you have wifi?</description></item><item><title>Good news!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/good-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2007 08:35:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/good-news/</guid><description>the train station here in chicago had my keys turned in. so I'm on my way there now in a cab. such a relief!!</description></item><item><title>Lost my keys</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/lost-my-keys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 19:24:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/lost-my-keys/</guid><description>Lost my car and apartment keys. I have no idea where they could be. I've been out in the cold rain waiting for another train to bring me back into the city. Maybe they're at my office, but I don't think they are. I'm screwed.</description></item><item><title>Nine Inch Nails is no longer with a record label</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/nine-inch-nails-is-no-longer-with-a-record-label/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 07:56:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/nine-inch-nails-is-no-longer-with-a-record-label/</guid><description>How awesome is this. I knew the time was coming, and i'm glad for everyone that it's here. NIN without limitations. Sweet.
&amp;quot;Hello everyone. I've waited a LONG time to be able to make the following announcement: as of right now Nine Inch Nails is a totally free agent, free of any recording contract with any label. I have been under recording contracts for 18 years and have watched the business radically mutate from one thing to something inherently very different and it gives me great pleasure to be able to finally have a direct relationship with the audience as I see fit and appropriate.</description></item><item><title>Trumblr</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/trumblr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 08:49:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/trumblr/</guid><description>I setup a Tumble log via Tumblr this morning. Kinda neat. It's just &amp;quot;stuff&amp;quot;, not &amp;quot;posts&amp;quot;. Check it out.</description></item><item><title>The Peanut Butter Solution</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/the-peanut-butter-solution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 11:19:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/the-peanut-butter-solution/</guid><description>{width=&amp;ldquo;275&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;412&amp;rdquo;}
Where to begin. I remember watching this movie as a kid. And by &amp;quot;remember&amp;quot; I remember vaguely very little about the movie other then how I felt about the movie. For years I thought I made up the movie. I didn't really remember the plot. All I remembered was a terrifying movie that troubled me deeply as a child and always stayed with me as I got older. For a while I figured it was a dream I had as a kid and that's why I don't really remember it, but just know it was messed up, as many dreams are.</description></item><item><title>My poor, poor car</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/my-poor-poor-car/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2007 21:12:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/my-poor-poor-car/</guid><description>Man, things are bad. Real bad.
So like my last post said, my car got towed, and I wasn't sure exactly why. Something to do with my temporary license plate on it. There's two options: 1) The plate was stolen and the car was ticketed and towed due to having no plate on the car. Or 2) There was an incorrect plate on the car, registered to someone else, and when a cop looked it up had the car towed because it was wrong and possibly stolen.</description></item><item><title>My car. WTF?</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/my-car.-wtf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 23:51:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/10/my-car.-wtf/</guid><description>So i'm not going to go too deep into the story right now. But my car has been towed by the city of Chicago because someone stole the license plate off it, and my iPod is missing from it. I'm the victim of a crime and was ticketed $500 for it. I have to pay that before I can get my car back. Details to come.</description></item><item><title>I'm cooking!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/im-cooking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2007 16:53:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/im-cooking/</guid><description>Phear. My first time cooking anything more than a grilled cheese sandwich. Chili is on it's way.
{width=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;305&amp;rdquo;} {width=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;360&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>My blog has been broke, sorry. And other stuff.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/my-blog-has-been-broke-sorry.-and-other-stuff./</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 07:55:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/my-blog-has-been-broke-sorry.-and-other-stuff./</guid><description>So my blog front page has been broken. The actual blog wasn't, and still isn't. But my custom RSS aggregator page that has been working flawlessly for years now suddenly isn't. I don't get it. Whatever, i'll fix it at some point. For now, though, it's just going to be redirected to the weblog page. Now you can read. Happy days!
Got tickets for *another* Birthday Massacre show coming up at the Abbey!</description></item><item><title>Updated screenshot</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/updated-screenshot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2007 10:20:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/updated-screenshot/</guid><description>I like my screenshots. I haven't posted one in a while, so here's another. This is what things look like when I'm home.
{width=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;180&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Head Cold</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/head-cold/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 16:20:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/head-cold/</guid><description>&amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-style: italic;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}I hate that &amp;quot;getting a head cold&amp;quot; taste in the mouth and throatal area. Tastes like boogers and defeat.&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-style: italic;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}-Merlin Mann&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}</description></item><item><title>Staying home</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/staying-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 00:01:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/staying-home/</guid><description>I sent an email that i'm not going into work Monday. I'm just feeling too lousy. If i'm not feeling better i'll go to the local clinic and get some drugs to fight this off. It seems like I was just sick, but here I am again feeling the same. Oh well.
Because i've slept so much this weekend it's after midnight now and i'm not really all that tired. I guess i'll read for a bit.</description></item><item><title>Feel lousy</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/feel-lousy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2007 08:00:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/feel-lousy/</guid><description>I feel lousy. I napped through a large chunk of yesterday. I woke up early today since I slept enough, and couldn't fall back asleep. I don't see myself going to work tomorrow. Probably see myself going to a doctor instead.</description></item><item><title>Trent Reznor gives Rip-off Avoidance, Download &amp; Share advice to fans</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/trent-reznor-gives-rip-off-avoidance-download-share-advice-to-fans/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 20:25:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/trent-reznor-gives-rip-off-avoidance-download-share-advice-to-fans/</guid><description>As for the special situation in China, it does not seem to be easy to &amp;gt; obtain Western music via legal channels, so I have the following &amp;gt; suggestion for our fans: If you can find and buy our legal CDs, I &amp;gt; express my thanks for your support. If you cannot find it, I think &amp;gt; that downloading from the Internet is a more acceptable option than &amp;gt; buying pirated CDs.</description></item><item><title>Ahh, the weekend</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/ahh-the-weekend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2007 22:24:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/ahh-the-weekend/</guid><description>So the weekend is soon upon us. And i'm glad to see it. It's been a really long week.
My parents invited me up to see them this weekend, but i'm just too tired. Not to mention I should be doing laundry and cleaning my apartment, all that fun stuff. But mostly I'm just exhausted to go anywhere and do much.
I got paid today, so I went grocery shopping. Spent about $100 in food, so that's good.</description></item><item><title>What a day</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/what-a-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 22:16:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/what-a-day/</guid><description>It was a sad day today. All in all I like most of the people I work with in my office. A few exceptions, and once i've mentioned before. But all in all, I think most everyone are good people and pretty smart.
By around 10am this morning I hated them all.
It was upsetting I was letting everyone get to me. But I'm not a people person. I like to sit in my cube with my nose to the monitor and get things done alone.</description></item><item><title>One of those days</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/one-of-those-days/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 22:56:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/one-of-those-days/</guid><description>Today is one of those days that I just want to blow my fucking brains out. I haven't had many of those days in the recent past. Maybe it's because i've been out of my antidepz and my fucking doctor won't let me have a refill.
Seriously I don't know what the hell is going on. I realize i'm completely shitty at making friends and keeping them and I don't know why.</description></item><item><title>My company on Facebook part 2</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/my-company-on-facebook-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 09:45:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/my-company-on-facebook-part-2/</guid><description>{width=&amp;ldquo;369&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;146&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Good day (I hope)</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/good-day-i-hope/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 07:36:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/09/good-day-i-hope/</guid><description>Today is our company outing. We're getting lunch, going on a boat cruise on the Chicago River, and then food and drinks at a bar &amp;amp; grill. As long as nothing breaks before noon, we'll actually be able to go this time. Last time was cancelled due to production issues we had to tend to.
So who else saw that Apple announcement yesterday? Everyone, right? Man oh man oh man. That iPod touch will be mine.</description></item><item><title>Car situation</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/car-situation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2007 08:36:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/car-situation/</guid><description>I had a few options.
Option 1) Refinance and keep the Scion. It turns out that's a very difficult option, because anyone that refinances also wants both names on the original loan to stay on the refinanced one. So that sucked.
2) Trade in my Scion and get a new car in order to start clean.
3) Drop the Scion off in Kelley's driveway, since it's just as much hers as it is mine and have her deal with it.</description></item><item><title>My company on facebook</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/my-company-on-facebook/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2007 11:33:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/my-company-on-facebook/</guid><description>Work and online social networks to NOT go together.</description></item><item><title>Crap with my car</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/crap-with-my-car/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 10:31:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/crap-with-my-car/</guid><description>So I thought I had the crap with my car dealt with, as Kelley is demanding to be removed from my auto loan. Now I just got an email:
&amp;quot;Unfortunately, we cannot refinance for you based on the information you provided because you applied by yourself and we cannot remove anyone from loans or titles. In other words, the names that are on your current loan/lease now are the names it must stay in for us to do the refinance.</description></item><item><title>OS X's TextEdit icon</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/os-xs-textedit-icon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 08:42:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/os-xs-textedit-icon/</guid><description>This is why I love Macs.</description></item><item><title>The Best Survey Ever</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/the-best-survey-ever/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 08:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/the-best-survey-ever/</guid><description>(Reposted from something I posted on MySpace)
I never do surveys. But I thought now would be a good time.
However, this one has got to be good. Nay, not good. This has to be the best survey ever.
Do you want to know what shirt I'm wearing right now? The last person I talked to on the phone? Current crush? My favorite color? The age I was first kissed?</description></item><item><title>Over 2,991,000 other tracks have been submitted to Last.FM profiles through PandoraFM.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/over-2991000-other-tracks-have-been-submitted-to-last.fm-profiles-through-pandorafm./</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2007 11:35:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/over-2991000-other-tracks-have-been-submitted-to-last.fm-profiles-through-pandorafm./</guid><description>Crazy. It's been over a year since PandoraFM v3 was released, and I haven't really touched it at all since then. And it still works, and people still use it.
This fact clicked today when I ran into a post on a tech site about someone discovering it for the first time and thought it rocked. Here I am thinking it's 10min from death, and someone else thinks it's a brand new rockin site.</description></item><item><title>Odd dreams</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/odd-dreams/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2007 09:22:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/odd-dreams/</guid><description>So i've had two dreams recently about me getting fired from my job. Last nights was even more disturbing.
It included our new uber-manager from Omaha yelling at me on the phone and then bringing my case to some peer review committee to see if I should be able to keep my job or not. He said &amp;quot;the choice was clear&amp;quot; and I could no longer work for the company.</description></item><item><title>Library of stuff</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/library-of-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2007 13:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/library-of-stuff/</guid><description>Check out my Movie, Music and Book library. I'm starting to catalog that stuff using Delicious Library.</description></item><item><title>Happy Weekend</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/happy-weekend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2007 00:03:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/happy-weekend/</guid><description>So I told myself two weeks ago this weekend would be dedicated to getting my butt in gear and sitting down in front of the console and starting where I left off with my album. I don't know, though. We'll see. I really have to clean my apartment and do laundry first. But even if this weekend isn't the weekend that I get back on track the good news is that I WANT to.</description></item><item><title>Why haven't I posted?</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/why-havent-i-posted/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 10:33:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/why-havent-i-posted/</guid><description>So I haven't posted since Lollapalooza. If you didn't see the photos, you may not have even known I had gone at this point. I'll make that rundown quick. Daft Punk was a life changing, unbelievable experience. It was the show of shows. Read any review of lolla for Friday and you'll only hear the same thing over and over. Amazing.
!!! on Sunday took 2nd place in putting on a great show.</description></item><item><title>Updates from Lollapalooza</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/updates-from-lollapalooza/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2007 07:24:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/updates-from-lollapalooza/</guid><description>Due to it being a special case, I'm going to add my twitter updates to my blog for the next three days. Then anyone who's subscribed to it, or stops by the site can see what I'm up to. Stay tuned! Next stop, 12:30 - Ghostland Observatory.</description></item><item><title>Should I create a work category?</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/should-i-create-a-work-category/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 08:54:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/should-i-create-a-work-category/</guid><description>I think I might need it. So I was made aware yesterday by &amp;quot;manager&amp;quot; that they planned on deploying the big platform update this weekend. This weekend. Lollapalooza. They scheduled this without asking me, without inviting me to any planning meetings. Nothing.
I missed Friday last year of Lollapalooza because of work. I refuse to miss it this year. If they want to deploy it this weekend, have fun. In fact, a document I saw said that i'm not even required to be there.</description></item><item><title>Cool my phone thing works</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/cool-my-phone-thing-works/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2007 08:21:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/cool-my-phone-thing-works/</guid><description>So I spent yesterday playing more with Asterisk PBX and I have a pretty neat system working. I could add all kinds of features now. So far I have voicemails being emailed to me working, custom menus, call forwarding to my fax line, cell phone and any other numbers. If it's a certain date/time/whatever I can make it go right to voicemail and not ring any phones, or just go right to a different line.</description></item><item><title>Phone nerd</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/phone-nerd/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2007 08:51:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/phone-nerd/</guid><description>I haven't done a little project for a while. I've been slacking. So I started one last night. I realized I never use my Vonage line. At all. It's really a complete waste of money. I used 0 min out of 500 last month. How very sad. Even though I like the features, I never use it.
So yesterday I decided to read up and learn about Asterisk, an open-source software PBX system.</description></item><item><title>Important by default</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/important-by-default/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 13:27:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/important-by-default/</guid><description>Don't you hate when people make themselves look important by holding everything back from everyone else? That's how things are at work now. My &amp;quot;manager&amp;quot; right now is the only person from my team involved in a huge production issue, and he won't let me be involved. I was hired here to work on issues like this, but he wants to look important by being known as the only person that can do things, and being the only person who did do things.</description></item><item><title>Worst. Manager. Ever.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/worst.-manager.-ever./</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 00:41:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/worst.-manager.-ever./</guid><description>I seriously cannot stand &amp;quot;working for&amp;quot; this guy. We have a huge update to our environment going live and he *just told me* that we're doing it tomorrow at midnight. WTF. That's something I should had known weeks ago. I ask him questions and he won't give me answers. Like &amp;quot;And what's the game plan, what's the timeline?&amp;quot; and he just says &amp;quot;you know what it is&amp;quot;. No I don't. He hordes information like crazy.</description></item><item><title>Work photo</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/work-photo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2007 08:53:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/work-photo/</guid><description>Friday was the last day for my uber-manager Khyle. It sucks that he left. {width=&amp;ldquo;133&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>How not to sexually harass your coworkers.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/how-not-to-sexually-harass-your-coworkers./</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 09:35:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/how-not-to-sexually-harass-your-coworkers./</guid><description>I have to go to mandatory sexual harassment training for work. I thought that was just from TV. How very corporate! Since this post isn't very entertaining, view the video below to make up for it. &amp;lt;object width=&amp;quot;425&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;350&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;movie&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/q_nRaLSg7iI&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html} &amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;wmode&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;transparent&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html} &amp;lt;embed src=&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/q_nRaLSg7iI&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&amp;quot; wmode=&amp;quot;transparent&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;425&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;350&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/embed&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/object&amp;gt;{=html}</description></item><item><title>AIM high</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/aim-high/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 23:53:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/aim-high/</guid><description>So long story short, like 7 months ago I changed the password on my AIM screen name in order to do some testing of code I was working on. I never changed the password back, and my client somehow forgot what the password was. As did I. I couldn't get the stupid &amp;quot;reset password&amp;quot; thing to work on aim.com, so I figured now was as good of a time as any just to sign up a new name again.</description></item><item><title>What a weekend</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/what-a-weekend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 00:13:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/what-a-weekend/</guid><description>I should go to bed, but I thought i'd post quick. It was an awesome weekend. Photos are up from Lauren, Mary and I going to Kinetic Playground Saturday night. And Mary and I went to The PItchfork Music Festival today. Now I have to try and pretend to be normal again and go back to work in the morning :P
{width=&amp;ldquo;133&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Obligatory Simpsons Avatar</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/obligatory-simpsons-avatar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 17:22:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/obligatory-simpsons-avatar/</guid><description>I wouldn't be a member of the 2.0 Digerati if I didn't post my personal Simpsons avatar, now would I? {width=&amp;ldquo;37&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}
Yeah, it doesn't really look like me. It's really as close I could get, though.</description></item><item><title>Rasputina last night</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/rasputina-last-night/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 07:57:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/rasputina-last-night/</guid><description>{width=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}
Saw Rasputina at The Abby last night. Was a good show. The set list was better the first time I saw them, but we had a good time anyway. They rocked out and everyone enjoyed it. I'm tired today, though. Out late, up early, and i'll be out late tonight too because of work.
Next stop, The Pitchfork Music Festival to see The New Pornographers and Of Montreal this Sunday.</description></item><item><title>Happy Day Off / General personal update</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/happy-day-off-/-general-personal-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2007 08:57:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/happy-day-off-/-general-personal-update/</guid><description>The whole America rah-rah thing isn't my bag, so I celebrate this holiday for what it really is. A day off. So one of my favorite guys at work, my uber-manager, Khyle is leaving. It sucks. He's an awesome guy, an outstanding manager and i'm worried about the atmosphere once he's gone.
I've got a new title in the company, I guess I never posted about that. &amp;quot;Senior Systems Administrator, West Notifications Group&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>New piercing</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/new-piercing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2007 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/07/new-piercing/</guid><description>Left lobe. 10 gauge. {width=&amp;ldquo;133&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}
Lauren thought I was crazy for getting that big of a piercing right off the bat. But there's nothing as invigorating as a big needle ripping through flesh to feel alive. I guess it could also make you feel like you're dying. But whatever. I think it's cool.</description></item><item><title>The World of Stupid Man, the Comic Book</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/the-world-of-stupid-man-the-comic-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2007 17:32:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/the-world-of-stupid-man-the-comic-book/</guid><description>So I came across an archive of little comics I made in 6th grade. These are surrounded around the character &amp;quot;Stupid Man&amp;quot; and his friends. I'll post a new one every once and a while. So to start things up is Stupid Man #1. Click on the thumbnail to read it.
{width=&amp;ldquo;60&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>A request to put some life into PandoraFM</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/a-request-to-put-some-life-into-pandorafm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 08:02:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/a-request-to-put-some-life-into-pandorafm/</guid><description>So PandoraFM version 3 is a little long in the tooth, i'm aware. It's almost a year old now. I'm proud to say, it still seems to work great! One year and 2.6 million tracks later people still use it every day, and people are still discovering it for the first time. That being said, the people who have been using it deserve something new. At the very least Pandora has updated their color scheme and PandoraFM no longer looks as pretty with regards to matching it.</description></item><item><title>How to get divorced using a mac</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/how-to-get-divorced-using-a-mac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2007 00:17:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/how-to-get-divorced-using-a-mac/</guid><description>&amp;quot;What?&amp;quot; You may ask? &amp;quot;That doesn't make sense!&amp;quot; Well sure it does. It's all about how you use your tools, and I used my Mac recently to get divorced.You too can use your Mac to end the tyranny and again regain freedom with your MacBook, Mac Pro, or whatever Apple branded product you may have on hand. Keep in mind, I do not recommend getting divorced with a PC. It may not go well.</description></item><item><title>An update now that things are done</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/an-update-now-that-things-are-done/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/an-update-now-that-things-are-done/</guid><description>So yeah. I'm divorced. She's still being really awful about things, though. I've let her know that if she hates me so much, she should stop reading my blog. I seriously don't get it. Nobody that she knows reads it. She never read it before we separated. She's just trying to make my life difficult.
But being she probably won't stop reading, and I guess my prose here is just so thrilling i'm going to have to set a ground rule for myself.</description></item><item><title>Congrats to me!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/congrats-to-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 17:32:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/congrats-to-me/</guid><description>{width=&amp;ldquo;76&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>A new beginning</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/a-new-beginning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 22:03:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/a-new-beginning/</guid><description>Thursday marked a big day in my life. A page was turned, and a new chapter began. Sometimes things happen that you can't change, and sometimes they don't always go the way you hope they would. Sometimes you force things into your life and they cause a wound that just won't heal. There are good days, there are bad days. But you know in the end that it won't work out, and it would eventually be gone forever.</description></item><item><title>Perpetual Hosting</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/perpetual-hosting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 19:14:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/perpetual-hosting/</guid><description>Here's an interesting topic, and one that i've put a lot of thought into. I'm not going to live forever. I sure hope not, anyway. In fact, I may not live until tomorrow. There's more things that'll kill then will keep things alive. I may just run into one of them. If that were to happen, what happens to my stuff? Does my life online die, like I never existed? Do I hope one of my friends from #TheCabin jumps in and archives all they can and puts up some kind of lame shrine like for this guy?</description></item><item><title>Sick</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/sick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2007 07:51:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/sick/</guid><description>Argh. I hate when I get sick, it never goes away. I got sick this weekend and it'll be here to stay for a while. It's the standard &amp;quot;i think it's a cold&amp;quot; but really I know it's a sinus infection, because that's what I get. It's a sore throat because of all the crap falling from my sinuses as a post-nasal drip, and when I blow my nose I get equal part nose crap and blood crap.</description></item><item><title>Status on my album, or whatever</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/status-on-my-album-or-whatever/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2007 10:11:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/status-on-my-album-or-whatever/</guid><description>So i've pretty much had the freedom now for over a month to work on my music whenever I want to. There's a problem though, an a rather large one. I don't want to. There's just too much going on, and i'm unable to focus on a large project like that at the present time. It's really bothering me. I mean, there's no timeline, so there's really no problem. It's my own thing, and there's nobody chomping at the bit to listen to this stuff.</description></item><item><title>Happy Monday</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/happy-monday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/happy-monday/</guid><description>So it's Monday. For whatever reason my alarm didn't go off, but I never sleep late anymore so I woke up without a problem anyway. Just woke up a little later than I wanted to. No biggy. Had a good weekend. Sat around and watched Joost last night. It's a great alternative to paying the awful cable company $100 month for Oxygen Network and the Golf Channel.
I'm not allowed to talk about certain people on my blog, but that doesn't mean I can't tell you what's going on in my life.</description></item><item><title>Looking at art</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/looking-at-art/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/looking-at-art/</guid><description>So i'm looking at stuff to throw on the walls. I bookmarked a few things on my apartment list at http://del.icio.us/gabek/apartment. My favorite is a big black circle for over $260. It's so pretentious. I love it. I'll be that guy. I have two more Matrix posters to hang, but they're so large, i'm not so sure i'm going to use them. They're so cool, though. Maybe i'll put one in my bedroom.</description></item><item><title>Happy Friday, Friends</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/happy-friday-friends/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 08:21:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/happy-friday-friends/</guid><description>I had a good birthday. Went to Pepes and had Tacos. Drank some Margar33tas. Played Super Mario Brothers 3, and drank some beer. I can't really ask for more than that. {width=&amp;ldquo;133&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}
I got my furniture in. Even with more crap, my apartment still looks empty. Argh. I try so hard. At least I have a dining room table and coffee table and some chairs now. No more eating pizza off the floor.</description></item><item><title>Overruled</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/overruled/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 22:40:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/overruled/</guid><description>I've been temporarily overruled again on what I can and can't post to my own web site. Seriously. Seriously? What a joke.</description></item><item><title>What do you do? A post on Jaiku.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/what-do-you-do-a-post-on-jaiku./</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 08:04:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/what-do-you-do-a-post-on-jaiku./</guid><description>I've had a Jaiku account now for a couple weeks, I really like it. It's a one stop shop to answer a question someone may ask you like &amp;quot;What do you do online?&amp;quot; Or &amp;quot;What do you like?&amp;quot; Or &amp;quot;Where's your stuff?&amp;quot; Increasingly many people have many different things spread throughout the internet. Bookmarks, playlists, blogs, etc etc. I've gone the extra step of building my website around the fact that there is no central repository of a person online anymore, and it allows me to add things as more things show up in my online life.</description></item><item><title>Welcome back my friends, to the show that never ends.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/welcome-back-my-friends-to-the-show-that-never-ends./</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 19:30:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/welcome-back-my-friends-to-the-show-that-never-ends./</guid><description>So it took me a while longer than I hoped, but here I am. Kelley filed a restraining and gag order against me. That means no talking about the divorce, at all, in any manner. On top of that after it's all over, the restraining order kicks in and says I can't post to my blog, at all, mentioning the divorce. Or that I was ever married, or anything.
Kind of dumb, isn't it?</description></item><item><title>An update</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/an-update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2007 14:37:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/an-update/</guid><description>I'm not allowed to post things to my blog anymore. I'm not sure if i'm allowed to say that, but my friends and family deserve a quick post. I can't tell you why, because i'm not allowed to tell you.
I can't tell you when i'll be able to again, i'm sorry. I thought password protecting the posts from the public would be over and above what i'd be expected to do, but nothing is good enough.</description></item><item><title>mmmm steak</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/mmmm-steak/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 09:28:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/mmmm-steak/</guid><description>I had the most delicious steak ever last night. I went to Ruth's Chris Steakhouse and it rocked. They flash cook the meat at 1800F, and the plate comes out at 500F. Had awesome sides of potatoes and some great desert to top it all off. My apartment kicks ass. The kitchen is complete and i'm able to move everything in there now. I got home late last night, so I haven't had a chance to do that yet.</description></item><item><title>Protected entries</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/protected-entries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 13:34:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/protected-entries/</guid><description>Many past and future entries are going to be protected on this blog. If you feel that you are someone who has been reading the site and would like access to them, please let me know. gabek@real-ity.com. However, many discussions will not be public at the current time, and for that I apologize. To view the post click on the title of the post from the main page (probably what you're looking at now, or via RSS), and type in the password you're given.</description></item><item><title>The Verbage</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/the-verbage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/the-verbage/</guid><description>&amp;quot;Specifically, the parties agree to not refer to the prior relationship on the internet, in any manner, including blog sites, web pages and the like. In the event this type of publication occurs in the future, the parties specifically reserve the right to pursue all remedies that would be available to them, including filing a claim for Intentional Infliction of Emotional Distress.&amp;quot;</description></item><item><title>So sue me and I moved into my new apartment</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/so-sue-me-and-i-moved-into-my-new-apartment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 06:58:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/05/so-sue-me-and-i-moved-into-my-new-apartment/</guid><description>I don't have a lot of time, as I need to finish getting ready for work, but i'd thought i'd post something up. I moved into my new apartment, and it kicks ass. Everything went really smooth. Nothing is really broke, no walls with holes in them, nothing crazy. It went really well, and I had a great crew helping me out. I'll get more into the apartment later, but I'm just glad to finally be here.</description></item><item><title>New Rules</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/new-rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2007 18:36:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/new-rules/</guid><description>Below is the email sent to Kelley outlining the new rules of our little situation. Enjoy.------- The truth is we have not been separated since November. You have taken part in perjury. For me to agree to the statement would be doing the same. However, if you agree to my requests from here on, I am willing to listen and accept your explanation of the statement as fact.
I've had enough of receiving paperwork full of demands from you when I've recieved no equal paperwork telling me what I'll get in return.</description></item><item><title>Got served with my papers</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/got-served-with-my-papers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2007 07:59:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/got-served-with-my-papers/</guid><description>Right out of a tv show. The doorbell rang and a stranger said &amp;quot;Are you Gabriel Kangas?&amp;quot; I said yes, and he handed me a stack of papers and walked away. What a bitch. She wanted to make this &amp;quot;easy&amp;quot;, she could had went to the county clerk's office and filled out a form and had been done with it. But now I'm just getting pissed off. I keep getting official paper after paper saying &amp;quot;Gabe will do this, Gabe will do that.</description></item><item><title>And now things really get messy. I'm losing my car.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/and-now-things-really-get-messy.-im-losing-my-car./</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/and-now-things-really-get-messy.-im-losing-my-car./</guid><description>Yes, more messy than the dirt thrown all over my stuff, and the eternal smell of incense in the house. I received a copy of the settlement proposal yesterday from my attorney. Imagine my surprise reading that if I don't get Kelley off my car loan by July 1st I have to sell my car and pay off the loan. This is after she said she would say on my car loan to make my &amp;quot;life easier&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>And things got worse</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/and-things-got-worse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 08:01:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/and-things-got-worse/</guid><description>Over the phone yesterday Kelley told me she wants me out. Point blank, out. Find somewhere else to live. She was screaming at me on the phone and said some really awful things. She told me that I took advantage of her mother's death. I don't even know what that means. So I left, and came back to get stuff to move it out of the house. When I got home the house full of smoke.</description></item><item><title>Cell bill</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/cell-bill/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 15:38:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/cell-bill/</guid><description>I just got a Sprint Cell Phone bill for almost $400. It must have to do with the change since Kelley left my sprint account. I can't believe how bad things are right now. Proof to those who say &amp;quot;it'll only get better&amp;quot; that it CAN get worse.</description></item><item><title>End of a weekend</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/end-of-a-weekend/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2007 23:08:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/end-of-a-weekend/</guid><description>Kelley stayed at a co-worker's house to play with their kids Saturday night. I missed having her at home. But today she came home, I got Kelley and I dinner, we were watching tv. I thought we were really enjoying each other's company, and it was nice not to be stressed out for a while. After a show, she mentioned she was going up to take a shower. She stopped on the way up to say something really mean.</description></item><item><title>Friday the 13th.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/friday-the-13th./</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2007 08:48:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/friday-the-13th./</guid><description>It's Friday the 13th. I still have nowhere to live. A payroll mistake by the company I work for set me back a little, so i'm not too happy about that. The last thing I need is for outside problems to impact me at this point. I need all the help I can get. Things are changing at work, again. At least in the &amp;quot;big picture&amp;quot; sense, not at the &amp;quot;chair level&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>Some updates</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/some-updates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2007 08:07:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/some-updates/</guid><description>So things got pretty heated the other night. She wanted us to start giving each other &amp;quot;space&amp;quot;, and then asked if I'd order us a pizza. I stepped out of the house to get some fresh air, not knowing if I would go somewhere or not to get out of the house and she said &amp;quot;you need to go&amp;quot;, turned off the lights, and locked the door. Good thing I had my keys.</description></item><item><title>Started packing my music equipment</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/started-packing-my-music-equipment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 21:42:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/started-packing-my-music-equipment/</guid><description>Obvious to say I won't be working no music again for a long while. Everything will be in boxes. That started tonight. Kelley has been packing my clothes and other personal belongings, but tonight I made the first move of my music equipment. Kelley wanted me to get certified in music production this year so I could start recording bands here at our house. She's taking that away from me. She's taking me being able to drum away from me.</description></item><item><title>Low</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/low/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 09:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/low/</guid><description>---------- "Low" as heard on 2002's "/me" album. Click to hear. Fuck me and my self prophesizing lyrics. The lyrics I wrote for my new album are crazy messed up. I wrote them having no idea my wife was going to divorce me. But the songs somehow knew. I swear they did.
Low ain\'t low. It can go, lower than you know.Look inside and it won\'t show, what happened long ago.</description></item><item><title>Day 5.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/day-5./</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2007 14:08:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/day-5./</guid><description>On day five. Believe it or not, as time goes by, no matter how much you hope... you have *less* money than you had then when you started. When you get paid, you get more, but when between pay periods the amount of money you have does go down. That does lead it to be pretty difficult to finding a new place to live and throwing together the funds needed to starting a new life.</description></item><item><title>And so it is.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/and-so-it-is./</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2007 09:40:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/04/and-so-it-is./</guid><description>{width=&amp;ldquo;133&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Seriously? Damnit.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/seriously-damnit./</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 22:02:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/seriously-damnit./</guid><description>So the person I despise more than anyone else on a professional level now is my boss. I've butted heads with him for years. YEARS. I remember getting into it with him at both our past clients. I've dealt with him all this time as a peer. He had no authority. Sure he'd push his weight around, tell you he's right and you're wrong, but I could blow him off without a problem.</description></item><item><title>A query</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/a-query/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 07:54:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/a-query/</guid><description>If you take the peripherals and case away from a computer, is it the same computer? If you take the sleek outside face away from a mac, is it then just a PC? What's inside? Can it be rebuilt as something new? Or should it just get trashed? It's far from operational without any kind of interface.
What do the insides really mean?</description></item><item><title>Ruby on Rails, .NET and other Frameworks in life</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/ruby-on-rails-.net-and-other-frameworks-in-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2007 08:25:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/ruby-on-rails-.net-and-other-frameworks-in-life/</guid><description>People say that working within restrictive frameworks give them freedom. Is it true?</description></item><item><title>So yeah, life sucks.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/so-yeah-life-sucks./</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 19:01:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/so-yeah-life-sucks./</guid><description>Kelley got in an accident the other day, the van is wrecked, but she's ok. So we're on one car. It sucks having to try and sync our schedules so I can be picked up, but we're doing our best. Kelley's dad is in the hospital. Heart and respiratory failure or something. He was knocked out pretty good last night.
And things continue to go downhill.</description></item><item><title>The useless and useful</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/the-useless-and-useful/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 20:40:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/the-useless-and-useful/</guid><description>So i'm picky with things sometimes. For instance, on my desktop I like having little widgets. However, I can never seem to find exactly what I want. It's easy to find something that gives me the weather. It's impossible to find something that gives it in fahrenheit and celsius, not to mention in multiple locations at once. It's easy to find a little applet that shows that I have a wireless signal.</description></item><item><title>Man, it's SXSW time already? How time flies. I'll sure not be busy.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/man-its-sxsw-time-already-how-time-flies.-ill-sure-not-be-busy./</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 09:41:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/man-its-sxsw-time-already-how-time-flies.-ill-sure-not-be-busy./</guid><description>It's been a whole year already since I hadn't gone to SXSW 2006 and it's time again for me to not go to SXSW 2007. I don't have my hotel all booked and my flights are not ready to go. I won't be arriving in Austin tonight.
I'm really pumped about the panels that are scheduled, I can't wait to not see them.
Did you see the lineups of the bands?</description></item><item><title>My new slogan</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/my-new-slogan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 00:16:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/03/my-new-slogan/</guid><description> If you can't use usenet, you shouldn't use the net. Stop the web. &amp;gt; It's not too late.</description></item><item><title>wtf</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/02/wtf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 00:21:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/02/wtf/</guid><description>Seriously. Should had stayed in bed today. Day went fine until I decided to go home from work and Metra decided to stop all trains from leaving Chicago on my train line.
So a few hours later (We're talking after 9pm finally) Metra decides I can finally go home and I do. Too bad the train station wasn't shoveled or plowed when I got off the train.
My car isn't anywhere near where you get off the train, it's quite the long treck.</description></item><item><title>So I cancelled cable</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/02/so-i-cancelled-cable/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2007 20:57:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/02/so-i-cancelled-cable/</guid><description>Or so I tried. I called anyway. The people at Comcast hooked me up with a new &amp;quot;deal&amp;quot; that I just couldn't pass up, or something. I have a feeling once I get the bill it won't be such a deal anymore. They find ways to add on tons of stupid charges. Add on all the other taxes and we'll see how much better off I am. I got pissed at Comcast once and for all.</description></item><item><title>headache clinic?</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/02/headache-clinic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2007 10:10:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/02/headache-clinic/</guid><description>To go or not to go? There's a place in chicago called the Diamond Headache Clinic. Being i've been on another bad downswing with the whole migraine thing i'm thinking I should see someone else... again. Not that I haven't seen enough people in the past, but it hasn't helped all that much. One thing I have got out of my neurologist is the wonderful drug of Relpax. You take one when you feel it coming on, and it takes about 2hrs to kick in.</description></item><item><title>Things and stuff, a real post in the spirit of a "blog"</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/02/things-and-stuff-a-real-post-in-the-spirit-of-a-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 22:28:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/02/things-and-stuff-a-real-post-in-the-spirit-of-a-blog/</guid><description>So lots going on. Where to begin?Today was the first meet-and-greet with the client's parent company. Felt awkward that I'm not part of it at all. When they welcomed me to the new company I wasn't going to correct them, I just nodded my head, shook hands and said it was nice to meet them.
I've been pretty confident all along that i'll be dispensed with after the acquisition. I just don't think they realize there's consultants around yet.</description></item><item><title>Couple random photos</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/couple-random-photos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 08:23:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/couple-random-photos/</guid><description>#TheCabin @ Staples&amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-size:0pt;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{=html}&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;{=html}{width=&amp;ldquo;133&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}
PandoraFM in PC World @ Walgreens {width=&amp;ldquo;133&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Go Bears!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/go-bears/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2007 19:22:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/go-bears/</guid><description>Go somewhere else, I mean. I'm not a fan of the Chicago Bears, Chicago's media toward the Chicago Bears, or anything dealing with the Chicago Bears. When they lose the Chicago media is all &amp;quot;Rex can't cut it, The Bears can't make it, turnz0rv3r.&amp;quot; and when they win it's all &amp;quot;Rex is the miracle worker, the Bears are the world's dream team!&amp;quot;. The city is the most two faced hypocritical fans of it's own team that i've ever seen.</description></item><item><title>So i'm working on music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/so-im-working-on-music/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2007 19:32:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/so-im-working-on-music/</guid><description>I think I have about 15 songs now in various stages of completion. There's probably only two or so that are &amp;quot;done&amp;quot;, another two or so that are barely started, and the rest all in between. I'm going through the phase now where I ignore all the original songs that I spent a lot of time on. During the holidays I didn't have much time to spend on music, so it was a good cleansing period.</description></item><item><title>Updating my site content</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/updating-my-site-content/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 19:40:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/updating-my-site-content/</guid><description>Just a quick update. I'm removing a few things from my web site here. First of all, removing any posts from my myspace blog... I deleted my myspace.com account. Second, digg.com Diggs. I found I wasn't digging stories just because I didn't want to flood my web page with things that probably aren't interesting. And last, my Podshow.com blog, because I hate podshow and don't use it anyway. So no loss, eh?</description></item><item><title>PandoraFM mentioned in PC World Magazine</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/pandorafm-mentioned-in-pc-world-magazine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2007 20:21:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/pandorafm-mentioned-in-pc-world-magazine/</guid><description>That's cool in itself, but the article name: The Web's Most Useful Sites. Really? Sweet! I'll take it!
Now I need to go out and get a print copy of the magazine, cuz that's so very cool.
Here's a PDF of the web version.
http://www.real-ity.com/dropbox/PC%20World%20-%20The%20Web's%20Most%20Useful%20Sites%20December%2022%202006.pdf :)
Edit: Jeff just got his copy of February's PC World and it's in there. Go out and get yourself a copy!
Listening to: Dance With Me from the album &amp;quot;Smokey Joe's Cafe - The Songs Of Lieber And Stoller - Act One&amp;quot; by Jerry Lieber &amp;amp; Mike Stoller</description></item><item><title>I'm going to school.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/im-going-to-school./</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 10:37:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/im-going-to-school./</guid><description>Kind of anyway.Berklee Music Starting a program for music production. Starting my first class January 8th. It's not real college, no college credits, nothing more than me wanting to learn things. So don't start thinking that i'm into the whole school thing, i'm not. But if you want to learn things, like I do, then that's cool. I see this as the complete opposite from &amp;quot;I take classes because I should.</description></item><item><title>End of Year Wrapup 2006.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/end-of-year-wrapup-2006./</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 00:11:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/end-of-year-wrapup-2006./</guid><description>&lt;p>How time flies! It's been over a year since my 2005 wrapup post, and things have &lt;strong>really&lt;/strong> changed! I hope you'll follow me through another journey that is my yearly post. I like to think the things I use are pretty good, and that I go through the crap so you don't have to. Here's the one time of year I can tell you not just what I recommend, but what I really use/do/listen to/etc. Step 1. &lt;a href="http://www.real-ity.com/blog/?p=120">Read last year's post.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 2. Read this one...`&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy Days Off</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/happy-days-off/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2006 10:15:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/happy-days-off/</guid><description>Well, they're days off for me, anyway. I've been off so far this week, and this is my last day off. Wanted to blow some vacation days before I lose them. Wish I could carry some over, but I can't. Oh well.
Been spending most of the time on music. Most of it really sucks, so I find myself wanting to spend more and more time making it not suck. I'm generally unsuccessful.</description></item><item><title>Over 1,000,000 tracks played through PandoraFM</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/over-1000000-tracks-played-through-pandorafm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2006 10:06:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/over-1000000-tracks-played-through-pandorafm/</guid><description>On July 1st of this year I started a counter on how many songs are being played through the PandoraFM interface. I haven't really been paying attention to it lately, in any aspect. I just let it run. I haven't been changing, fixing.. doing anything to it. I'm actually quite proud of that, it's running well for a ton of people and i'm not having to make daily fixes. I guess all that time I spent on version 3 paid off in the end.</description></item><item><title>New project: CabinTunez. The ultimate mp3 collection.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/new-project-cabintunez.-the-ultimate-mp3-collection./</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2006 14:14:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/new-project-cabintunez.-the-ultimate-mp3-collection./</guid><description>Been working with Bob the past few days on a new Cabin project. I started the framework a while back but never did much with it. Unfortunately, this is all private, so I can't really share it. But I can give you a screenshot and make you wish you had access to CabinTunez, the ultimate mp3 collection.
{width=&amp;ldquo;148&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;}</description></item><item><title>Martin at Last.FM</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/11/martin-at-last.fm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2006 07:48:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/11/martin-at-last.fm/</guid><description>Martin, co-founder of Last.FM invited me to stop by their office and visit next time I'm in London. How cool is that! Another data point in my Google Earth KMZ of life.</description></item><item><title>Server Status</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/10/server-status/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2006 08:18:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/10/server-status/</guid><description>So I got email really working. It wasn't working before. In fact most emails were bouncing. So if you emailed me, and it bounced... please send again. Got my web log back up, obviously. Tonight i'll have to reinstall the photo album database. I just realized I have the old version installed that wasn't database driven. Wonder if I can import it. Still a ton lost, but maybe it's something?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/1/01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/1/01/</guid><description>--- layout: post title: Goodbye, Rdio description: I chronicle my time as a user and employee of the much-loved music streaming service. categories: - San Francisco tags: - rdio - pandora - featured status: publish type: post published: true date: 2015-11-17 17:41:12.000000000 +00:00 cardthumbimage: '/blog/images/rdio-retro-image.jpg' cardheaderimage: '/blog/images/rdio-retro-image.jpg' meta: _thumbnail_id: '289' author: name: Gabe Kangas website: http://gabekangas email: gabek@real-ity.com github: https://github.com/gabek image: '/images/avatar-64x64.png' ---
Like everybody else, I felt like I had heard every song on Pandora by the time I discovered Rdio.</description></item></channel></rss>