<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/categories/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A brief update on Owncast</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/12/a-brief-update-on-owncast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/12/a-brief-update-on-owncast/</guid><description>I made a post when I pushed up my initial idea of Owncast to GitHub, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted any status updates to my own website since then. There&amp;rsquo;s been some significant traction lately, so I wanted to take a moment to write an update.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been making steady progress under the radar with a fantastic group of people who have discovered the project. We knew that once we completed our Owncast web admin feature that we&amp;rsquo;d let a few more people know about the status of things, since it&amp;rsquo;s an added level of polish and ease of use that might appeal to people.</description></item><item><title>Apple Has Shut Down The Bat Player</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/08/apple-has-shut-down-the-bat-player/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 09:41:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/08/apple-has-shut-down-the-bat-player/</guid><description>Today The Bat Player on AppleTV was shut down. I wanted to document a bit about the history of the application, and why it&amp;rsquo;s being rejected from the Apple AppStore.
I started The Bat Player in 2014. I wanted a better Internet Radio experience on the TV. I dreamt of artist info, album details and photos. At the time most Internet Radio apps just showed text of the currently playing track and I wanted more.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye Longtail Music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/12/goodbye-longtail-music/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:21:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/12/goodbye-longtail-music/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I shut down Longtail Music, my internet radio discovery platform. I wanted to give a bit of a postmortem to talk about what I sent out to do, what it did, and why I think things never worked out.
I originally built Longtail Music as a spinoff from my time with The Bat Player, an internet radio client for the TV. I thought if The Bat Player was a client for people who already love internet radio and know what they want to listen to, then I want to build something on the web for people to discover internet radio for the first time and discover a station they would love.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Longtail Music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2017/04/introducing-longtail-music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2017/04/introducing-longtail-music/</guid><description>{=html} &amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/214576527?wmode=opaque&amp;amp;amp;api=1&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;640&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;360&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Longtail Music Promo&amp;quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; It's no secret I've been frustrated with music discovery for a while. Ever since Rdio shut down I've listened to less music on mainstream services. While I do have a Spotify account, I tend to only use it to listen to old playlists and comfort music.
Where music discovery has been successful for me, however, is with internet radio.</description></item><item><title>Launching The Bat Player on the Roku Store and its aftermath</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/07/launching-the-bat-player-on-the-roku-store-and-its-aftermath/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 16:39:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/07/launching-the-bat-player-on-the-roku-store-and-its-aftermath/</guid><description>After a year of development The Bat Player went live on Roku's Channel Store.
The Bat Player first went public in September of last year. This means if you knew the right Roku Channel Code you could install it on your device. I put up a web site to make this easier, and shared it with a couple specific communities like the Roku forums and Reddit's Roku subreddit.
My goal all along was to get it available in their mainstream directory.</description></item><item><title>Developing for Roku</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2014/12/developing-for-roku/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2014/12/developing-for-roku/</guid><description>{=html} &amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/112659447?wmode=opaque&amp;amp;amp;api=1&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1280&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;720&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;The Bat Player&amp;quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&amp;gt; {=html} &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; Ask yourself, &amp;quot;Do I know anybody who's developed anything for the Roku Media Player?&amp;quot; More than likely the answer is no. If you ask others you might get get some response, but more than likely nobody you know has done it either.
And that's why I wanted to throw up a little piece about building for the Roku.</description></item><item><title>Building TastemakerX for iOS</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/12/building-tastemakerx-for-ios/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 19:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/12/building-tastemakerx-for-ios/</guid><description>It's still in beta, and I'm still happily iterating over all of the features of the application, but I wanted to share the tools I used, the services I take advantage of, and overall tidbits that might be useful to fellow developers about how I've been building TastemakerX. Maybe you can in turn share some things with me.
Tools that made my life easier. &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-
Spark Inspector
Spark Inspector Both it and Reveal popped up around the same time, but since then I've been using Spark Inspector as a tool to debug view-related things.</description></item><item><title>Stuff I'd like to do in 2013</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/01/stuff-id-like-to-do-in-2013/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 18:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/01/stuff-id-like-to-do-in-2013/</guid><description>I'm not a fan of New Years resolutions, but there are some things I'd like to do in this next year. All very doable things, but if you think that in any way you'd be able to help with any of them I'd certainly be up for pointers!
Contribute to an open source project that focuses on a) mobile and b) something I care about. (Note: I checked out the Colloquy source last night and started looking at their bug list to see if I could help with anything).</description></item><item><title>Boulder Startup Week 2011</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/05/boulder-startup-week-2011/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2011/05/boulder-startup-week-2011/</guid><description>So on the recommendation of my friend @sethhwilson in the hour before the deadline I half-assed an email to @ryanwanger of Boulder Startup Week for their &amp;quot;We'll fly you to Boulder free&amp;quot; offer. They were going to hand pick a handful of people and bring them in for the event. I honestly kind of forgot about it, and I really only did it as one of those &amp;quot;take advantage of opportunity because you never know&amp;quot; kind of things that I'm trying to be proactive about.</description></item><item><title>Lost and Found: A video experiment started in 2006</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/lost-and-found-a-video-experiment-started-in-2006/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 13:57:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/lost-and-found-a-video-experiment-started-in-2006/</guid><description>In 2006 I was diligently working on my (still unreleased) new album &amp;quot;The Longest Post&amp;quot;. With that I decided to create a couple music videos both as an experiment on if I could make something fun, and to have a visual way to distribute some songs. A couple apartment moves later and the hard drives with the music videos were lost.
Until now. In October, 2010 I found the hard drives while cleaning out my music studio and decided it was time to show them to the world.</description></item><item><title>#TheCabin Mobile for iPhone</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/09/#thecabin-mobile-for-iphone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 15:43:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/09/#thecabin-mobile-for-iphone/</guid><description>I've always said if I took all the time and effort I spent into side projects and spent them on something else I'd have a lot of cool other things. But I've spent some nights and weekends working on this new little app, my first submission to the iTunes App Store. (Approved in 8 days, FYI) As some of you may know, for the past 15 years I've been helping manage an internet relay chat (IRC) channel I started called #TheCabin.</description></item><item><title>TechStars for a Day, startup culture, and my comparisons to Omaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/05/techstars-for-a-day-startup-culture-and-my-comparisons-to-omaha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 13:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/05/techstars-for-a-day-startup-culture-and-my-comparisons-to-omaha/</guid><description>Alright, stay with me. I promise you'll get something at the end. I don't promise you'll like it, though. I attended TechStars for a Day in Seattle. If you want to know what this rockin' organization does check it out. But in short, they are a business accelerator. Get your company off the ground in the most awesome way possible.
It seemed like a classic case of serendipity. I was behind the controls at Big Omaha helping the speakers tell their inspiring stories when an email invite came in from TechStars to join them in Seattle to hear more about the program and to give them an opportunity to meet me.</description></item><item><title>I was asked what I've been doing. So here you go!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/04/i-was-asked-what-ive-been-doing.-so-here-you-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2010 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/04/i-was-asked-what-ive-been-doing.-so-here-you-go/</guid><description>I struggled on what should be included in this post. A part of me thinks having a veil over personal feelings about things that I'm doing are a good thing. But that's the opposite of transparency, and I do want to take as many people on the wild ride with me as possible. A while back my buddy Frank said my next blog post should be about what I'm doing. It wasn't until then that I realized from the outside (especially outside of Omaha), what I do, what my goals are, and my what daily routine is may seem a little odd, if not completely invisible.</description></item><item><title>I've been quiet! I've been busy!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/01/ive-been-quiet-ive-been-busy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/01/ive-been-quiet-ive-been-busy/</guid><description>I haven't blogged for quite a while. And that's not a bad thing. It's been a couple months now since I left my position at West, and I haven't said a word about it since then. There's no real reason why except I've been super busy. Busy with a handful of really awesome things.
I've had the chance to work on some really neat projects lately, and I'm really looking forward to continuing it.</description></item><item><title>Admiral Ackbar joins Twitter</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/admiral-ackbar-joins-twitter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 15:39:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/08/admiral-ackbar-joins-twitter/</guid><description>Per recommendation of @EternalCow I built a bot that puts a much needed appearance of Admiral Ackbar (@AdmiralAckbar_) on Twitter. He's warning (as he should be) to all who will listen that &amp;quot;It's a trap!&amp;quot; This is funny, but the most entertaining part is the fact that people are replying back.
See below for a real time update of responses to &amp;quot;It's a trap!&amp;quot;
I'll soon have itsatrap.org up :P</description></item><item><title>My interview about Retweet Thursday</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/my-interview-about-retweet-thursday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 11:29:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/my-interview-about-retweet-thursday/</guid><description>Well who would have thought? The fine people over at Silicon Prairie News were interested in talking to me about the weirdest meme to ever hit Twitter (aside from #MufasaMonday I suppose), #retweet_thursday. They told me they weren't sure who was behind it at first, but figured out it was out of Omaha somewhere, so they pinpointed it to me. I never really made it public that the bot was run by me, but I wasn't really hiding the fact either :)</description></item><item><title>Making a leap</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/making-a-leap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 10:20:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/making-a-leap/</guid><description>I'm going to be a real ass-hat with this post, and I apologize. I'm not going to tell any details, but instead I'm just going to type and you can be annoyed afterwards. I've been working on a project. And at first I thought it was going to go one direction, but then I decided to take it a different direction in my execution of it.
Previous projects I've worked on usually have a life cycle that includes me wanting to build something, I work a lot in all of my spare time on it, putting out a version, and then being drained from my &amp;quot;day job&amp;quot; and unable to continue to work on it anymore.</description></item><item><title>Tweply and SMS</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/03/tweply-and-sms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 11:43:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/03/tweply-and-sms/</guid><description>Happy post Saint Patrick's day. So maybe I was optimistic (or pessimistic, depending on how you see it) about Tweply and SMS functionality. Like other projects I've thrown together I felt a need that I couldn't find elsewhere, and then offered it to others. Except this time it's costing me more than I expected with people signing up for it.
I love that people find it useful, but unfortunately I'm paying much more than I expected.</description></item><item><title>Tweply - since nobody talked me out of it</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/tweply-since-nobody-talked-me-out-of-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/02/tweply-since-nobody-talked-me-out-of-it/</guid><description>I was hoping someone would talk me out of another stupid idea. Damn you all. So this is what you get. An alpha thingy of Tweply. http://www.real-ity.com/tweply/
No promises how well it'll work, but it should work ok. It looks ugly. Well.. actually it looks more like nothing. That's how my design skills are. Couple header tags, a center, some text and not close out the body.
Again, you have to give out your twitter password to use it.</description></item><item><title>PandoraFM defaced yesterday</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/pandorafm-defaced-yesterday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 04:37:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/02/pandorafm-defaced-yesterday/</guid><description>Yesterday morning PandoraFM was defaced.
A hacker, not unknown to me from the past, put up some pretty graphic text on the front page of PandoraFM about me. Things i'd never say were posted up, along with mention of contacting &amp;quot;my girlfriend&amp;quot; and family as well. Except I don't have a girlfriend. And the photo he had up was extremely old, certainly not one i'd ever use.
I got ahold of the guy on IRC and talked to him for a bit.</description></item><item><title>Over 2,991,000 other tracks have been submitted to Last.FM profiles through PandoraFM.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/over-2991000-other-tracks-have-been-submitted-to-last.fm-profiles-through-pandorafm./</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2007 11:35:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/08/over-2991000-other-tracks-have-been-submitted-to-last.fm-profiles-through-pandorafm./</guid><description>Crazy. It's been over a year since PandoraFM v3 was released, and I haven't really touched it at all since then. And it still works, and people still use it.
This fact clicked today when I ran into a post on a tech site about someone discovering it for the first time and thought it rocked. Here I am thinking it's 10min from death, and someone else thinks it's a brand new rockin site.</description></item><item><title>A request to put some life into PandoraFM</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/a-request-to-put-some-life-into-pandorafm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 08:02:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/06/a-request-to-put-some-life-into-pandorafm/</guid><description>So PandoraFM version 3 is a little long in the tooth, i'm aware. It's almost a year old now. I'm proud to say, it still seems to work great! One year and 2.6 million tracks later people still use it every day, and people are still discovering it for the first time. That being said, the people who have been using it deserve something new. At the very least Pandora has updated their color scheme and PandoraFM no longer looks as pretty with regards to matching it.</description></item><item><title>PandoraFM mentioned in PC World Magazine</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/pandorafm-mentioned-in-pc-world-magazine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2007 20:21:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2007/01/pandorafm-mentioned-in-pc-world-magazine/</guid><description>That's cool in itself, but the article name: The Web's Most Useful Sites. Really? Sweet! I'll take it!
Now I need to go out and get a print copy of the magazine, cuz that's so very cool.
Here's a PDF of the web version.
http://www.real-ity.com/dropbox/PC%20World%20-%20The%20Web's%20Most%20Useful%20Sites%20December%2022%202006.pdf :)
Edit: Jeff just got his copy of February's PC World and it's in there. Go out and get yourself a copy!
Listening to: Dance With Me from the album &amp;quot;Smokey Joe's Cafe - The Songs Of Lieber And Stoller - Act One&amp;quot; by Jerry Lieber &amp;amp; Mike Stoller</description></item><item><title>Over 1,000,000 tracks played through PandoraFM</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/over-1000000-tracks-played-through-pandorafm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2006 10:06:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2006/12/over-1000000-tracks-played-through-pandorafm/</guid><description>On July 1st of this year I started a counter on how many songs are being played through the PandoraFM interface. I haven't really been paying attention to it lately, in any aspect. I just let it run. I haven't been changing, fixing.. doing anything to it. I'm actually quite proud of that, it's running well for a ton of people and i'm not having to make daily fixes. I guess all that time I spent on version 3 paid off in the end.</description></item></channel></rss>