<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recommendations on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/recommendations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recommendations on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/recommendations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2018 in review</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2018-12-28-2018-12-my-2018-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2018-12-28-2018-12-my-2018-in-review/</guid>
      <description>I figured enough has taken place this year, enough changes have taken place, and I’ve worked on enough projects that a post recapping things might be worthwhile.
To start, here’s a playlist of my favorite songs of the year that you can listen to while reading this post.
So what did I do with this year?  It seems, looking back, I wrote a ton of code. Professionally I contributed to a Roku app, two iOS apps, AppleTV and Amazon Fire/Android TV apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radvent Dec 5 - #Radvent tunage</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2010-12-05-2010-12-radvent-dec-5-radvent-tunage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2010-12-05-2010-12-radvent-dec-5-radvent-tunage/</guid>
      <description>Create the soundtrack of your year.
Now THIS is more like it! Though to be honest I feel like I talk about music to people so often I don&#39;t know what to put here that&#39;s worth reading.
It&#39;s actually pretty easy for me to find what I&#39;ve been listening to this past year because of Last.FM. In fact here is my 12 month chart in detail. However, this year I haven&#39;t really been &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Song Recommendation: Mark Mallman - Mother Made Me Do It</title>
      <link>http://example.org/_posts/2010-10-11-2010-10-weekly-song-recommendation-mark-mallman-mother-made-me-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/_posts/2010-10-11-2010-10-weekly-song-recommendation-mark-mallman-mother-made-me-do-it/</guid>
      <description>I haven&#39;t done a music recommendation post in a while. It&#39;s certainly not weekly, but I&#39;m not changing the naming. I don&#39;t know, stopped feeling inspired, I guess.Well fuck if I don&#39;t feel inspired now.
I&#39;ve always been a fan of Mark Mallman&#39;s. It started, like many of artists I enjoy do, seeing a show of theirs without knowing who they were beforehand. This is a prime example of the Gabe Kangas music/movie introduction theory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>