<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mysterious Dottie on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/mysterious-dottie/</link><description>Recent content in Mysterious Dottie on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 13:52:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/mysterious-dottie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TechStars for a Day, startup culture, and my comparisons to Omaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/05/techstars-for-a-day-startup-culture-and-my-comparisons-to-omaha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 13:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/05/techstars-for-a-day-startup-culture-and-my-comparisons-to-omaha/</guid><description>Alright, stay with me. I promise you'll get something at the end. I don't promise you'll like it, though. I attended TechStars for a Day in Seattle. If you want to know what this rockin' organization does check it out. But in short, they are a business accelerator. Get your company off the ground in the most awesome way possible.
It seemed like a classic case of serendipity. I was behind the controls at Big Omaha helping the speakers tell their inspiring stories when an email invite came in from TechStars to join them in Seattle to hear more about the program and to give them an opportunity to meet me.</description></item><item><title>Gabe takes on South by Southwest Interactive 2010</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/03/gabe-takes-on-south-by-southwest-interactive-2010/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 19:26:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/03/gabe-takes-on-south-by-southwest-interactive-2010/</guid><description>One of the things I've convinced myself of in this past year is that if there's something I want to do, then I should do it.{.alignleft .size-medium .wp-image-1523 width=&amp;quot;218&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;quot;240&amp;rdquo;} Sounds simple right? But not so much. In this particular example, South by Southwest, it's something I've wanted to attend for years. But instead of just deciding I was going to go I wallowed in my cube and read/watched what was going on in the week long center of the world.</description></item><item><title>I've been quiet! I've been busy!</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/01/ive-been-quiet-ive-been-busy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/01/ive-been-quiet-ive-been-busy/</guid><description>I haven't blogged for quite a while. And that's not a bad thing. It's been a couple months now since I left my position at West, and I haven't said a word about it since then. There's no real reason why except I've been super busy. Busy with a handful of really awesome things.
I've had the chance to work on some really neat projects lately, and I'm really looking forward to continuing it.</description></item></channel></rss>