<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Owncast v0.1.0 Retrospective - Redesign</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2023/02/owncast-v0.1.0-retrospective-redesign/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2023/02/owncast-v0.1.0-retrospective-redesign/</guid><description>With Owncast v0.1.0 in a bug fixing and early testing phase now, I thought I’d write some blog posts about what it’s been like to work on the project. A lot of projects don’t go into depth about how the sausage is made, but I still think people are interested in what’s going on even though they don&amp;rsquo;t go out of their way to ask.</description></item><item><title>Decentralized discovery</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/08/decentralized-discovery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/08/decentralized-discovery/</guid><description>Often the first thing brought up when discussing decentralized content is the difficulty of discovery. Big Tech has all these data points combining the content on their platform with all the consumers so they can make educated guesses to route people to content that benefit the platform, data brokers, advertisers, governments, and lastly somewhere down the line the consumers. How can those who want to opt out of those networks compete in this game?</description></item><item><title>An exciting update about Owncast</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2021/06/an-exciting-update-about-owncast/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2021/06/an-exciting-update-about-owncast/</guid><description>Today in our periodic team sync-up call I announced to the Owncast team that we have been awarded a grant by the NLnet Foundation to support work around federation and ActivityPub.
This is super exciting, as NLnet have proven to be a steward of openness, standards and open source. Having approval from NLnet and allowing Owncast to join that community of fantastic projects really makes me believe that Owncast is going the right direction and caring about the right things.</description></item><item><title>A personal update about career and the future</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2021/04/a-personal-update-about-career-and-the-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2021/04/a-personal-update-about-career-and-the-future/</guid><description>Before COVID hit I was about three years into working at a pretty cool company as an iOS engineer. I joined the company before the product launched and had a great time. But like things do, sometimes you grow apart when the company gets bigger and priorities change. So at the point everyone started working from home full time it became increasingly more difficult and I decided to leave the company.</description></item><item><title>A brief update on Owncast</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/12/a-brief-update-on-owncast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/12/a-brief-update-on-owncast/</guid><description>I made a post when I pushed up my initial idea of Owncast to GitHub, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted any status updates to my own website since then. There&amp;rsquo;s been some significant traction lately, so I wanted to take a moment to write an update.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been making steady progress under the radar with a fantastic group of people who have discovered the project. We knew that once we completed our Owncast web admin feature that we&amp;rsquo;d let a few more people know about the status of things, since it&amp;rsquo;s an added level of polish and ease of use that might appeal to people.</description></item><item><title>Apple Has Shut Down The Bat Player</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/08/apple-has-shut-down-the-bat-player/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 09:41:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/08/apple-has-shut-down-the-bat-player/</guid><description>Today The Bat Player on AppleTV was shut down. I wanted to document a bit about the history of the application, and why it&amp;rsquo;s being rejected from the Apple AppStore.
I started The Bat Player in 2014. I wanted a better Internet Radio experience on the TV. I dreamt of artist info, album details and photos. At the time most Internet Radio apps just showed text of the currently playing track and I wanted more.</description></item><item><title>Owncast: A project to take control over your own live streaming</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/06/owncast-a-project-to-take-control-over-your-own-live-streaming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/06/owncast-a-project-to-take-control-over-your-own-live-streaming/</guid><description>Backstory. In 2020 the world changed when everyone become stuck in their homes, looking for creative outlets to share their art, skills and themselves from inside their bedroom.
This created an explosion of live streaming on Facebook Live, YouTube, Instagram, and Twitch. These services provided everything they needed, an easy way to live stream to the world, and a chat for users to be a part of their community.</description></item><item><title>Some recent projects for my DJ mix hobby</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/05/some-recent-projects-for-my-dj-mix-hobby/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/05/some-recent-projects-for-my-dj-mix-hobby/</guid><description>While the lockdowns have been going on, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t been working (I&amp;rsquo;ll probably blog about that soon), I&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping busy with other projects.
I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up a new hobby of doing some DJ mixes, streaming them on internet radio, and recording them for sharing with friends. This has led me to building some tooling around all of this stuff that I think, for a small population, might find useful.</description></item><item><title>When work becomes life: A Pandemic story</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/03/when-work-becomes-life-a-pandemic-story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/03/when-work-becomes-life-a-pandemic-story/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s no lack of thinkpieces around the lockdowns and global work from home changes taking place. But I wanted to discuss a different angle that people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be discussing, at least publicly.
Right now the internet is flooded with screenshots of Zoom video conferences, everyone smiling, talking about their cute background images and how comfortable it is to be home. They&amp;rsquo;re talking about how they&amp;rsquo;re working more efficient than ever, how they can just roll out of bed and immediately start working.</description></item><item><title>It's time a for change: I'm trying Linux on the desktop</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/05/its-time-a-for-change-im-trying-linux-on-the-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/05/its-time-a-for-change-im-trying-linux-on-the-desktop/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve felt lousy about the internet, software, computers and technology lately. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve abandoned a project of mine and that made me feel pretty bad. It made me think about my relationship with my personal computer and the things I use it for. I realized once I removed macOS and iOS software development from things I use my computer for I&amp;rsquo;m not really tied to a Mac. And though I love macOS, Macintosh computers, and the entire Apple ecosystem, I just needed to look at something else for a while and rekindle that passion I have for my computer.</description></item><item><title>Working with others on personal projects</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/working-with-others-on-personal-projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/working-with-others-on-personal-projects/</guid><description>I like working with other people. I like having people to throw ideas off of, and having sanity checks for approaches I&amp;rsquo;m taking with things. I like the additional creativity that happens when you have another voice in the conversation and I like learning from people who know more about a topic than I do.
This is generally pretty difficult with personal projects. And for whatever reason many of my projects start with me using a technology I&amp;rsquo;ve never used before.</description></item><item><title>Can we encourage Facebook employees to go elsewhere?</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/can-we-encourage-facebook-employees-to-go-elsewhere/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/can-we-encourage-facebook-employees-to-go-elsewhere/</guid><description>I was walking to work this morning past a group of Facebook employees waiting for their bus. I wanted to say something to them. While I didn&amp;rsquo;t, it got me thinking, what if?
What if I actually stopped to say something? Would it turn confrontational? Would they ignore me? What if I had an encouraging, positive, standardized statement that said &amp;ldquo;Hey, you&amp;rsquo;re really fucking good at your job. You have options.</description></item><item><title>New web site for 2019</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/01/new-web-site-for-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/01/new-web-site-for-2019/</guid><description>If you look back at my recent 2018 Year in Review you know I was toying with the idea of updating my web site to use a static site generator. As you can see, I went through with it. Let me explain a bit of the process, and my rationalization behind it all.
I last did a major refresh of my web site about 6 years ago where I went from self-hosting a Wordpress blog to moving everything over to Squarespace.</description></item></channel></rss>