<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>seattle on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/seattle/</link><description>Recent content in seattle on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 13:52:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/seattle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TechStars for a Day, startup culture, and my comparisons to Omaha</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/05/techstars-for-a-day-startup-culture-and-my-comparisons-to-omaha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 13:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/05/techstars-for-a-day-startup-culture-and-my-comparisons-to-omaha/</guid><description>Alright, stay with me. I promise you'll get something at the end. I don't promise you'll like it, though. I attended TechStars for a Day in Seattle. If you want to know what this rockin' organization does check it out. But in short, they are a business accelerator. Get your company off the ground in the most awesome way possible.
It seemed like a classic case of serendipity. I was behind the controls at Big Omaha helping the speakers tell their inspiring stories when an email invite came in from TechStars to join them in Seattle to hear more about the program and to give them an opportunity to meet me.</description></item><item><title>Seattle trip recap</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/seattle-trip-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 11:12:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/seattle-trip-recap/</guid><description>I had a nice trip to Seattle last week. It was really for work purposes, they were sending me to F5 LTM training, but I knew I'd be able to make it into a fun vacation as well. I had no plans when going there, but that rarely stops me from having a good time. Thanks to Twitter, and my blog, you're able to see a step by step recap of my whole trip by accessing my Twitter archive page for the week.</description></item></channel></rss>