<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chicago on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/categories/chicago/</link><description>Recent content in Chicago on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:55:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/categories/chicago/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflecting on my ten year High School reunion</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/10/reflecting-on-my-ten-year-high-school-reunion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:55:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/10/reflecting-on-my-ten-year-high-school-reunion/</guid><description>I didn't originally want to go. But to everyone who told me I should: Thank you. Everyone knows I didn't know what to expect. But now that the Grant Community High School class of 1999 reunion is over I can't help but look at those four years far different than I did before. I'll be honest and tell you that I really did discount that time. It wasn't awful, but I was glad it was behind me.</description></item><item><title>Ten year class reunion</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/ten-year-class-reunion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 07:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/ten-year-class-reunion/</guid><description>Wow, ten years since I graduated high school. Many probably will say &amp;quot;it seems like only yesterday&amp;quot; but to me it seems much, much longer. In fact, to be honest, I hardly remember those four years at all. Sure some special moments stand out that included performances or things with friends, but on the whole... really, nothing. I wasn't planning on going to the reunion. It wasn't until my friend Becky from high school asked me to go did I cave and signed up and booked a flight.</description></item><item><title>NIN for the last time. For real this time. Chicago.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/nin-for-the-last-time.-for-real-this-time.-chicago./</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 10:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/09/nin-for-the-last-time.-for-real-this-time.-chicago./</guid><description>{.size-thumbnail .wp-image-1241 width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;} Friday morning started like any other Friday morning. By Friday afternoon I found out that Andy Peters and I were headed to Chicago that night to see one of the last performances of our favorite band, Nine Inch Nails.
A while back Skid Vis surprised Andy and I by telling us he hooked us up with tickets to the completely sold out Nine Inch Nails show in Chicago.</description></item><item><title>Mourning the loss of an office</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/mourning-the-loss-of-an-office/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/07/mourning-the-loss-of-an-office/</guid><description>Yesterday it was announced that the office I used to work at in Chicago, and who many still work at will be closing at the end of October. I understand that business is business, but these are my friends. Friends that believed my company when they acquired it a couple years ago and said &amp;quot;this office and everyone in it is going nowhere. We value the employees here and we're keeping this Chicago office.</description></item><item><title>Hello from Chicago</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/hello-from-chicago/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 16:32:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/01/hello-from-chicago/</guid><description>I dragged Cassie (well actually she drove most of the way) to Chicago this week. Been here since Tuesday night, and it's really nice to see the city again.
It is a little eye opening though. Living here for so long, then going elsewhere, and then coming back.
All the odd looks and questions when I say I really do like Omaha, and i'm not just saying that to back myself up in the move.</description></item><item><title>My last day at the Chicago office</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/my-last-day-at-the-chicago-office/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 14:46:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/my-last-day-at-the-chicago-office/</guid><description>So today i'm saying my goodbye's at the Chicago office. There's a get together after work today at a local pub and it seems like a decent amount of people are going to be showing up. Just got back a few ago from my last ROM coffee run. My secret crush, Lilly, wasn't there, though.
My desk is clean, things are packed up for me to bring home... another chapter closed in the big book of relocation.</description></item><item><title>7 days to go/Photo montage</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/7-days-to-go/photo-montage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 16:48:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/7-days-to-go/photo-montage/</guid><description>Seven days from today I'll be on my way to Omaha. A moving company is coming first thing Saturday morning to put everything on a truck and off I go. Sounds so simple.
In honor of me leaving, I put together a quick collection of some photos of random times/events/entertaining things that took place here. I have another week to make some more great memories, but here's a little selection so far.</description></item><item><title>Chronicling my time in Chicago #3</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/chronicling-my-time-in-chicago-#3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:27:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/chronicling-my-time-in-chicago-#3/</guid><description>So I've been back now since Tuesday night. I can say it's slightly odd being back. I had a nice going away lunch with my old team Wednesday, and went out last night after work with some of the Chicago people for dinner and drinks.
I'm seeing more and more people moving on with their lives without me in it. Makes sense, and completely expected, but often hard to watch. People I would be spending more time with and be close to, but given the limited time it's easier just to let things move on by.</description></item><item><title>Anyone shop online for clothes? Aparently it's more difficult than I thought.</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/anyone-shop-online-for-clothes-aparently-its-more-difficult-than-i-thought./</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 14:39:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/anyone-shop-online-for-clothes-aparently-its-more-difficult-than-i-thought./</guid><description>Seems like right now is the first time in a while i've just been sitting around relaxing. Threw some laundry in, picked up a little. Probably get back to packing this weekend at some point.
A week from right now I'll already be in Omaha. Slightly surreal.
I'm trying to go through online and bookmark new clothes, since I'm having to go through an overhaul of my wardrobe. I can no longer wear concert tshirts and cartoon characters to work.</description></item><item><title>Chronicling my time in Chicago #2</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/chronicling-my-time-in-chicago-#2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 10:05:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/10/chronicling-my-time-in-chicago-#2/</guid><description>So last weekend when I last blogged I met up with Katie, Tracy, Michelle and Frank. We had a blast! This Friday night we hope to go out and be all stupid again. In fact, a friend of Frank's (ex-girlfriend's sister actually) is from Omaha, and is in town. So she's going to go out with us. I have so many awesome resources for this move, I can't complain one bit.</description></item><item><title>Chronicling my time in Chicagoland #1</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/chronicling-my-time-in-chicagoland-#1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 20:43:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2008/09/chronicling-my-time-in-chicagoland-#1/</guid><description>Tonight I called my buddy Sean at Old Town Tatu to schedule my Illinois state tattoo. Tuesday night at 8pm. Not sure where it's going yet, or in what style... but he's an awesome artist, and i'll work with him on it. I just want to take Illinois with me when I go. I sent out a blast email (and myspace post) today to everyone letting them know of my time table.</description></item></channel></rss>