<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>open source on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/open-source/</link><description>Recent content in open source on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Common sense doesn't scale</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/12/common-sense-doesnt-scale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/12/common-sense-doesnt-scale/</guid><description>Imagine you were hired as a babysitter by some parents for their child. They are usually pretty casual about things, but they mentioned the kid has to go to bed at 8pm.
8pm comes around and the movie the kid is watching has 5 minutes left. And while I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a babysitter, and I know nothing about children, I would like to think that I, and probably most people, would let the kid watch that 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Ship software, not code</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/06/ship-software-not-code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/06/ship-software-not-code/</guid><description>Note from the editor. That&amp;rsquo;s me, Gabe. I&amp;rsquo;m the editor. I&amp;rsquo;ve had this blog post in draft status for a while, originally creating the outline for a possible conference talk. I didn&amp;rsquo;t write it to be negative about any particular software, language, or approach. However, in the past day I&amp;rsquo;ve done some software installing and found myself experiencing much of what I wrote below. However, it&amp;rsquo;s still only a coincidence and I didn&amp;rsquo;t write this to be on the offensive against any one project.</description></item><item><title>Being a part of a team</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/05/being-a-part-of-a-team/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2022/05/being-a-part-of-a-team/</guid><description>Growing up I was never a sports person, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend a lot of time on what you&amp;rsquo;d call &amp;ldquo;typical&amp;rdquo; teams. But I was heavily into the performing arts all throughout my youth. This included different organized groups such as choirs, theater performances, and both competitive and non-competitive bands of all kinds, including the stereotypical high school garage band. This continued on even after high school, where I took part in a couple competitive Drum &amp;amp; Bugle corps.</description></item></channel></rss>