<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>projects on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/projects/</link><description>Recent content in projects on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I'm discontinuing work on Mastochist for Mastodon</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/04/im-discontinuing-work-on-mastochist-for-mastodon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/04/im-discontinuing-work-on-mastochist-for-mastodon/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m no longer going to continue work on my Mastodon client, Mastochist. And even though it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really impact anybody but myself, I felt I owed people a detailed explanation and apology since people have heard me talk about the work I&amp;rsquo;ve put in it for quite a while.
Mostly I owe an apology to Cara who I hired to design the look of the app, and she became my sounding board as I built out features.</description></item><item><title>Working with others on personal projects</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/working-with-others-on-personal-projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/working-with-others-on-personal-projects/</guid><description>I like working with other people. I like having people to throw ideas off of, and having sanity checks for approaches I&amp;rsquo;m taking with things. I like the additional creativity that happens when you have another voice in the conversation and I like learning from people who know more about a topic than I do.
This is generally pretty difficult with personal projects. And for whatever reason many of my projects start with me using a technology I&amp;rsquo;ve never used before.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Longtail Music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2017/04/introducing-longtail-music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2017/04/introducing-longtail-music/</guid><description>It's no secret I've been frustrated with music discovery for a while. Ever since Rdio shut down I've listened to less music on mainstream services. While I do have a Spotify account, I tend to only use it to listen to old playlists and comfort music.
Where music discovery has been successful for me, however, is with internet radio. Having a person with deep knowledge within a certain style hand-picking tracks for me every day has proven time and time again that it's a system that works.</description></item><item><title>Lost and Found: A video experiment started in 2006</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/lost-and-found-a-video-experiment-started-in-2006/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 13:57:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/lost-and-found-a-video-experiment-started-in-2006/</guid><description>In 2006 I was diligently working on my (still unreleased) new album &amp;quot;The Longest Post&amp;quot;. With that I decided to create a couple music videos both as an experiment on if I could make something fun, and to have a visual way to distribute some songs. A couple apartment moves later and the hard drives with the music videos were lost.
Until now. In October, 2010 I found the hard drives while cleaning out my music studio and decided it was time to show them to the world.</description></item></channel></rss>