<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>roku on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/roku/</link><description>Recent content in roku on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/roku/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The removal of the legacy Roku SDK</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/junk/2019-01-02-the_removal_of_the_legacy_roku_sdk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/junk/2019-01-02-the_removal_of_the_legacy_roku_sdk/</guid><description>I should have put money on this.
EDIT: A previous version of this post stated that legacy visual screen components would be removed from Roku OS on January 1, 2019. While Roku still intends to remove the legacy visual screen components in a future OS update, this will not occur in January 2019. -Roku</description></item><item><title>Launching The Bat Player on the Roku Store and its aftermath</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/07/launching-the-bat-player-on-the-roku-store-and-its-aftermath/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 16:39:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/07/launching-the-bat-player-on-the-roku-store-and-its-aftermath/</guid><description>After a year of development The Bat Player went live on Roku's Channel Store.
The Bat Player first went public in September of last year. This means if you knew the right Roku Channel Code you could install it on your device. I put up a web site to make this easier, and shared it with a couple specific communities like the Roku forums and Reddit's Roku subreddit.
My goal all along was to get it available in their mainstream directory.</description></item><item><title>Developing for Roku</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2014/12/developing-for-roku/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2014/12/developing-for-roku/</guid><description>Ask yourself, "Do I know anybody who's developed anything for the Roku Media Player?" More than likely the answer is no. If you ask others you might get get some response, but more than likely nobody you know has done it either.
And that's why I wanted to throw up a little piece about building for the Roku.
Chapter 1: I want to listen to Streaming Internet Radio. Marantz audio reciever For me it started innocently enough.</description></item></channel></rss>