<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recommendations on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/recommendations/</link><description>Recent content in Recommendations on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/recommendations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A journey through my music tastes</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/03/a-journey-through-my-music-tastes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/03/a-journey-through-my-music-tastes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this blog post as a draft for a couple months now. And who knows how long it would have stayed as a draft, but Keith Flint of The Prodigy died this week, and given how much I owe to The Prodigy being one of my earliest electronic loves, I felt I should actually publish it.
My music taste and the different artists that I've listened to throughout my life is a big part of my identity.</description></item><item><title>Radvent Dec 5 - #Radvent tunage</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-5-#radvent-tunage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 20:06:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/12/radvent-dec-5-#radvent-tunage/</guid><description>{.aligncenter .size-medium .wp-image-14617 width=&amp;ldquo;232&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;}
Create the soundtrack of your year.
Now THIS is more like it! Though to be honest I feel like I talk about music to people so often I don't know what to put here that's worth reading.
It's actually pretty easy for me to find what I've been listening to this past year because of Last.FM. In fact here is my 12 month chart in detail.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Song Recommendation: Mark Mallman - Mother Made Me Do It</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/weekly-song-recommendation-mark-mallman-mother-made-me-do-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2010/10/weekly-song-recommendation-mark-mallman-mother-made-me-do-it/</guid><description>I haven't done a music recommendation post in a while. It's certainly not weekly, but I'm not changing the naming. I don't know, stopped feeling inspired, I guess. Well fuck if I don't feel inspired now.
I've always been a fan of Mark Mallman's. It started, like many of artists I enjoy do, seeing a show of theirs without knowing who they were beforehand. This is a prime example of the Gabe Kangas music/movie introduction theory.</description></item><item><title>Gabe's tools of the trade</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/gabes-tools-of-the-trade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 14:45:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2009/11/gabes-tools-of-the-trade/</guid><description>This isn't the first time I've made a post like this. In fact I used to make a yearly recap of all the tools, software, hardware, etc that made me productive that year. For whatever reason I didn't this past year. Not sure why. Guess I was busy hanging out with you or something. Inspired by Andy Peter's Barcamp Omaha talk I thought I'd share some non-obvious things I use to do things on a daily basis.</description></item></channel></rss>