<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>internet radio on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/internet-radio/</link><description>Recent content in internet radio on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 09:41:48 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/internet-radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Bat Station</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/project/the-bat-station/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/the-bat-station/</guid><description>The Bat Station is an internet radio station that categorizes itself as &amp;ldquo;Gothy and dancy, with a 90s twist&amp;rdquo;.
Gabe runs this station to not only share the music he loves with people, but also to generally increase the amount of internet radio stations that are available.
Audio Stream link for you to put in your player of choice.
Audio Stream link for you to put in your player of choice.</description></item><item><title>Apple Has Shut Down The Bat Player</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/08/apple-has-shut-down-the-bat-player/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 09:41:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2020/08/apple-has-shut-down-the-bat-player/</guid><description>Today The Bat Player on AppleTV was shut down. I wanted to document a bit about the history of the application, and why it&amp;rsquo;s being rejected from the Apple AppStore.
I started The Bat Player in 2014. I wanted a better Internet Radio experience on the TV. I dreamt of artist info, album details and photos. At the time most Internet Radio apps just showed text of the currently playing track and I wanted more.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye Longtail Music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/12/goodbye-longtail-music/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:21:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/12/goodbye-longtail-music/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I shut down Longtail Music, my internet radio discovery platform. I wanted to give a bit of a postmortem to talk about what I sent out to do, what it did, and why I think things never worked out.
I originally built Longtail Music as a spinoff from my time with The Bat Player, an internet radio client for the TV. I thought if The Bat Player was a client for people who already love internet radio and know what they want to listen to, then I want to build something on the web for people to discover internet radio for the first time and discover a station they would love.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Longtail Music</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2017/04/introducing-longtail-music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2017/04/introducing-longtail-music/</guid><description>It's no secret I've been frustrated with music discovery for a while. Ever since Rdio shut down I've listened to less music on mainstream services. While I do have a Spotify account, I tend to only use it to listen to old playlists and comfort music. Where music discovery has been successful for me, however, is with internet radio. Having a person with deep knowledge within a certain style hand-picking tracks for me every day has proven time and time again that it's a system that works.</description></item><item><title>node-internet-radio</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/project/node-internet-radio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/project/node-internet-radio/</guid><description>Node.js module to get Now Playing information from an internet radio stream in the form of the following object:
{ listeners: '89', bitrate: '128', title: 'Die Antwoord - I Fink U Freaky', fetchsource: 'SHOUTCAST_V1' } The syntax is simple:
getStationInfo(url, callback, [method]); Install npm install node-internet-radio This Node.js module supports three different methods to fetch the station details of an internet radio stream. All but fetching details from the raw audio stream give you the currently playing track, bitrate, and listener count.</description></item></channel></rss>