<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>development on Gabe Kangas</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/tags/development/</link><description>Recent content in development on Gabe Kangas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabekangas.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I'm discontinuing work on Mastochist for Mastodon</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/04/im-discontinuing-work-on-mastochist-for-mastodon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/04/im-discontinuing-work-on-mastochist-for-mastodon/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m no longer going to continue work on my Mastodon client, Mastochist. And even though it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really impact anybody but myself, I felt I owed people a detailed explanation and apology since people have heard me talk about the work I&amp;rsquo;ve put in it for quite a while.
Mostly I owe an apology to Cara who I hired to design the look of the app, and she became my sounding board as I built out features.</description></item><item><title>Working with others on personal projects</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/working-with-others-on-personal-projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2019/02/working-with-others-on-personal-projects/</guid><description>I like working with other people. I like having people to throw ideas off of, and having sanity checks for approaches I&amp;rsquo;m taking with things. I like the additional creativity that happens when you have another voice in the conversation and I like learning from people who know more about a topic than I do.
This is generally pretty difficult with personal projects. And for whatever reason many of my projects start with me using a technology I&amp;rsquo;ve never used before.</description></item><item><title>Why your tech stack matters (It's not why you think)</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2018/02/why-your-tech-stack-matters-its-not-why-you-think/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 17:32:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2018/02/why-your-tech-stack-matters-its-not-why-you-think/</guid><description>Recently I've received a lot of messages from recruiters looking for an iOS developer to build with React Native. And while I generally don't care what technologies people are selecting to build their products, I find this to be a subject that I think warrants a deeper dive. But a disclaimer up front: I have a bias, and I only speak for me, not for any team I'm currently or have been a part of.</description></item><item><title>Launching The Bat Player on the Roku Store and its aftermath</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/07/launching-the-bat-player-on-the-roku-store-and-its-aftermath/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 16:39:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2015/07/launching-the-bat-player-on-the-roku-store-and-its-aftermath/</guid><description>After a year of development The Bat Player went live on Roku's Channel Store.
The Bat Player first went public in September of last year. This means if you knew the right Roku Channel Code you could install it on your device. I put up a web site to make this easier, and shared it with a couple specific communities like the Roku forums and Reddit's Roku subreddit.
My goal all along was to get it available in their mainstream directory.</description></item><item><title>Developing for Roku</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2014/12/developing-for-roku/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2014/12/developing-for-roku/</guid><description>Ask yourself, "Do I know anybody who's developed anything for the Roku Media Player?" More than likely the answer is no. If you ask others you might get get some response, but more than likely nobody you know has done it either.
And that's why I wanted to throw up a little piece about building for the Roku.
Chapter 1: I want to listen to Streaming Internet Radio. Marantz audio reciever For me it started innocently enough.</description></item><item><title>Building TastemakerX for iOS</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/12/building-tastemakerx-for-ios/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 19:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/12/building-tastemakerx-for-ios/</guid><description>It's still in beta, and I'm still happily iterating over all of the features of the application, but I wanted to share the tools I used, the services I take advantage of, and overall tidbits that might be useful to fellow developers about how I've been building TastemakerX. Maybe you can in turn share some things with me.
Tools that made my life easier. Spark Inspector Spark Inspector Both it and Reveal popped up around the same time, but since then I've been using Spark Inspector as a tool to debug view-related things.</description></item><item><title>Stuff I'd like to do in 2013</title><link>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/01/stuff-id-like-to-do-in-2013/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 18:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabekangas.com/blog/2013/01/stuff-id-like-to-do-in-2013/</guid><description>I'm not a fan of New Years resolutions, but there are some things I'd like to do in this next year. All very doable things, but if you think that in any way you'd be able to help with any of them I'd certainly be up for pointers!
Contribute to an open source project that focuses on a) mobile and b) something I care about. (Note: I checked out the Colloquy source last night and started looking at their bug list to see if I could help with anything).</description></item></channel></rss>